原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
时间轴    西·查    想念Gallifrey的wholock
时间轴    知之    caroline    啾
时间轴    噃噃     紫夏     壬虚浪影
翻 译     辰星晓Reginamoon    苏小黛
翻 译     海云生    Carolgcz    冰岛豆腐
翻 译     kathy567    持久    nemonini
翻 译     杏仁斯嘉丽    马丁马丁回音山
翻 译     伊森泽生    子V    glida    王木木
翻 译     Sakura的小书包    布塔
校 对     Sakura的小书包    布塔诚荐
后 期     咖啡·Lee
总 监     布塔
In the Still of the Night - The Five Satins
♪ In the still of the night ♪
♪ I held you ♪
♪ Held you tight ♪
♪ 'Cause I love ♪
♪ Love you so ♪
♪ Promise I'll never ♪
♪ Let you go ♪
♪ In the still of the night ♪
♪ I remember ♪
♪ That night in May ♪
♪ The stars were bright above ♪
♪ I'll hope and I'll pray ♪
♪ To keep Your precious love... ♪
我年轻的时候  以为刷房子真就是刷房子
When I was young, I thought house painters painted houses.
我懂什么
What did I know?
我当时是个工人
I was a working guy.
南费城的卡车司机107号地方工会的工会代表
A business agent for Teamster Local 107 out of South Philly.
千百个工人中的一员
One of a thousand working stiffs...
直到我不再是了
until I wasn't no more.
然后
And then...
我开始刷房子
I started painting houses...
亲自
myself.
他们女儿的婚礼
格蕾丝·安妮·巴法利诺
嫁给
罗伯特·里特
在这件事情上
In this particular matter,
一切都是围绕着婚礼的
the whole thing was built around the wedding.
比尔·巴法利诺的女儿在底特律结婚
Bill Bufalino's daughter was getting married in Detroit.
比尔是卡车司机工会的律师  但更重要的是
Bill was a Teamster lawyer, but more important,
他是罗素·巴法利诺的表亲
he was Russell Bufalino's cousin.
罗素不想坐飞机
Now, Russell didn't want to fly,
所以我打算开车送他去参加婚礼
so I was gonna drive him to the wedding.
他想顺路处理一些生意上的事情
He wanted to take care of some business along the way,
对罗素而言  这就意味着一件事
which in Russell's case meant only one thing:
钱  收钱
Money... collecting it.
所以我们开车去的
So we'd drive.
他和他老婆凯丽  以及我和我老婆艾琳
Him and his wife Carrie and me and my wife Irene.
我喊她琳妮
Or I call her Reenie.
我想着我们走费城外的476号公路
I figured we would take 476 out of Philly,
然后我们到匹兹顿接上罗素
and then we go up to Pittston and pick up Russ,
我们一般都是这么走的
which is usually how we did it,
然后沿80号州际公路西段开过宾州
and then Interstate 80 West through the rest of Pennsylvania,
然后我们横穿俄亥俄州到托莱多
and then we'd go across Ohio, all the way to Toledo,
接着我们沿着75号公路北上底特律
and then we would go 75 North to Detroit.
总共要花三天
It was gonna take about three days
算上所有谈生意以及抽烟的时间
with all the business breaks and cigarette stops,
因为罗素不允许任何人在车里面抽烟
since Russell didn't allow nobody to smoke in the car.
他说蓝眼睛吉米和迈尔·兰斯基
He says Jimmy Blue Eyes and Meyer Lansky
说服他戒了烟
convinced him to stop smoking
当时他们从自己在古巴的赌场里被赶了出去
when they were getting kicked out of their casinos in Cuba
还被卡斯特罗开枪打了
and getting shot at by Castro.
我也说不清楚  也许是那种
I don't know. It might have been one of those,
"上帝啊如果我活着度过这一劫
"Please-God-if-I-ever-get-out- of-this-fucking-thing-alive-
我就再也不抽烟了"的情况
I'll-never-smoke-again things too."
但我知道从卡斯特罗那件事开始
But I do know that from Castro on,
罗素就再也不许别人在车里抽烟了
Russ wouldn't allow nobody to smoke in his car,
就连凯丽也不行
not even Carrie.
听说
你
刷房子
能尽快停车吗
Can we stop soon?
我们刚上车两分钟  亲爱的
We're only in the car two minutes, honey.
甚至还没上公路呢
We're not even near the highway.
我知道  罗素  但你不喜欢在公路上停车
I know, Russell. But you don't like to stop on the highway.
也不能这么说
Well, it's not that so much.
是他们不允许你在公路上停车
They don't let you stop on the highway.
好吧  那我们就在车里抽吧
Okay, so then we'll smoke in the car.
我的白内障怎么办
And what about my cataracts?
我会开窗的
I'll crack the window.
凯丽  我发过誓的  记得吗
Carrie, I made a vow. Remember?
记得我发过誓吗  凯丽
Remember I made a vow, Carrie?
好吧  这下我不能在...
Yeah, now I can't smoke on...
行吧  这下我不能抽烟了
All right, and now I can't smoke.
看见我们到哪了吗
See where we are?
那是...
Is... Is that...
太巧了吧
What are those odds?
德士古石油
出什么问题了  小子
What's the problem, kid?
我不知道  感觉车坏了
I don't... I don't know. It sounds funny.
车停了  再启动  就没动力了
It stops, it starts, it loses power.
我看看能不能给你搭把手
Let me see if I can give you a hand.
我看看  检查一下这些塞子
Let me see. Check all these plugs.
火花塞没问题
Spark plugs are okay.
分电盘盖也没问题
The distributor cap's okay.
很好
Good.
一定是这个...出问题了
It's gotta be something with... with this.
定时链
Timing chain.
就是这么回事  这上面有个塞子
This is what this is. There's a cap on it.
这个塞子松了  不应该松的
This cap is loose. It ain't supposed to be loose.
所以这意味着它们已经老化了
So that means they're getting worn out.
你得...
You just gotta...
试试  拧紧它
Try that now. Tighten it up.
我会开车  但不会修车
I can drive 'em. I can't fix 'em.
你可以重新上路了  小子
You're back in business, kid.
谢了
Thanks.
-我怎么回报你呢  -不用
- I owe you anything? - No.
你不用回报我
No, you don't owe me anything.
谢了
Thanks.
-我叫弗兰克  -你好  弗兰克
- Frank. - Hey, Frank. How ya doing?
你叫什么
What's your name?
你是哪里人
Where you from?
-费城  -你是费城人啊
- Philly. - Oh, you're from Philly.
是的
Yeah.
在费城你一般去哪玩
Where you hang out there?
卡拉汉
Callahan's.
滚球俱乐部
Bocce Club.
但那是个酒吧  不是玩滚球的俱乐部
But it's a bar, it's not a bocce club.
是嘛  你玩滚球吗
Oh, yeah. You play bocce?
不玩
Nah.
好了  弗兰克  把那玩意修好
All right, Frankie... get that fixed.
因为它肯定还会掉链子的  我告诉你
Because it'll go again on you, I'm telling you.
-谢谢  -好了
- Thank you. - All right.
我会去修的  再次感谢
I will. Thanks again.
祝你好运  小兄弟
Good luck, buddy.
我以为他是加油站老板
I mean, I thought maybe he owned the gas station.
因为他一定是个老板  看得出来
'Cause he owned something, you could tell.
结果发现整条路都是他的
Yeah, it turns out he owned the whole road.
I Hear You Knockin' - Smiley Lewis
♪ You went away and left me long time ago ♪
牛排和猪排
友好酒吧
♪ And now you're knocking on my door ♪
这只吗
This one?
♪ I hear you knocking ♪
敬礼  干了  朋友们
Salute! Drink up, fellas.
上帝保佑
God bless.
走着  走着  今天一起赚点钱
Let's go. Let's go. Let's make some money today.
这可是个酒吧
It's a bar.
向你老婆问好
Say hello to your wife, huh?
我有个赚钱的法子  推销那些后腿肉
I got a way you can earn, to push those hindquarters.
这里有个人  他会为此出大价钱的
There's a guy in here, he'll pay a lot of money for them.
来吧  我们先干了再谈生意
Come on, let's shoot this first and then we'll talk business.
在酒吧的另一头  十二点钟方向...
At the other end of the bar, at twelve o'clock...
看见他了吗  有点秃的那个
You see him? He's got a rescinding hairline.
没错  他能让你赚大钱
Yeah, you'll make a lot of money with him.
看见他了吗  瘦剃刀  他是这地方的老板
See him there? Skinny Razor. He owns the place.
剃刀
Razor?
他放高利贷  还在酒吧开了个赌注站
He shylocks and runs a little book out of the joint.
他挺能耐的  人脉很广
He's got a lot of good action, good connections.
-他叫剃刀  -是的  他曾经在肉店工作
- Razor's his name? - Yeah, he used to work at a butcher shop.
我朋友爱尔兰人弗兰克在这里
My friend Frank Irish is here.
我和你说过的那个
The one I told you about?
-开卡车的  -对  运后腿肉
- Oh, the truck. - Yeah, hindquarters.
我是弗兰克·希兰
Frank Sheeran.
你喜欢牛排吗
You like steak?
喜欢
I do.
我送牛排
I deliver steak.
是吗
Do ya?
上好的牛排
Good steak.
我可以给你送牛排
I could deliver you steak.
-可以吗  -可以
- Could ya? - I could.
价格也公道  最低价
Good price too. The best.
-我们晚点再聊  -好的
- We'll talk later. - Okay.
谢了  瘦子
Thanks, Skinny.
外面冷死了
It's freezing out there.
我不介意
I don't mind it.
我不行  我怕冷
Not me. I hate it.
帮我个忙  你出去的时候...
Hey, do me a favor. When you go outside...
帮我把封条装上
put the seal on for me.
-好吧  反正我得出去  -我欠你个人情
- All right. I gotta go out anyway. - I owe you one.
♪ You'd better go back to your used-to-be ♪
♪ Because your love's no good to me ♪
♪ I hear you knocking ♪
友好酒吧
♪ But you can't come in ♪
♪ I hear you knocking ♪
♪ Go back where you've been ♪
♪ They call, they call me the fat man ♪
♪ 'Cause I weigh two hundred pounds... ♪
25块  A级后腿肉
给  弗兰克
There you go, Frank.
-下次见  -好的  托尼  谢了
- See you next time. - All right, Tony. Thanks.
好多了  弗兰克
Much better, Frank.
我不碰特选级  只运极佳级
I don't go near Choice. I only do Prime. That's it.
美国牛肉分级制度中
极佳级和特选级
分别为最好的前两个等级
下周二能再给我搞一些来吗
Can I get some more for next Tuesday?
你想要多少
How many you want?
至少五块
At least five.
好的  给你五块
Okay. Five, you got.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
阿门
Amen.
这他妈是怎么回事
What the fuck is this?
托尼  我不...
Tony, I don't...
这他妈是怎么回事  弗兰克
What the fuck is this, Frank?
我不知道
I don't... I don't know.
我是说...
I mean...
车不是我装的
I don't load the truck.
是装车的人装的车
The loaders are supposed to load the truck.
也许他们没干好自己的活儿  我不知道
Maybe they didn't do their work. I don't know.
你没意识到车变轻了吗
You didn't realize you were driving a light horse?
没有  我只是...
No. I just...
没意识到  感觉挺正常的
Nothing. It felt fine.
拜托  弗兰克  拜托
Oh, come on, Frank. Come on.
我说的是真的  我...
I'm telling you. I...
千真万确  我真不知道是怎么回事
God's truth. I just don't know what happened.
我不知道  也许是...
I don't know. Maybe some...
-车是空的  -我知道
- It's empty. - I know it is.
我知道
I know it is.
你们看什么看  回去工作
What are you guys looking at? Go back to work.
所有人
All of youse!
我怎么和老板交待
What am I gonna tell the boss?
我说了我真不知道是怎么回事
Well, I'm telling you that I don't know what's going on.
别问我  因为我...
Just don't look at me 'cause I, you know...
那我还能去问谁
Well, who else can I look at?
这件事可不能怪在我头上  弗兰克
This is not gonna be on me, Frank.
-我都说了  -也怪不到我头上
- I'm telling you right now. - Not gonna be on me,
我只是开车的  别的什么都没干
I just drive the truck. That's all I do.
好吧  弗兰克·希兰  是叫这个吗
Okay, Frank Sheeran. Am I saying that right?
律师
威廉·E·巴法利诺
是的  就是这名字
Yeah, you said right.
根据合同  这得感谢吉米·霍法
Under the contract, thanks to Jimmy Hoffa...
管理层只能在有非常具体的指控时才能开除司机
management can only fire a driver on very specific charges.
-你上班迟到过吗  -没有
- So, you ever show up late? - No.
-有任何交通违规吗  -没有
- Do you have any moving violations? - No.
-你在工作期间喝酒吗  -不喝
- Do you drink on the job? - No.
你打过人吗
You ever hit anybody?
-在工作期间吗  -对
- On the job? - Yeah.
-那没有  -好的
- No. - Okay.
偷窃不算吗
What about stealing, that ain't grounds?
这个嘛
Well...
他们能证明吗
can they prove it?
应该不能
I don't think so.
那就没什么好担心的了
All right then, we don't have nothing to worry about.
如果他们能证明
If they can prove it,
他们也只是想让你供出其他同伙的名字
they're just gonna want names from you. Accomplices.
仅此而已  你交代几个名字就能回家了
That's all. You give them a couple of names, you go home.
还能保住你的工作
Keep your job.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think about that?
-你会交代名字吗  -不
- Would you give them names? - No.
没有名字
No names.
你知道吧  我并不...
You know, I don't, uh...
我并不关心你到底做没做
I don't care whether you did it or not.
对我来说没有区别
That makes no difference to me.
-我知道  -我是来帮你辩护的  对吧
- Yeah, I know. - I'm here to defend you. Right?
对
Right.
怎么  你想知道我到底做没做吗
What, you want to know if I did it or not?
这个嘛
Well...
不管怎样我都会替你辩护
I'm gonna defend you either way.
我知道  只是...
Yeah, all right, but...
我没偷他们东西时可是勤勤恳恳工作的
I, I work hard for them when I ain't stealing from 'em.
法官大人  如果这是是非对错的问题
Your Honor, if this was about right or wrong,
公司应该早就开除希兰先生了
the company would have sought Mr. Sheeran's dismissal.
可他们没有
They didn't.
他们指控希兰先生
They only accused Mr. Sheeran
只是因为公司希望他能指认同伙
because the company hoped he could name conspirators,
而他没法指认  因为并不存在什么同伙
which he couldn't do because they don't exist.
不存在同伙是因为他并没有偷东西
They don't exist because he didn't steal anything.
他没偷东西是因为他是个模范员工
He didn't steal anything because he's an exemplary employee,
工作八年都没请过一天病假
who in eight years has never taken a day of sick leave.
他唯一违反过的只有他自己工会的规矩
The only rule he ever broke is his own union's,
在冷死人的大冬天  帮其他人把半扇半扇的牛肉
by helping others carry sides of beef from his truck
从他的卡车上搬进他们的冷藏库里
to their refrigerators in the dead of winter.
全体起立
All rise.
现在开庭
Court is in session.
我要驳回此案并给予警告
I'm dismissing this case with a warning.
好的  法官大人
Yes, Your Honor.
不  不是警告你  希兰先生
No, no, not you, Mr. Sheeran.
你们下次要是再把工人告上法庭
You bring another working man before this court
没有证据而只有威胁
with threats instead of evidence,
相信我  你们会后悔的
believe me, you'll be sorry.
要是我持有这家公司的股份  我一定赶紧卖了
If I owned stock in this company, I would sell it.
我不知道他怎么做到的  我也不会问
I don't know how he did it, and I ain't gonna ask.
我只知道比尔·巴法利诺帮我摆脱了一件
All I know is that Bill Bufalino got me out of
我原本绝无可能脱身的案子
a case where I should never have gotten away with it.
罗马别墅餐厅酒吧
我本该彻底败诉的
I should've been down for the count.
人们会感谢你今天的所作所为  弗兰克
People are gonna appreciate what you did today, Frank.
他们有家人  有孩子
You know, they got families, they got kids.
他们需要这些工作
They need those jobs.
然而  我们却在外庆祝
Instead, we went out celebrating...
罗素
Russell!
而我则就此走上了
...and I met what was gonna turn out to be
余生的道路
the rest of my life.
我就觉得刚进来的人是你
You know, I thought that was you walking in outside.
当然了  这可是我们的地盘
Yeah, yeah, you know, this is our place.
我给你介绍个叫弗兰克的新人吧
Can I introduce you to this new guy Frank?
当然  好的
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
弗兰克  来见见我的表兄罗素·巴法利诺
Frank, I want you to meet my cousin Russell Bufalino.
-你好啊  -你好  幸会
- How are ya? - Hi, nice to meet you.
几个月前你帮我修过我的卡车
You helped me with my truck a couple of months ago.
没错  想起来了  定时链坏了
Oh, yeah, yeah, that's right. The timing chain.
-对  -你找人修了吗
- Yeah. - Did you get it fixed?
-我第二天就找人修了  -好样的
- I fixed it the next day, yeah. - Attaboy.
-再次感谢你  -不客气
- Thanks again. - Oh, you're welcome.
我的荣幸  你修好了就好
My pleasure. I'm glad you fixed it.
你最好注意点
You better watch.
这里有很多不好惹的家伙  他跟你说了吗
There's a lot of tough guys around here. Did he tell ya?
你并不怕不好惹的家伙  是吧
You're not afraid of tough guys, are ya?
对
No.
我想也是  回见
I didn't think so. I'll see you around.
-好的  -谢了  罗素
- Okay. - Thanks, Russell.
你表兄之前帮了我大忙
Your cousin saved my ass.
不然我可能会损失一整车的货
I could've lost the whole load.
是啊  他非常了解卡车
Yeah, yeah. Well, he knows everything about trucks, really.
他在汽水公司干过很长时间
Yeah, he worked at Canada Dry for a long time.
-维托  你好吗  -幸会
- Vito, how are you? - Pleasure.
我们去坐卡座吧
I think, uh... Let's take the booth.
来吧  你会喜欢这里的
Come on. You're gonna love this.
也许我当时还不知道罗素·巴法利诺是谁
Maybe I didn't know who Russell Bufalino was back then,
但我在报纸上看过无数照片和报道
but I'd seen enough pictures and stories in the newspapers
足以知道当时跟他一起吃饭的是安吉洛·布鲁诺
to know he was eatin' with Angelo Bruno.
布鲁诺当时刚成为
I mean, Bruno, he... he was just made
费城的新任老大
the new boss of Philadelphia.
从费城到大西洋城的一切都由他负责
He took care of everything from Philadelphia to Atlantic City.
这点我是知道的
That, I knew.
安吉洛·布鲁诺
1980年在自家门外的自家车里
头部中枪而亡
而我当时只需知道这些
And that was all I had to know
就能知道罗素·巴法利诺
to know that Russell Bufalino
绝不是汽水公司的卡车维修工
was no truck mechanic from Canada Dry.
这面包真棒
This bread is very good.
-好吃吧  -好吃
- Good, eh? - Yeah.
你这样的爱尔兰人是在哪学的意大利语
Where did an Irisher like you learn to speak Italian?
在意大利  二战的时候
In Italy - the war.
意大利哪里
Where?
萨莱诺
Salerno.
安齐奥
Anzio.
西西里岛
Sicily...
卡塔尼亚附近
around Catania.
卡塔尼亚  我就是卡塔尼亚人
Catania? I'm from Catania.
是吗  我就觉得你有点卡塔尼亚口音
Yeah? I thought you had an accent like Catania.
你参战了多久
How long were you in the war?
四年
Four years.
411天在战场上
411 days in combat...
122天在安齐奥
122 at Anzio.
45步兵团的
Forty-fifth Infantry.
我的天
Minchia.
-是啊  -天啊
- Yeah. - Minchia.
对的
Yeah.
你当时怕死吗
Were you afraid of dying?
一直很怕
Always afraid.
要是有人说他不怕可千万别信
And don't let anybody tell you that they weren't afraid.
-那纯属胡扯  知道吗  -是啊
- That's a lot of bullshit. You know? - Yeah.
人人都很害怕  而且会经常祈祷
Everybody's afraid. And you pray a lot.
我就经常祈祷
I prayed a lot.
我祈祷说  要是能活着离开
I prayed that I'd never sin again as long as I live
我这辈子一定再也不沾染罪恶
if I could just get out of here.
但紧接着战斗就开始了
But then the fighting starts
你就把一切都忘了
and then you forget about everything.
你只想活下来  保住小命
You're just trying to survive, stay alive.
当我明白自己撑过了战争时
Once I saw that I was getting through the war,
我看了看自己的周围  说...
I looked around me, I said...
我说  "从现在起  一切顺其自然"
I said, "From now on, whatever happens, happens."
听天由命  去他的
Che successe successe. Fuck it.
你懂的  你接到命令就得奉命行事
You know, you got orders, you follow them.
他们让你带几个俘虏去树林里
They tell you to bring some prisoners into... into the woods,
他们并不会告诉你该怎么做
you know, and they don't tell you what to do...
他们只说  "动作快点"
But they just say, you know, "Hurry up."
说来疯狂  但我一直不能理解
It's crazy, but I never understood
他们怎么会乖乖听话
how they would just keep digging
挖自己的坟墓
their own graves, you know. I mean...
停
Stop!
上来
Raus!
可能他们觉得如果干得好
Well, I mean, maybe they thought if they did a good job,
那个拿枪的人
the guy with the gun
就会改变主意
would change his mind.
罗素  他立刻就对我有了好感
Russell, he... he took a shine to me right away.
不久之后
After a while,
他就开始给我分派些小任务了
he started giving me little things to do.
不过那时候  安吉洛本人
But then Angelo himself,
也开始交给我一些小任务了
he started giving me little things to do too.
罗素的老婆  凯丽
Russ's wife, Carrie,
她的家族很久很久以前
her family goes all the way back, way, way back
在西西里岛跟巴法利诺家族是一个镇上的
to the same town in Sicily as the Bufalinos.
他们总会谈论这事
They talked about it all the time.
她来自黑帮中的皇室  可以这么说
She came from mob royalty, if you want to call it that.
希安德拉家族
希安德拉家族  对他们来说  就好像他们是早期
The Sciandras. To them, it was like they came over on the...
乘坐意大利五月花号来到美国的
the Italian Mayflower.
五月花号是英国移民驶往北美的
一艘最为著名的船只
你上楼去吧  清洗一下
Why don't you go upstairs, wash up.
衣服给我  我去处理
Give me those clothes. I'll get rid of them.
别忘了脱鞋  罗素
Don't forget your shoes, Russell.
弗兰克
Hey, Frank,
能尽快停车吗
can we stop soon?
问问你老公吧  罗素
Yeah, yeah, well, ask your husband. Russell?
他都睡死了
He's out cold.
不用  我能行
No, no, I got it.
-能行吗  -行
- Sure? - Yeah.
我们到哪了
Where are we?
快到路易斯堡了
We're close to Lewisburg.
到了告诉我  提醒我一下
Let me know when we get there. Remind me.
-我有几个地方要去  -好的
- I got some stops to make. - Okay.
罗素的生意无所不包
Russell had a piece of everything.
他在皮茨顿有家店叫佩恩布帘店
He had this store in Pittston called Penn Drape & Curtains.
他在那里经营着一切生意
And he ran everything out of there.
谁知道都有些什么
Who knew what it all was?
他肯定有合伙人
I mean, I'm sure the man had partners.
这种人总是有合伙人的
They always have partners.
没人能独占所有钱财
Nobody keeps all the money.
但人人都听罗素的  这点我能确定
But everybody listened to Russ. That I can tell you.
你想贿赂一个法官  先问问罗素
You wanted to bribe a judge, you asked Russell.
你不知道该贿赂法官多少钱
You didn't know how much to bribe him,
罗素会告诉你
Russell was gonna tell you.
好  行  我马上就去
All right, all right. I'll be right there.
来吧  交给我就行  别担心
Come on. I'll take care of it. Don't worry about it.
你想提拔一个手下
You want to promote one of your guys,
罗素会告诉你行或不行
Russ would tell you you could or you could not.
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
跟史蒂夫去他那  带上维托
Go with Steve down to his place. Take Vito with you.
在那边逗留一会
And just hang around for a while.
有几个家伙一直来找麻烦  摆平他们
These guys keep coming around, so straighten them out.
-我会处理的  罗素  -好的
- I'll take care of it, Russ. - Okay.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - No problem.
那谁...你在这里
Where's... Oh, here you are.
我在这里
I'm right here.
你想让某人消失
You want to make somebody disappear,
你得争得罗素的同意
you got to get Russell's permission.
没有第二条路
You know, no two ways about it.
-不  我一点都不担心  -我想也是
- No, I wasn't worried. - I didn't think so.
-帮我给你父亲带个好  -我会的  谢谢
- Tell your father I said "Hi." - I'll tell him. Thanks.
你怎么还在这里  我刚跟布鲁诺说了
What are you doing here? I just told Bruno.
你得跟布鲁诺一起去
You gotta go with Bruno.
-好的  我马上去  -去吧  小心
- Oh, yeah. Yeah, I'm on my way. - Yeah. Take care.
而当你为罗素办事时
And when you did something for Russ,
你得亲力亲为
you did it yourself.
正如罗素常说的
Like Russ used to say...
我让人替我去处理事情的时候
When I ask somebody to take care of something for me,
我希望他们能亲自处理
I expect them to take care of it themselves.
我不需要几个人处理同一件事
I don't need two roads coming back to me.
佩恩布帘店
阿尔伯特·安纳斯塔夏
黑手党"谋杀集团"首领
1957年死于纽约一家理发店
安纳斯塔夏在理发店被杀时
When Anastasia got killed in the barbershop,
罗素被请出来安定人心
it was Russell they brought in to calm things down,
好让大家不要大开杀戒
so that everybody wasn't just going around killing everybody
并把事情摆平
and it could all get straightened out.
我们知道出了什么事
We know what happened.
我们也无能为力  木已成舟
We can't change it. It is what it is.
请转告我的朋友  我很乐意帮忙
Please tell my friend I'm happy to help.
光看外表你永远猜不到他的身份
You'd never know it by looking at this guy,
但条条大路通罗素
but all roads led back to Russ.
钱在哪里
Where's the money?
-他没有  -他没有
- He don't have it. - He don't have it?
他说了点他妈妈的事...
He said something about his mother...
停  别跟我说
Stop. Don't tell me.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
他妈死了  然后葬礼花了他一大笔钱
His mother died and the funeral set him back.
-是不是  -对  完全正确
- Yeah? - Yeah. Exactly. Exactly.
他该死的老娘
His fucking mother's...
在过去十年死了又死
fucking dying over and over for the last ten years.
我要怎么办
What do I do?
留在这里
Don't leave.
拿着
Here.
给他看看  别用
Just show it to him. Don't use it.
看
Look.
弗兰克
Hey, Frank.
瘦子想见你  上车
Skinny wants to see you. You get in the car.
-我正要去见他  -快上车
- I was just gonna go see him. - Get in the fucking car.
-我正要...  -上车
- I was just gonna... - Get in the fucking car!
-我正要去见他  -别跟我耍滑头
- I was just gonna go see him! - Yeah, don't get cute with me.
你跟我扯了那堆你妈死了的屁话
You give me that bullshit about your mother.
赶紧上车
Get in the fucking car!
弗兰克  我对天发誓  我正要...
Frank, I swear to God, I was just gonna...
给我上车
Get in the fucking car!
想跟我耍滑头
You want to get cute with me?
扯了一堆你妈病了死了
All that fucking bullshit about your mother
之类的鬼话
and sick and all that and dying.
我发誓我正要去见他
I swear, I was just gonna go see him.
我对天发誓  我本来打算明天来见你的
I swear to God, I was gonna come see you tomorrow.
-明天  -明天  我对天发誓
- Tomorrow? - Tomorrow. I swear to God.
明天  来这里
Tomorrow. Here.
-什么时间  -你要我什么时候来
- What time? - What time do you want me?
一点如何  我一点来
One o'clock? I'll be here at 1:00.
一点  怎么  你还要睡懒觉吗
One o'clock? What, are you sleeping in?
你说个时间
You tell me.
十点  到这里
Ten o'clock. Here.
-十点  -明天
- Ten o'clock. - Tomorrow.
明天
Tomorrow.
用你妈发誓  用你妈发誓
Swear on your mother. Swear on your mother!
-用你妈发誓  -我以我妈发誓
- Swear on your mother! - I swear on my mother!
我以我妈发誓
I swear on my mother!
你明天什么时间到这里
What time you gonna be here tomorrow?
-我十点就到  -十点
- I'll be here at ten o'clock. - Ten o'clock?
-明天  -好
- Tomorrow. - Yeah.
-到这里  -好的
- Here. - Yeah. Yeah.
我明天就把钱带来  一分不少
I'll bring you the money tomorrow. The whole thing.
把他丢出去
Get him out of here.
出去  出去
Get out of here. Get out of here.
-我对天发誓我会来的  -出去
- I swear to God, I'll be here. - Get out of here.
我要怎么回家
How am I supposed to get home?
-出去  -搭公交
- Get out of here. - Take the fucking bus!
让他妈来接他
Let his mother pick him up.
她怎么了
What's the matter with her?
没什么  她在杂货店碰翻了点东西
Nothing. She knocked something over
把地上弄得一团糟
at the grocery store and made a mess,
-店主就吼了她  -吼了她
- and the grocer yelled at her. - He yelled at her?
对  然后推了她
Yeah, and he shoved her.
他推了她
He shoved her?
对
Yeah.
他推你了吗
Did he shove you?
他叫什么  杂货店的那个家伙
Who was this? The guy at the store?
拐角那个杂货店吗  乔吗
The grocery store on the corner? Joe?
他推了吗
Did he?
宝贝  他推你了吗
Honey, did he shove you?
回话  他推你了吗
Just answer me. Did he push you?
他推你了吗  不论如何  他推了吗
Did he shove you? Whatever it is, did he do that?
我们走
Let's go.
弗兰克
Frank.
弗兰克  那人不是故意的  只是意外
Frank, he didn't mean it, the man. It just happened.
什么意思  什么叫他不是故意的
What do you mean, he didn't mean it?
他碰了她  你在说笑吗
He touched her. What, are you kidding me?
他无权推她  碰她
He has no right to push her. Touch her.
碰她一下都不行
Not even put one pinky on her.
就是他吧
That's him, right?
你留在这里  留在这里
Stay here. Stay here.
弗兰克  我很抱歉  但你女儿犯了错
Frank, I'm sorry, but your kid was out of line.
-我只做了  -你碰了我女儿吗
- I only did what... - You touched my daughter?
天啊  对不起
God, I'm sorry.
不  求你  不  弗兰克
No. Please. No, no, Frank.
弗兰克  求你了  不
Frank, please, please, please. No.
不  弗兰克  不
No, no, Frank! No!
-受着吧  你这混蛋  -不  别这样
- Take that, you motherfucker! - No! Come on!
我的手  我的手
Oh, my fucking hand. My fucking hand!
多洛莉丝
Dolores.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
罗素和凯丽为我们刚出生的女儿多洛莉丝施了洗礼
Russell and Carrie baptized our new daughter, Dolores.
场面很棒  我们都很荣幸
It was a wonderful occasion, and we were honored.
大家都来了
Everybody showed up.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
阿门
Amen.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
唯一的问题是
The only thing is,
孩子多了  要赚的钱也多了
you got more kids, you gotta earn more money.
你想赚一万块的快钱吗
You wanna make a quick ten grand?
悄悄话迪图里奥  不是那个
Whispers DiTullio. Not the Whispers
差不多同一时间在车里被炸死的悄悄话
they blew up in that car around the same time.
这是另一个悄悄话
This was the other Whispers.
这个会赚钱的好悄悄话
The good one who knew how to make money.
我把借钱借给了一家店
I got this place I front money to.
这家店生意很好  真的很好
It's a good business. Really good business.
是一家洗衣店
It's a laundry.
他们的业务是从大西洋城的
What they do is, they collect the linen, towels,
各种大小酒店饭店
sheets and everything from
收布制品  毛巾床单之类的
all the hotels and restaurants in Atlantic City.
清洗并熨烫
They wash it, they iron it.
正常情况下  赚钱就跟印钞一样容易
Normally, it's like a license to print fucking money.
但最近情况有变
Until recently.
特拉华出现了一家公司
There's this other company that opened up down in Delaware.
他们想把我们挤走
They're trying to put us out of business.
典范布品
他们降价  恐吓我们的司机
They're cutting their prices. They're scaring our drivers.
抢我们的客户
They're trying to take our customers from us.
说实话  我有点担忧
To tell you the truth, I'm a little concerned.
别人说他们有点担心
Whenever anybody says they're a little concerned,
说明他们特别担心
they're very concerned.
其实
As a matter of fact,
我担心得不止一点
I'm really more than a little concerned.
他们说自己不止是一点点担心
And when they say they're more than a little concerned,
说明他们已经绝望了
they're desperate.
我想把他们的公司炸了
I want this fucking place bombed,
烧了  焚了  你怎么整都行
burnt, torched, whatever the fuck you have to do.
你打过仗  你知道该怎么办
You were in the war. You know what to do.
你们怎么对柏林就怎么对那地方
Leave that fucking place like you left Berlin.
把那里夷为平地
Burnt to the fucking ground.
我要让他们倒闭
I want them out of fucking business.
他们是谁
Who... who are they?
特拉华的典范布品服务公司
It's the Cadillac Linen Service in Delaware.
一群犹太人开的
It's run by a bunch of Jews.
让他们拿他们的保险赔偿
Let them collect their insurance,
他们肯定投了不少保险
which I'm sure they have plenty,
然后滚出这里
and leave this fucking other place alone,
别碰我的地盘
the one I'm involved in.
-这可不是一万  -这里有两千
- This ain't ten grand. - It's two grand.
你让那些该死的犹太洗衣妇失业之后
When you put these Jew fucking washerwomen out of business,
我就把剩下的钱给你
then you get the rest of your money.
我之所以现在手头有点紧
The reason I'm a little short on the money right now,
是因为我不想找瘦子
I don't wanna go to Skinny,
我不想找那些放高利贷的
I don't wanna ask anybody when they're gonna charge me a vig,
因为那样我就得还一辈子债
and I'm gonna be paying them forever.
我要从别的地方弄钱
I'm getting the money somewhere else.
别人不必知道
And nobody has to know.
特别是瘦子
Especially not Skinny
因为我不找他借钱
because I'm not getting the money from him.
你看起来有点犹豫
And I see you look a little hesitant.
相信我  我知道你的能耐
Believe me, I know what you can do.
要是我少付了你的钱
If I stiff you on the money,
你肯定会让我没有好下场
you're gonna do something terrible to me.
我不想要那样
I do not want that.
我中彩票了
I hit the number.
奖金大概有一千五
It's about 1,500.
我几个小时后回来
I'll see you in a few hours.
典范布品
炸药
弗兰克
Frank.
安吉洛想见你
Angelo wants to see you.
-现在吗  -对  就现在
- Now? - Yeah, now is good.
什么事
What's it about?
我不知道  来吧  我开车送你
I don't know. Come on. I'll drive you.
抱歉  打烊了
坐吧  弗兰克
Sit down, Frank.
你去特拉华做什么
What're you doing in Delaware?
炸一家洗衣店
Bombing out a laundry place.
我就是赚点外快
I was just doing a job to make some extra money.
让那家店没法经营
Putting this place out of action.
让那家店倒闭
Putting this... putting this place out of commission.
谁让你干的
For who?
现在可不是保持沉默的时候
Now is not the time to not say.
悄悄话
Whispers.
另一个悄悄话
The other Whispers.
你知道典范布品服务公司的老板是谁吗
You know who owns the Cadillac Linen Service?
做洗衣行业的犹太人
Some Jews in the laundry business.
-雇主是这么说的  -他们只占部分股份
- That's what they told me. - They own a part of it.
还有人是老板
Somebody else got an interest in that.
-你知道是谁吗  -不
- You know who? - No.
也可以理解为"是我"
我知道
I do.
-是谁  -不  是我
- Who? - No. I do.
其他的股份是我的
I own the other part.
而不是我认识持有剩余股份的人
Not I know somebody who owns the other part.
安吉洛  我不知道你有这家公司的股份
Angelo, I didn't know you had any part of it.
我要是知道的话
I would never have done what I did
是绝对不会那么做的  我不知道
if I knew you were involved. I didn't know.
我绝不会对你做这种事
I would never, never do that against you.
悄悄话没说老板是犹太黑帮吗
Whispers didn't tell you it was Jew mob?
没有  他说是犹太洗衣妇
No, he said Jew washerwomen.
犹太洗衣妇
Jew washerwomen.
他还说了什么
What else he say?
我猜他让你保密
I bet he said keep it to yourself.
别跟城里其他人透露一个字
Don't say nothing to nobody Downtown.
的确
He did.
我没核实
I didn't check.
对不起  我应该先核实一下的
I'm sorry. I should've checked.
-我能把钱退给他吗  -他用不着了
- Can I give him his money back? - He won't need it.
你留着吧
You can keep it.
我不想惹麻烦
I... I don't want no trouble.
我把钱退给他吧  我没关系
I'll just give it back to him and I'm okay.
他用不着了
He won't need it.
好吧  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
谢罗素吧
Thank Russell.
我本来不想浪费时间
I wouldn't have wasted my time.
打算让犹太黑帮找你算账
I'd have let the Jew mob have you.
你这个朋友真没得说
You got a good friend here.
你不知道他多仗义
You don't know how good a friend you got.
-我知道  -不  你不知道
- I... I know. - No, you don't know.
去吧台那等着吧
Wait by the bar, would you?
像这种情况
In a case like this,
最好的办法就是用全新的家伙
the best thing to do is you use something brand new.
刚开箱的
Right out of the box.
否则  你不知道它在哪里被用过
Otherwise, you don't know where it's been.
或被谁用过
You don't know who's used it,
跟什么案子有关联
what crime it was connected to.
那无异于找死
That's suicide.
所以我推荐用全新的  刚开箱的
So I recommend something new, straight out of the... the box.
冰冷  干净
Stone cold. Clean.
你来了
There you are.
我不知道你会从哪边过来
I didn't know which way you were coming from.
我不知道你从哪边...
I didn't know which way you were...
当然  下一步就是
Naturally, the next thing you wanna do
把家伙扔掉  你得毁灭证据
is throw the thing away. You wanna get rid of it.
大家都扔在斯古吉尔河的一个地方
There's a spot in the Schuylkill River everybody uses.
如果派人潜到河底
If they ever send divers down there,
找到的武器够武装一个小国家了
they'd be able to arm a small country.
一名男子在人行道上被枪杀
对我来说  杀死悄悄话后  一切都变了
For me, everything changed after Whispers.
这就像在军队
It was like the army.
你服从命令
You followed orders.
听吩咐做事
You did the right thing.
就会得到相应的奖赏
You got rewarded.
罗马别墅餐厅酒吧
我替罗素做事
And when I handled things for Russell,
从来都不是为钱
it was never for money,
而是为了表达尊重
but as a show of respect.
你给他跑跑腿  帮帮忙
When you ran a little errand, you did a little favor,
当你需要帮忙的时候  他也还你人情
you got a little favor back if you ever needed it.
你总是会需要帮忙的
And you always hurried back.
-菲尔  你好啊  -你好
- Phil, how you doing? - How are you?
See the Pyramids Along the Nile - Patti Page
♪ See the pyramids along the Nile ♪
菲尔·泰斯塔
1981年3月15日于自家门廊被一枚钉子炸弹炸死
你好  弗兰克
How you doing, Frank?
♪ Watch the sun rise on a tropic isle ♪
弗兰克·辛德文
1980年10月29日身中三枪死于巷子内
♪ Just remember, darling, all the while ♪
谢谢  维托
Thank you, Vito.
♪ You belong to me... ♪
-你好  弗兰克  -你好
- Hi. Frank. - Hi.
你要来点什么吗
What can I get for you?
先给我上杯酒吧
I'm just gonna get the wine now.
好的
Okay.
有需要尽管叫我
Just call me if you need anything.
好的
I will.
-慢用  弗兰克  -谢谢
- Help yourself, Frank. - Thanks.
情况变了
Things change.
-她是新来的吧  -对
- She's the new one, right? - Yeah.
她是个好姑娘  好姑娘
A nice kid. Nice kid.
是啊
Yeah.
♪ I'll be so alone without you ♪
什么时候都不应该离开你的妻子
No time is a good time to leave your wife,
汽车旅馆
但我就是那时候离开妻子的
but that's when I left mine.
阿德斯里埃克斯汽车旅馆
授权人签字
埃拉  最近还好吗
Ira, what's going on?
-挺好的  你呢  -我也是
- Good. All well? - Yes.
-有遇到什么麻烦吗  -没有  一切顺利
- Any problems? - No. Everything's good.
谢谢你
Thank you.
就停在这辆凯迪拉克后面
Right after this Caddy, pull over.
到了  美丽皮草店
There it is. Fair Furriers.
美丽皮草店
他在等你
He's expecting you.
美丽皮草店
菲尔  你的店真不错
Phil, you got a nice shop here.
谢谢
Thanks.
人们喜欢来这里逛
People like to come to this store.
但你儿子真是个瘪三
But your kid is a real sfigato.
明白吗  他很讨人厌
You understand? He's a pain in the ass.
他太野了  你得管管他
He's a wild kid. You gotta learn to control him.
如果你不管
And if you don't,
就再也没人想来这里逛了
nobody's gonna want to shop here anymore.
如果你的生意不好  对我也没有好处
If it's not good for you, it's not good for me.
你明白我的意思吧
You understand what I'm saying.
罗素  他给你惹麻烦了  我向你道歉
I want to apologize, Russell, for the aggravation.
这份是我和罗素送的  那份是你和弗兰克送的
This is from Russell and I. That's from you and Frank.
这个是我们俩送的
This one'll be from you and me.
要不送把宝宝汤匙吧
Well, what about a baby spoon?
她要宝宝汤匙有什么用
What's she gonna do with a baby spoon?
-他们还没结婚  -生个孩子就能用了
- They're not even married. - Have a baby.
他们都还没结婚呢
They're not even married yet.
我向你保证  罗素
I give you my word, Russ.
-好的  你的话我信  菲尔  -谢谢
- All right. Your word's good, Phil. - Thank you.
好了  我们走吧  女士们
Okay, let's go, girls.
-完事了  -是的  弄完了
- Okay, we're done? - Yes, we're done.
你在搞什么
What are you doing?
-你什么时候才能机灵点  -什么
- When the hell are you gonna wise up, huh? - What?
好样的  不愧是我女儿
There we go. That's my girl.
天呐
Oh, my God!
太棒了
Yes!
佩琪
Peggy.
过来一下
Come over here.
我说不好  我...
I don't know. I don't...
我感觉她不喜欢我
I get the feeling she don't like me.
-她好像有点怕我  -不  不是的
- Like she's afraid of me. - No, no.
她就是这样
That's the way she is.
有时她也会怕我
She's afraid of me at times too.
她就是有点敏感
So, uh, it's just she's a sensitive kid,
敏感而已
but that's all it is.
我能理解她怕我
I can understand her being afraid of me,
但是她不应该怕你  弗兰克
but she shouldn't be scared of you, Frank.
是
No, well...
有时她会在报纸上看到关于我的报道
And then she hears about me in the papers sometimes...
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
你要跟自己的孩子亲一点  弗兰克
You gotta be close to your kids, Frank.
我们很亲近
I am. I am.
有孩子是你的福分
You're blessed to have them.
凯丽和我没有小孩  我跟你说过
I mean, Carrie and I can't have kids. I told you.
你真是有福气  有福气
But you're blessed. You're blessed.
叫她一下  叫她过来
Call her. Call her. Tell her to come over.
佩琪宝贝  过来
Sweetheart. Peggy. Come here.
过来
Come here.
-过来  -到罗素伯伯这里来
- Come here. - Come over by Uncle Russ.
-你好吗  -挺好的
- How are you? - Good.
你知道为什么上帝会把天空造这么高吗
Do you know why God made the sky so high?
不知道
No.
这样小鸟在天上飞的时候
So that the little birdies don't bunk their head on it
才不会碰到头啊
when they're flying around.
可爱吧
Isn't that cute?
这是一个小笑话
A little joke.
不好笑吗
Isn't that funny?
你要吃点糖果什么的吗
You want some candy or something?
不用了
No.
不  你们不想吃糖
No, you guys don't want any candy.
需要我为你做点什么吗
There's nothing I could do for you?
不用了
No.
需要的话你要告诉罗素伯伯
Well, if there is, you let Uncle Russell know.
好
Okay.
回去玩吧
Go back. Have some fun.
知道我什么意思了吗
You see what I mean?
明白我的感觉了吗
You see that feeling I get?
她就是  腼腆而已
She's just... She's shy, that's all.
她没有恶意
She... She don't mean nothing.
有时候  父母离婚了
Sometimes, when the parents get divorced,
孩子们就会迷茫  然后他们会充满恨意
the kids get all confused, and then they get resentful
不知道该向谁发泄
and they don't know who to take it out on,
或是站哪边
or, you know, which side, or...
不  你说得对
No, you're right.
但是这一点我很幸运
I'm lucky in that way because
因为琳妮和玛丽相处得很好
Reenie and Mary, they get along like gangbusters,
孩子们轮流在两家住  没什么问题
so the kids go back and forth with no problem.
要把家人留在身边  留意这一点
Keep your family close. Keep an eye on that.
我就是提醒你一下
Anyway, I'm just telling you, you know.
我想我就是运气好
I mean, I'm... I'm just lucky.
是啊
Yeah.
工会的工作怎么样
How's it going with the union?
工会是世界上最好的
The union's the best in the world.
-你喜欢  -是啊  只是...
- You like it, huh? - Yeah, well, it's just...
我想要找个稳定点的工作  不过
I mean, I wish I had something more steady, but...
就是有些
Yeah, it's...
-管理怎么样  -好啊
- How about organizing? - Yeah.
-我想干那个  可是  -怎么
- I would like to do that. But... - Yeah?
很多人都等着呢
there's a long line.
-换句话说  等候名单很长  -是
- A long waiting list, if you will. - Yeah.
我们的一个朋友遇到了一点麻烦
Well, a friend of ours is having a little trouble.
-高层的朋友  -谁啊
- Friend at the top. - Who's that?
高层
The top.
霍法
Hoffa?
嗯
Yeah.
之前我听说
I heard the other day
有人要用水管揍他
that some guys tried to pipe him
-因为一个工人的赔偿问题  -是的
- because of a workman's comp case. - Yeah.
听说他把他们打得落花流水
Yeah, I heard he beat the shit out of them.
是  可他那样能撑多久呢
Yeah, but how long is he gonna keep doing that?
总有这事儿那事儿
Things are gonna keep happening.
他身边需要一个可靠的人
He needs somebody he can trust around him.
一个可以一直跟着他的人
Somebody to be with him all the time.
是
Yeah.
我让麦基接电话
Let me put McGee on the phone.
喂
Hello.
我的朋友  你好吗
Hiya, my friend. How are you?
我找来了我跟你说过的那个年轻人
Listen, I got that kid I was talking to you about here.
我让他接电话  你跟他说  好吗
I'm gonna put him on the phone, let you talk to him, okay?
好的
All right.
你好
Hello.
-是弗兰克吧  -是我
- Is that Frank? - Yes.
弗兰克你好  我是吉米·霍法
Hiya, Frank. This is Jimmy Hoffa.
你好  很高兴认识你
Yeah, yeah. Glad to meet you.
我也很高兴认识你  虽然是在电话上
Well, glad to meet you, too, even if it's over the phone.
听说你刷房子
I heard you paint houses.
是的  先生  是的
Yes. Yes, sir, I... I do. I do.
我还
And I, uh...
自己做木工
I also do my own carpentry.
很高兴你这么说
I'm glad to hear that.
听说你是工会的兄弟
I understand you're a brother of mine.
是的  先生  从1947年就在107号地方工会了
Yes, sir. Local 107. Since 1947.
是吧
Yeah! You know, uh,
我们的朋友对你评价非常高
our friend speaks very highly of you.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
-他这个人要求可不低  -我尽力而为
- He's not an easy man to please. - Well, I do my best.
有这么个情况
Well, you know, there's a situation...
如今  年轻人不知道吉米·霍法是谁
Nowadays, young people, they don't know who Jimmy Hoffa was.
他们完全没概念
They don't have a clue.
他们可能知道他消失了什么的
I mean, maybe they know that he disappeared or something,
但仅此而已
but that's about it.
可在当时  全国上下
But back then, there wasn't nobody in this country
吉米·霍法
没人不知道吉米·霍法是谁
who didn't know who Jimmy Hoffa was.
上帝保佑  吉米
God bless, Jimmy.
你做的一切  你是个真正的绅士
Everything you've done, you're a real gentleman.
很好
That's good.
50年代的时候  他和猫王一样受欢迎
In the '50s, he was as big as Elvis.
60年代的时候  他和披头士一样受欢迎
In the '60s, he was like the Beatles.
除了总统以外
Next to the president,
他是国内最有权力的人  无人可及
he was like the most powerful man in the country. Bar none.
你如果买东西
If you got it,
卡车会把东西送过去
a truck brought it to you.
卡车司机工会
如果你买食物  衣服
If you got your food, your clothing,
药物  家用燃料
your medicine, if you got fuel for your homes,
工业用燃料
fuel for your industries,
卡车会把东西送去给他们
a truck brought it to them!
我们卡车停下的那天
The day our trucks stop,
就是美国停下的那天
America stops!
现在出了点状况  弗兰克
Well, there's a situation going on now, Frank,
需要处理
that needs to be attended to.
他们想分裂工会
You know, they're trying to tear the union apart.
大公司和政府联手
Big business and the government working together,
想要拉我们下马
trying to pull us down.
大公司在进攻
Big business is on the attack!
他们来了  来势汹汹
They're coming! They're coming hard
长驱直入
and they're coming fast!
大公司和政府
Big business and the government
想要在我们的阶层里埋下异议的种子
are trying to sow the seeds of dissent among our ranks,
而此时我们正需要联合
at a time when we need unity!
我们需要团结
We need solidarity!
我想把这话写在空中
I want to write it in the sky.
团结
Solidarity!
你想加入这场战斗吗
You wanna be a part of this fight?
是的  先生
Yes, I do, sir.
你想成为这历史的一部分吗
Would you like to be a part of this history?
是的  我想
Yes, I would.
无论你需要我做什么  我都随叫随到
Whatever you need me to do, I'm available.
你明天能来芝加哥吗
Can you come to Chicago tomorrow?
可以  先生
Yes, I can, sir.
那好  到时见
All right, then. See you then.
-他喜欢说话  对吗  -是的
- He likes to talk, don't he? - Yeah.
还以为我是在跟巴顿将军说话
Thought I was talking to General Patton.
弗兰克  你过来的唯一原因是
You know, Frank, the only reason why you're here,
海员工会  他们想和我们一样
the Seafarers Union, they're signing up
俄罗斯人和土耳其人浴室
签约非工会的
the same non-union cab drivers
出租车司机
as we want to do.
没人知道你是谁
Nobody knows who you are
没人知道你在这做什么  好吗
and nobody knows what the fuck you're doing here. Okay?
-嗯  -只有你我知道你为何来此
- Yeah. - You and I know why you're here.
我们得签约这些司机
We gotta be able to sign these drivers up
这样保罗·霍尔的工会就签约不了他们
so Paul Hall doesn't get 'em for his fucking union.
不知为何  女同性恋
For some reason, lesbians.
这些司机大多都是该死的女同性恋
Most of these drivers are fucking lesbians.
我不知道为什么
I have no reason why.
保罗·霍尔四处宣传
Paul Hall's running around
说他可以比我们的哥们吉米
saying that he's gonna get a better contract
提供一份更好的合同
than our boy fucking Jimmy.
他就是个狗杂种
He's a cocksucker. Yeah.
吉米收买了戴利市长
Jimmy has Mayor fucking Daley in his pocket.
我们做什么警察都不会管
The cops are okay with whatever the fuck we do.
他们不会帮我们把车推下水
They're not gonna help us push these cars in,
但他们也绝对不会让任何人阻止我们
but they certainly are not gonna let anybody fucking stop us.
懂吗
Okay?
用力  大伙儿用力
Come on! All of you guys. Come on!
把车子推下去  小心点
Let's get this fucking thing in there. Watch yourself!
太费劲了
This is a lot of work.
你有想过用糖果吗
Yeah, you ever think of using candy?
-什么  -糖果
- What? - Candy.
糖果是什么鬼
What the fuck is candy?
炸药  轻拿轻放
卢  把门打开
Hey, Lou, open the fucking gate.
知道  知道
I got it. I got it.
来  你把汽油拿着
Here, you take the gas.
弗兰克  吉米有个特点
Frank, there's one thing about Jimmy.
他不喜欢等人
Don't ever make him wait.
如果你和他约好见面  你一定要准时到场
If you make a meeting with him, you get there on time.
最好是提前到
Better yet, get there early.
我必须强调这一点
I can't stress this enough.
他觉得时间很可贵
His problem is that time is of essence.
这是最重要的
And that's the important thing.
我还要跟你说件事  吉米不喝酒
I gotta tell you one more thing. Jimmy doesn't drink.
是的  世界上最大的货运工会的老大
Yeah. The head of the largest trucking union in the world,
他不喝酒
he don't drink.
这事最糟的地方在于
The worst part about it is,
他不允许别人在他身边喝酒
he doesn't allow anybody to drink around him.
还有件事
Another thing about him,
吉米讨厌西瓜
Jimmy hates fucking watermelon.
但我们喜欢西瓜
But we're gonna like watermelon.
吉米  你当时真该去看看
Jimmy, you shoulda seen it,
慢慢沉下水
sinking in the water.
一辆接一辆  我敢打赌  等他们隔天醒来
One by one. I bet you, when they woke up the next morning,
那些该死的出租车司机
those fucking cab drivers,
他们去找自己的出租车
they went to look for their cabs,
他们根本不知道发生了什么
they didn't know what the fuck hit 'em.
真是个好主意  乔伊
That's a great idea, Joey.
好主意
Great idea.
不是我想出来的
Well, it wasn't my idea.
我哥们弗兰克  是他的主意
My man Frank. It was his idea.
我跟你说
Let me tell you something.
弗兰克去了码头  他接管了码头
Frank hit that pier, he took over the pier.
不管他叫他们做什么  不管他说什么
Whatever he told them to do, whatever he said,
他们都照做
they did it, you know.
我从没见过任何人像他那样穿过人群
I never seen a guy walk through a crowd like he does.
他一个人都不碰
He doesn't touch a fucking person!
所有人都自觉让路
Everybody gets out of the way.
我没开玩笑  我发誓
I'm not kidding you. I swear.
那些人和他素不相识  就像
Guys he never met in his life. You know, it was like...
就像摩西  记得摩西吗
like Moses. Remember Moses?
他走进海洋还是大海
When he walked into the ocean, the sea,
不管是什么  水面就分开了
whatever the fuck it was, and it opened up!
就是他  相信我  吉米  他有那能力
That's him. I'm telling you. Jimmy, he's got it.
你觉得如何
So, what do you think?
你还需要他在这待几天吗
You need him a couple of days more?
是的  我们还有一些零碎的事要处理
Yeah, we gotta clear up a few dribs and drabs.
你们真喜欢西瓜啊
You guys sure like watermelon.
想吃一口吗
Want a bite?
决不
Not on your life.
你当时在场  你亲眼看到了
You were there. You saw it firsthand.
那些人不是工会
Those guys ain't union.
他们就像是纳粹同谋  在战场后方行动
They're like Nazi collaborators, operating behind the lines.
-你懂的  你打过仗  -没错
- You know. You were in the war. - I sure do.
在战争期间  你从一个地方转移到另一个地方
In a war, you go from point A to point B.
有时候
Sometimes,
你会在路上洒一些啤酒
you spill a little beer along the way.
你觉得这哲学有道理吗
That philosophy make sense to you?
当然
Sure does.
很好
Good.
吉米  他不是因为喜欢我
Jimmy, he didn't make me stay in his suite
而让我住他的套房
because he liked me.
他让我跟他一起住是因为他不想让我
He made me stay with him because he didn't want me
用我的名字在酒店登记
registering in my name at the hotel.
这样  就没有证据证明我去过芝加哥
This way, there was no proof I was even in Chicago.
加油  吉米  你落后好多
Come on, Jimmy, you're way behind.
什么都阻止不了她
Nothing stops her.
芝加哥那事之后  我和吉米走得更近了
After Chicago, Jimmy and I got close.
老婆们也相处得很融洽
The wives hit it off.
因为吉米和约瑟芬的孩子
And with Jimmy and Josephine's kids
大多已成年  离开了家
mostly grown up and out of the house,
他们从我们孩子身上也获得不少乐趣
they got a kick out of our kids too.
吉米  佩琪  来拍张照
Jimmy, Peggy, let's get a picture.
"约"·霍法
好  快来
Oh. Yes. Come on.
尤其是佩琪
Especially Peggy.
她和吉米  他们一下就喜欢上了对方
She and Jimmy, they fell for each other right away.
你知道比起拍照我更喜欢什么吗
You know what I like even better than getting my picture took?
什么
What?
惊喜吧
Surprise!
佩琪
Peggy!
对佩琪来说  吉米不像罗素
To Peggy, Jimmy wasn't like Russ,
韦尔冰淇淋店
不像瘦子也不像我
or Skinny or even me.
抱歉各位  这是买给我和佩琪的
Sorry, everybody. This is just for Peggy and I.
一方面  吉米没有绰号
For one thing, Jimmy didn't have a nickname
比如"剃刀"或者"钟楼怪人"
like "The Razor," Or "The Hunchback,"
或者"黄鼠狼"亦或者"悄悄话"
or "The Weasel," Or "Whispers."
怎么不说谢谢
So what happened to "Thank you"?
谢谢
Thank you!
还有  对她来说  他是在帮助人
And also, to her, he was helping people.
他在帮他们赚更多钱  过得更好
He was helping them make more money, live better lives.
他没有踩别人的手
He wasn't stomping on somebody's hand.
"如果你买东西  卡车会把东西送过去"
"'If you have it, a truck brought it to you."
这是霍法先生说的
This is what Mr. Hoffa says.
职业介绍日  1960年
他是卡车司机工会的主席
He's the president of the Teamsters Union
成员超过一百万
with over a million members.
他们都支持他因为他们有稳定的工作
They all support him because they have steady jobs,
我是吉米·霍法的朋友
丰厚的薪水以及退休后的养老金
great pay and a pension for when they retire.
卡车司机养老基金
The Teamster Pension Fund
有八十亿美元
had eight billion dollars in it.
全部都由吉米控制
And Jimmy had complete control over every bit of it.
沙丘酒店
这模型是不是很美
Isn't this a beautiful presentation?
我只想要一笔过渡性贷款  吉米
I mean, a bridge loan is really all I'm asking, Jimmy.
我不会把工会成员的养老金
I'm not gonna piss away my members' pension dough
投资在风险过大的项目上
on something too risky.
这没有风险  吉米
This is not a risk, Jimmy.
《明斯基的荒唐事》这个节目是我的
I got Minsky's Follies.
赌城大道第一个露乳舞女秀是我的
I got the first topless act on the Strip.
相信我  我们在那的生意可好了
I'm telling you, we're booming in there.
酒都卖不过来...
I can't get the drinks out...
我就想要建一个高尔夫球场
Just asking for a golf course.
你知道我从未让你损失一分钱
You know you never lost a dime with me.
吉米  我们会很感激
Jimmy, we'd really just appreciate
你帮杰克做的事的
whatever you could do to help Jake along here.
我只需要150万的完工保证金
One-five is all I need for a completion bond.
好吧  去拿钱吧
Okay. Okay. Go to the bank.
谢谢  这个项目会大获成功的
Thank you. It's gonna be a big success.
谢谢你  吉米  你是王子
Thank you, Jimmy. You're a prince.
-你是好人  -是的  我是好人
- You're a mensch. - Yeah, I'm a mensch.
多亏了霍法先生
And, because of Mr. Hoffa,
工人生病时有医疗保险
workers have medical insurance for when they get sick,
他们知道退休后  不会挨饿
and know when they retire, they're not going to go hungry.
当时有太多的文书工作
There was so much paperwork back then
吉米只能用一个叫艾伦·多夫曼的年轻人开的
that Jimmy had to use an insurance company
一家保险公司来处理贷款
that was run by this kid, Allen Dorfman, to work out the loans.
不  一分钱都不借
No, no, nothing for nothing.
下次  试试口气好一点
Next time, try asking a little bit fucking nicer.
艾伦·多夫曼  1979年
在芝加哥的一处停车场头中八枪身亡
然后呢  进展如何
And? And? How'd it go?
情况一度很危急
It was a little touch and go for a little bit.
-但是最后还是顺利达成了  -很好
- But at the end, fine. - Good.
是罗素让吉米
It was Russ who got Jimmy
给戈特利布这样的人贷款
to give guys like Gottlieb the loans,
他能分到一成
and, you know, he would get like 10% of that.
我也不知道  也许更多
Or whatever, you know. Maybe more.
听着  你告诉马尔特杜佐我很感激
Listen, you tell Marteduzzo from me that I appreciate it.
人人都会感激
And everybody's gonna appreciate it.
这是好事
It's a good thing.
行  我会的
Okay. I'll do that.
那时  你不能去普通银行
Back then, you couldn't go to regular banks
因为钱是用来赌博的
because the money was for gambling.
千真万确  就是这样  我没开玩笑  不能去
God's truth, that's what it was. I'm serious. You couldn't.
所以黑手党  他们怎么办呢
So the Mob, what did they do?
他们找卡车司机工会贷款
They went to the Teamsters for the money.
是卡车司机工会介入其中
It was the Teamsters that stepped in
他们借出的钱打造了拉斯维加斯
and lent the money that built Las Vegas.
-这是红木  -别  比利
- This is the mahogany... - Don't, Billy.
-别碰  -我不碰
- Don't touch the stuff. - I won't.
-该上哪去上哪去  -好
- Just go where you gotta go. - Okay.
当时的生意多得让人应接不暇
There was more business than anybody could handle.
所以吉米把一些生意
So Jimmy had to shove some of the deals
塞给了他老婆约
off on to his wife Jo,
她完全不知道
who had no idea she had 22%
她拥有一个叫"太阳谷"的
of a Florida land deal
佛州土地交易公司22%的股份
called "Sun Valley,"
几艘包租渔船
some charter fishing boats,
以及一个带私家雪山的滑雪度假屋
and a ski lodge with its own mountain.
吉米有个客户叫山姆·詹卡纳  绰号"莫莫"
One of Jimmy's clients was Sam "Momo" Giancana,
他和肯尼迪家族是世交
who was friends with the Kennedys from back
这两家自约翰·肯尼迪的父亲在禁酒令期间走私酒
when Jack's father made his fortune with the Italians
和意大利人一起赚大钱时就认识了
as a bootlegger during Prohibition.
露希尔·亨特
刘易斯·康宁汉姆
玛丽昂·希克斯
德妮思·鲍威尔
艾米特·伍兹
莫莫和辛纳屈跟肯尼迪家族混
Momo, Sinatra hung out together with the Kennedys.
艾米特·伍兹
莫莫和肯尼迪
Momo and Kennedy,
不管你信不信  甚至有同一个女友
believe it or not, even had the same girlfriend.
在同一时期
Together. At the same time.
真是太疯狂了
Talk about crazy.
所以对黑手党来说  帮助乔·肯尼迪
So it was easy for the Mob to help Joe Kennedy
让他儿子当选总统很容易  非常容易
get his son elected president. That was easy.
他们操控了选票
They just punched up the vote a little
确保他在伊利诺伊州胜出
to make sure that he won in Illinois.
雷蒙德·克拉克
艾米特·伍兹
作为交换
In exchange for that,
新上台的总统要把卡斯特罗从古巴赶下台
the new president was supposedly gonna get Castro out of Cuba
这样我们的人就能拿回他们的赌场
so our guys could get their casinos back,
赛马场  捕虾船
and race tracks, and shrimp boats,
以及他们在哈瓦那
and everything else that they had,
曾拥有的一切
and owned down there from Havana back.
不过那事没成
But that... that didn't happen.
投民主党
意大利人想让爱尔兰人肯尼迪当总统
The Italians wanted Kennedy the Irishman for president,
他们如愿了
and that's what they got.
习惯吧  因为以后我们每时每刻都得看到了
Get used to it, because we're gonna be seeing it 24/7.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
该死的肯尼迪家族
Goddamn Kennedys.
我在看该死的肯尼迪家族
I'm looking at the goddamn Kennedys.
吉米  孩子们都在呢  注意言辞
Jimmy, the kids. Language.
有什么差别
What difference does it make?
他们迟早都要学会的
I mean, they gotta learn sooner or later.
我们要和这些人开战
We're going to war with these people.
开战
War!
我已经说了无数次了
If I said it once, I said it a thousand times,
我不在乎他们是不是爱尔兰人
I don't care they're Irish.
我不在乎他们是不是天主教徒
I don't care they're Catholic.
如果要说这辈子有谁你不能信
If there's one person you can't trust in this life,
那就是百万富翁的孩子
it's millionaires' kids.
你说得对  吉米
You're right, Jimmy.
尤其是那个小杂种
Especially that little son of a bitch.
你是说你不记得
Are you saying you don't remember
你帮过约翰尼·迪奥吗
doing any favors for Johnny Dio,
罗伯特·肯尼迪
还是说你不记得你们的对话
or you don't remember the conversation?
我是说  我已经尽力回忆了
I'm saying, to the best of my recollection,
根据我的回忆
I must recall on my memory,
我想不起来了
I cannot remember.
那这两万块是哪来的
Then where did this $20,000 come from?
个人的
Individuals.
哪些个人  霍法先生
Which individuals, Mr. Hoffa?
未经核查的情况下  这笔我借的钱
Off hand, that particular amount of money I borrowed,
我目前也想不起是找谁借的
I don't know at this particular moment.
但是根据我取得的贷款记录
But the record of my loans, which I requested, I have,
在这段时间内
and out of all the moneys I loaned
我贷款的所有钱  都投资给了这些企业
during this period of time I went into these ventures.
该死的肯尼迪家族
Those goddamn Kennedys,
他们总是得偿所愿
they get what they want!
吉米  吉米  孩子们在呢
Jimmy. Jimmy, the kids.
他已经让我
Him and all the bullshit problems
-处处受制  -吉米
- he put me through already. - Jimmy.
我得走了  别指望我看这个
I gotta go. You don't expect me to look at this.
我不指望
No, I don't.
对罗素这样的人来说
For guys like Russ,
那最好不过了
it couldn't have been better.
支持肯尼迪当总统
我是说  罗素
I mean, Russ,
支持肯尼迪当总统
肯尼迪当选他也有出力
oh, yeah, he did his part for getting Kennedy elected,
支持肯尼迪当总统
这点毫无疑问
that's for sure.
你在做什么  我叫你把它...
What are you doing? I told you to put it...
我叫你贴到所有杆子上
I told you to put them on every pole.
你还在这瞎转
You're still walking around.
所以约翰·肯尼迪
So what's the first thing
为了感谢芝加哥的帮助做的第一件事是什么
that Jack Kennedy does to thank Chicago for all their help?
他让他的垃圾弟弟上位了
He puts his shitass brother in there,
那个预科学校混蛋
that little prep school punk,
他让他成了司法部长
and he winds up making him attorney general.
鲍比上任后做的第一件事是什么
And what's the first thing Bobby does?
他不仅对付吉米
He goes after not just Jimmy,
从某种程度上讲  你也能理解
which in a way you could understand.
吉米无比厌恶肯尼迪家族
I mean, Jimmy hated the Kennedys so much
以至于他从工会拿了五十万给尼克松
he gave Nixon $500,000 in Teamster cash.
但鲍比还去对付詹卡纳
But Bobby also goes after Giancana,
马切洛  特拉菲坎特  以及其他所有
Marcello, Trafficante, and all the other guys
当初帮他哥哥入住白宫的人
who put his brother in the White House in the first place.
那是在干什么
What's that about?
弗兰克
Frank.
-谢谢  -圣诞快乐
- Thank you. - Merry Christmas.
我是漏掉了什么吗
Am I missing something?
谢谢你  凯丽
Thank you, Carrie.
-太漂亮了  -真美
- That's gorgeous. - Beautiful.
戴着它健健康康  我们爱你
Wear it in the best of health. We love you.
这是给佩琪的
Okay, now this one is for Peggy
罗素伯伯送的  圣诞快乐  亲爱的
from Uncle Russell. Merry Christmas, my love.
看呀
Oh, look at those.
太好了
So nice!
我听说你喜欢滑冰
I heard you like to skate.
你该说什么
What do you say?
谢谢
Thank you.
现在我和罗素伯伯可以带你去滑冰了
Now me and Uncle Russell could take you ice skating.
我想圣诞老人
I think Santa Claus left you
在里面还给你留了点东西
a little something extra in there too.
你该对罗素伯伯说什么
What do you say to Uncle Russell?
你该说什么
What do you say?
弗兰克  没关系
Frank, it's all right.
她已经说了一次谢谢了  这就够了
She said thank you once. That's enough.
因为鲍比是司法部长  他们把我们盯得很紧
With Bobby as attorney general, I mean, they were all over us.
我们不能在电话里说事
I mean, we couldn't talk on the phone
因为我们知道有人窃听
because we knew it was being bugged.
你什么都不能做  哪也不能去
You couldn't do nothing. You couldn't go nowhere.
什么都做不了
You couldn't do anything.
总之情况特别糟糕
It was a bad, bad, bad situation.
然后吉米  算了
And then Jimmy... Forget it.
鲍比  现在作为司法部长  他有权力
Bobby, now as attorney general, he has the power
送任何人进监狱  毋庸置疑
to send anybody to jail, and no question about it.
吉米在鲍比的打击对象名单上名列前茅
And Jimmy was at the top of Bobby's hit list.
他甚至组建了一只专门的"抓捕霍法小队"
He even set up a special "Get Hoffa Squad,"
他找来了联调局
where he had his own guys from the FBI,
还有国税局的人夜以继日地工作
the IRS working 'round the clock.
他们唯一的工作就是送吉米·霍法进监狱
Their only job was to put Jimmy Hoffa in jail.
我是认真的  他们只干了这事
I'm serious. That's all they did.
这房间里全是该死的蠢货
I am sitting in a room full of fuckin' idiots.
一群傻逼
You dumb motherfuckers!
你们知道你们做了什么吗
You know what you did?
你们找来约翰尼·奥鲁克的孩子
You take Johnny O'Rourke's kid
你们让他
and you put him on
成为总组织者
as general organizer,
支付了他3.6万
pay him 36 fucking grand,
与此同时
at the same time,
你们让他卖保险给他爸爸的...
you let him sell insurance to his fucking father's...
他爸爸的...
to his fucking father's...
卖给他爸爸的地方工会
to his fucking father's locals!
该死
Damn it!
怎么能犯这种错
How do you do that?
你们是有多蠢
How stupid can you be?
那该死的狗杂种肯尼迪
That fucking cocksucker Kennedy
我去哪他都盯着我
has got his nose up my ass everywhere I go!
你们不知道他对我紧追不舍吗
You don't know that they're hounding me?
他们监视我做的每件事
They're looking at everything I do.
你们却让这发生在大庭广众之下
And you let this happen in public!
你们成全了他
You're giving it to him!
我要去坐牢了  懂吗
I'm going to jail. You understand?
拜你们所赐  我要去坐牢了
I'm going to prison because of you,
一群蠢货
you dumb motherfuckers.
这是你们想要的  你们想让我进监狱
This is what you wanted. You wanted to put me in jail.
告诉我  好让我就地杀了你们
Tell me now so I can kill you right here.
就地
Right here!
你去哪
Where're you going?
什么叫"我去哪"
What do you mean, where am I going?
我他妈不干了  这就是我要去的地方
I fucking quit, that's where I'm going.
你为什么不干了
What are you quitting for?
你叫我蠢货
You gonna call me a motherfucker?
你可以这么跟他们说话  但跟我不行
You can talk to them like that, you can't talk to me like that.
弗兰克  不  我没说你  你...
Frank. No! That didn't apply to you. What are you...
-没说我  -是的
- Didn't apply? - No!
那你要告诉我你没在说我
Then you gotta let me know it didn't apply to me.
我就站在那
I'm standing right there.
我根本没看到你站在那
I didn't even see you standing there!
我就站在那  吉米
I was standing right there, Jimmy.
你胡扯什么呢
What are you talking about?
但我没在说你  我还能说什么
But it didn't apply to you! What else can I say?
你有问题的话  就先把我拉到一边
You got a problem, you pull me aside.
你不能辱骂了我然后又说你没在说我
You don't insult me and then you say it didn't apply to me.
我要怎么把你拉到一边  我根本没看到你
How am I gonna put you aside? I didn't even see you there.
拜托  弗兰克  你知道我不是那样的人
Oh, come on, Frank, you know me better than that.
你知道我不是那样的人
You just know me better than that.
拜托
Please.
来吧  不会有事的
Come on. It's gonna be all right.
不会有事的  来
It's gonna be all right. Come on.
来  我为什么要对你说那样的话
Come on, why would I ever say anything like that to you?
你得控制这些人
You gotta control these people.
一切都在掌控之中  别担心
I'm controlling everything. Don't worry about it.
但是当然  当然  我...你懂的
But certainly, certainly, I... you know.
来  各位  出去
Come on. Okay, guys, get out of here now.
我不知道吉米是怎么管理工会的
I mean, I don't know how Jimmy is running the fucking union.
鲍比和联调局总是盯着他
Between Bobby and the FBI up his ass all the time,
他都快疯了
he's going fucking crazy.
告诉吉米  我为他的麻烦感到遗憾
Tell Jimmy I'm sorry for his troubles.
老一辈认识老肯尼迪  他们会去和他谈
The old-timers know the Old Man. They'll talk to him.
他们会跟他讲清楚的
At some point, they'll straighten it out for him.
但他无法理解
Yeah, but he can't understand,
我和你说实话  我也无法理解
and I gotta be honest with you, I don't understand either,
你们最初怎么就让混蛋肯尼迪兄弟
how youse could help get those two fucking Kennedy pricks
当选了
elected in the first place.
他肯定没法理解
It don't make no sense to him, that's for sure.
他不必事事都理解
He doesn't have to understand everything.
你明白我的意思  有时这样更好
You know what I'm talking about. Sometimes it's better.
这个...
Well...
只是我看到他那样  我没法
It's when I see him like that, I don't, you know,
我想...我感觉不好受
I... I'm tryin' to... I feel bad.
我想怎么也得帮帮他
I wanna help him in some way.
听我说  他太情绪化了
Listen, he's too emotional.
就像是个到处折腾来
Like some guy who's always rushing,
折腾去  却看不清大局的人
rushing all over the place and they miss the big picture.
比如古巴
Like Cuba.
让我们重新开赌场
Getting us back into casinos.
让我们重回哈瓦那
Getting us back into Havana.
比如除掉那个混球卡斯特罗
Like getting rid of that fucking Castro prick.
老一辈和老肯尼迪谈过了
The old-timers spoke to the Old Man.
老肯尼迪跟他儿子约翰谈过了  告诉了他
The Old Man talked to his son Jack, and he told him,
别忘了是谁帮他上位的
"Don't forget who the fuck he owes."
他知道他欠了谁的人情
He knows who the fuck he owes.
所以我要你
So I want you
去一个叫里程碑运输的地方
to go down to a place called Milestone Hauling.
有个叫菲尔的家伙
There's a guy named Phil.
他会给你一辆卡车
He's gonna give you a rig.
你把卡车开到巴尔的摩的
You drive the rig down to Baltimore
一家水泥厂去
to a concrete plant.
在东方大道上
It's on Eastern Avenue.
整条街上只有它  不会找不到的
It's the only one on the street. You can't miss it.
那里会有人等着你
A guy's gonna meet you there.
一个叫费瑞的娘炮
A fairy named Ferrie.
向前开  然后倒车进来
Just pull it forward and then back it in.
该干活了
Let's go, let's go.
你要在那取点东西
You'll pick up some things.
他会给你一些文件  以防你被拦下来
He'll give you some paperwork in case you get stopped.
你把卡车开到佛州
You drive the truck down to Florida.
佛州海岸灰狗巴士车道
杰克逊维尔外面的一条灰狗巴士车道上
A dog track outside Jacksonville.
把车留在那里
You leave it there.
一个叫亨特的大耳朵家伙会在那里等你
A guy with big ears named Hunt will meet you there.
他会给你一辆车  让你开回费城
He's gonna give you a car to drive back to Philly.
你看什么呢
What are you looking at?
你在看我的耳朵吗
You looking at my ears?
什么
Sorry?
我的耳朵
My ears.
-你在看我的耳朵吗  -你的耳朵
- Are you looking at my ears? - Your ears?
没有
No.
我做了手术  所以谁都不需要
I had an operation, so there's no need for anyone
再看我的耳朵了
looking at my ears anymore.
好吧  我也没看你的耳朵
Yeah, well, I ain't looking at your ears.
行吧
Right.
你走吧  赶紧的
Get out of here. Go on.
...在猪湾空降
...unfolded in the Bay of Pigs.
行动极不顺利
Nothing went as planned.
伞兵们无法
Paratroopers were unable
炸毁通往海岸地区的道路
to blow up roadways leading to the beach area.
卡斯特罗的军队奔赴前线
Castro raced toward the scene.
地下潜伏人员本能够
The underground might
将路炸毁  但他们一无所知
have blown up the roads but it knew nothing.
很快  卡斯特罗的军队就将炮火对准了滩头阵地
Soon, Castro had artillery firing on the beachhead.
他的飞机摧毁了入侵舰队
His planes destroyed invading ships
其中包含一个旅的兵力和重要军火
carrying a brigade of men and vital ammunition.
滩头阵地无法扩大
The beachhead could not be enlarged
伞兵们很快便试图杀回
and paratroopers were soon trying to fight their way back
岸边的小块区域
to the small section of the shore
这里的入侵者已经被压制
where the invaders were pinned down.
1500人被留在岸边  没有空中掩护
1,500 men had been dumped on a shore without air cover
也没有舰炮掩护
or protective fire from ships.
卡斯特罗只需等到他们弹尽粮绝
Castro had to wait only until they ran out of ammunition
就可将他们一举歼灭
before mopping them up.
稍后  卡斯特罗在入侵区域高调面对记者
Later, Castro was to strut around the invasion area with newsmen,
并阐述了犯下的错误
and expound on the errors that had been made.
他的资料充足
He had ample material.
已经备受侮辱的美国
The United States, already humiliated,
仍然受到世界大多数国家的谴责
stood condemned by most of the countries of the world.
见鬼
Shit!
不出我所料  他们搞完了古巴
Just as I predicted. They fuck up Cuba,
这个呆子就要冲我和工会来了
Boobie starts coming after me and the union.
他在寻求廉价的宣传手段
He's looking for some cheap publicity.
就是这样  他就是这么做的
That's all it is. That's what he's doing.
好吧  都会平息的  吉米
Okay. Well, it's all gonna blow over, Jimmy.
不  不会平息的  怎么平息
No, it's not gonna blow over. How's it gonna blow over?
他们永远都不会忘记
They're never gonna forget
-我资助过尼克松  -冷静点  吉米  拜托
- that I gave money to Nixon! - Calm down. Jimmy, please.
我们会处理好的
We're gonna handle this.
老一辈的
Couple of the old-timers,
他们会去找老肯尼迪
they're gonna get to Old Man Kennedy now.
好吗  他们会去找他的  他是病了  但...
Okay? They're gonna get to him. He's a little sick, but...
-病了  -是  但是...
- Sick? - Yeah. But...
他那是中风了  不是病了
He had a fucking stroke. That's not sick.
那是...那是将死之人了  好吧
That's you're... you're close to the grave, is what.
他马上就毫无价值了
He's turning into a fucking eggplant.
好吧  这也不能怪谁啊  这...
Okay. Well, you can't blame anybody for that. That's...
我又没打算怪谁
I'm not looking to blame anybody.
但真要怪谁的话  得怪肯尼迪小子们
But if there's any blame going around, it's the Kennedys.
我可以告诉你  是他的儿子害死了他
His kids killed him. Let me tell you that.
他还没死  但他快死了  快死了
He's not dead, but he's going. He's going.
他们害死了他  他们能让任何人犯心脏病
They killed him. They'd give anybody a heart attack.
久病后于1969年去世
老约瑟夫·P·肯尼迪
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我去工作
I'm going to work.
回去睡觉吧
Go back to sleep.
杜维尔
我能说的是  我们不会罢休
All I can say is that, we will not stop.
因为我们已经坚持了五十年
Because we've been doing that for 50 years!
有什么好处
What good does it do?
让律师去开开卡车
Let the lawyers... Let the lawyers drive a truck.
他们需要纸笔  需要印台
They need their pencils and papers and their ink pads.
那完全是另一回事了
That's... That's a whole other story.
但我们会挺过去的
But we're gonna get through this.
他们用什么法律狗屁打压我们
We're gonna get through this legal bullshit
我们会挺过去的
and garbage they're throwing at us.
We're gonna get through it because
新泽西卡车司机
因为呆子肯尼迪想要什么  并不意味着
"Boobie" Kennedy wants something, that doesn't mean
这个纨绔子弟就能得手
the rich boy is gonna get it.
你们明白我的意思吧
You understand what I'm saying?
我不在乎他要什么  反正他得不到
I don't care what he wants. He's not gonna get it!
他得不到  因为
He's not gonna get it because
我们是这个国家
we are the biggest and best,
最庞大  最优秀
and most honest union
最诚实的工会
in this country!
对  没错
Yeah, that's right.
我就等着这个
I waited for that!
你们知道我今天要讲的关键词是什么
And you know the operative word I'm talking about here.
-团结  -对
- Solidarity. - Yeah!
团结有效  对我们所有人都有效
And it works. It works for all of us.
对我们的朋友弗兰克·菲茨西蒙斯有效
And it works for our friend here, Frank Fitzsimmons!
这位是弗兰克·菲茨西蒙斯
Frank Fitzsimmons here,
我的执行副主席
my executive vice president.
如果有谁能胜任这份工作  那就是他
If there's anyone that can do this job, it's this man here.
有他为我保驾护航
And with him at my back,
我们一定会蒸蒸日上
where are we gonna go but up!
对吗  菲茨
Is that right, Fitz?
完全正确  吉米
All the way, Jimmy!
霍法  霍法  霍法
Hoffa! Hoffa! Hoffa!
一个工会人
A union man!
我觉得他们喜欢菲茨
You know, I felt they liked Fitz.
毋庸置疑
No two ways about it.
是  你提拔了菲茨
Yeah, you gave Fitz some buildup.
希望他不会辜负你
I mean, I hope he deserves it.
怎么说  菲茨有什么不妥吗
Why? What's wrong with Fitz?
我说不好  我不想批评他
I don't know. I don't want to knock the guy,
但我也说不好
but I... I don't know.
你不用批评他  告诉我
Well, you're not knocking him. Just tell me...
告诉我你的感受
Tell me what you feel.
他很忠诚  这我可以确定
I mean, he's a loyal guy, I'm sure.
他是个好人
He's a nice guy,
但他不够敏锐  不够聪明
but he ain't that sharp. He ain't that smart.
他还...
And he's also like a...
他总打高尔夫球
He plays a lot of fucking golf, you know.
他打高尔夫球
He plays golf?
那又如何  二把手就需要这样的
So what? That's what you want from a number two.
不需要太聪明的人
You don't want somebody too smart.
需要一个好人  大家喜欢他
You want a nice guy. People like him, you know.
不傻  但是个
Not dumb, but somebody,
可以放心让他走在身后
you know you can have walking behind you
而不怕被捅刀子的人
without getting knifed.
-希望你是对的  -我总是对的
- Well, I hope you're right. - I'm always right.
我可以对菲茨可以放一百个心
I can sleep like a babe with Fitz.
我担心的是矮子
It's the Little Guy I have to worry about.
你知道我说的是谁
You know what I'm saying.
-是  -是
- Yeah. - Yeah.
矮子
The Little Guy.
-我担心的是他  -嗯
- That's my worry. - Yeah.
那个王八蛋
That son of a bitch.
怎么了
What's the matter?
没事  没事  你是对的
Nothing. Nothing. You're right.
我是对的  是的
I'm right. Yeah.
-你不会觉得困惑吧  -完全不会
- You're not perplexed, are you? - Not at all. Not at all.
我和你说了我对菲茨的感受  至于普罗  你懂的
I mean, I told you how I felt about Fitz. Pro. You know.
好  那就好  因为有时我觉得
Yeah. Good, because sometimes I feel
只有我一个人看穿了那个狗杂种
I'm the only one who sees right through that cocksucker.
♪ 让我们举杯... ♪
♪ So let's raise a glass... ♪
-他是个坏人  -他是个坏人
- He's a bad guy. - He's a bad guy.
♪ 敬最伟大的人 ♪
♪ To the greatest guy ♪
♪ 能有他是560号地方工会之幸 ♪
♪ 560 is lucky enough to ever have ♪
♪ 你是我们的兄弟 ♪
♪ You're our boy ♪
♪ 托尼·普罗 ♪
♪ Tony Pro ♪
♪ 我们都是你的兄弟 ♪
♪ We're all yours ♪
矮子就是托尼·普罗文扎诺
The Little Guy was Tony Provenzano.
人称托尼·普罗
They called him Tony Pro.
他是新泽西一个大帮派的首领
He was a capo in a big Jersey crew
并且是新泽西联合市
and the president of the Local 560
560号地方工会的主席
in Union City, New Jersey.
♪ 他是最伟大的人 ♪
♪ He's the greatest guy ♪
♪ 能有他是560号地方工会之幸 ♪
♪ 560 is lucky enough to ever have ♪
托尼  托尼  托尼
Tony! Tony! Tony!
普罗和吉米  他们一起发迹
Pro and Jimmy, they came up together
他们曾经很亲近
and they were close... for a while.
你们没日没夜地工作
You turl, you work,
而大企业的老板们
while the corporation kings
行业的骄子们
and princes of industry,
他们坐拥巨额报销账单
with their vast expense accounts
高昂薪水  以及豪华游艇
and salary and luxurous yachts,
却致力于毁灭我们
have dedicated themselves to our destruction.
打倒他们
Down on them!
我用不着谁来跟我说托尼·普罗的故事
I didn't need nobody to tell me about Tony Pro.
我还需要知道些什么  我知道的够多了
Oh, no. What did I need to know? I knew enough.
这家伙让萨利·巴格斯
This is a man who had Sally Bugs strangle
勒死了"三指"托尼·卡斯特里图
Tony "Three Fingers" Castellito
就因为三指在工会里的地位越来越高
just because Three Fingers was coming up big in the union.
那还是他自己人  那可是他自己人
And it was his own guy. It was his own guy.
萨尔瓦多·布里古里欧  绰号"小虫萨利"
1979年脸中三枪身亡
托尼·普罗太担心
Tony Pro was so fucking worried
这家伙会击败他
that this guy was gonna beat him out
以至于在让小虫萨利勒死他之后
that after he had Sally Bugs strangle the guy,
还让萨利把他塞进了碎树机
he had Sally stick him in a fucking tree shredder.
这样就再也没有竞争了
That way there'd be no competition,
毕竟他已经粉身碎骨了
not even from the grave.
他已经失控了
He's out of control.
拿这种人该怎么办
What are you gonna do with a person like this?
他想从每个人那都分杯羹
He's got a hand in everybody's pocket.
勒索货运公司
Shaking down the trucking companies.
你能想象吗
Can you imagine that?
四处威胁人
Threatening people.
偶尔威胁威胁人
I mean, you know, threatening people once in a while,
没问题  我能理解
okay, I understand.
但一直威胁人呢
But all the time?
会让人注意到我们  你明白吗
It's drawing attention to us, you understand?
那样的家伙会毁了工会的声誉
Guys like that give the unions a bad name.
得做点什么了
Something's got to be done.
我说真的  得做点什么了
I mean it. Something's gotta be done.
托尼毕竟是托尼...
Tony being Tony, uh...
不好...不好弄  我们不能...
that ain't... that ain't easy. We can't...
我不是那个意思  我不是
I don't mean that. I don't...
不是那个意思
Not... Not that.
我只是
Yeah, I'm just...
我只是想让劳工阶层
I'm just saying get working guys
那些熟悉工会的  卡车司机工会的正式成员
who know the unions, card-carrying Teamsters,
就像你我这样的
like you and me.
开始竞选
Start running,
接管几个地方工会
take over some of the locals.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
-他不会喜欢的  -谁
- He ain't gonna like that. - Who?
去他的  他算什么东西
Fuck him. Who the fuck is he?
地痞流氓罢了
He's a gangster.
我领导着工会  我是主席
I run the union, I'm the president.
我的意思是
So, I mean...
我所需要的是一些懂事的家伙
All I need is some guys who know their ways around.
知道怎么把控自己
Know how to handle themselves, you know.
仅此而已
That's all.
所以我想让你去竞选
That's why I want you to run for president
326号地方工会的主席
of Local 326.
你就是我的家人  弗兰克
You're like family to me, Frank. You know.
你  艾琳
You, Irene,
孩子们
the girls.
可爱的佩琪
The lovely Peggy.
但这并不是我这么做的原因
But that's not why I'm doing this.
我给你的一切都是你自己赢得的
I'm not giving you anything you didn't earn,
都是你应得的
you didn't deserve.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我不知道该说什么了  吉米
I...I don't know what to say, Jimmy.
-我是说...  -只管说你愿意就好
- I mean, um... - Well, just say you'll do it.
你只需要说愿意
That's all you got to say.
而且  我能保证你会赢
Plus, I can guarantee you're gonna win.
你只要竞选326号地方工会的主席
Ha! When you run for president
你就一定会赢
of 326, you're gonna win.
我保证
I guarantee it.
好  没问题  我愿意
Yeah, okay, I'll do it. Yeah.
认真的吗
You mean it, huh?
当然  我很荣幸
Yeah, yeah. I'm... I'm honored.
我爱你  我真的爱你  抱一个
I love you. I just love you, you know. Come here.
我爱你  伙计
I love you, man.
爱到难以言表
I can't tell ya.
天
Oh, gee.
太好了
This is so good, you know.
我终于能喘口气了
I feel like I can breathe again.
太有意思了
It's so funny. I...
不知怎么地  我...
Somehow I...
我也不知道  我以为你会拒绝
I don't know. I thought you would've said no.
我很高兴你答应了
I'm glad you said yes.
我想说
I mean...
弗兰克
Frank...
你从来不显露情绪  很难判断
You never reveal how you feel, you know. It's hard to tell.
我很荣幸  吉米  我不知道
I'm honored, Jimmy. I don't know...
我只是不知道该说什么
It's just I don't know what to... say,
但是我很荣幸
you know, but I'm honored.
那就好
Well, that's good.
让我感觉很好
That makes me feel good.
我能喘口气了
I can breathe.
太好了
That's so great.
我
I...
卡车司机326号地方工会
我还能说什么  我的一切都是吉米给的
What can I say? I mean, I owe it all to Jimmy.
他把我从运肉卡车中解救出来  给了我新的开始
He took me out of a meat truck, he gave me my start.
他给我了首个职位  他给了我第一个工会
He gave me my first charter. He gave me my first union.
-你好  -你好
- How are ya? - Hey, how are you?
我是弗兰克·希兰  326号地方工会的新任主席
Frank Sheeran, the new president of Union 326.
-我来自我介绍一下  -很高兴认识你
- I wanted to introduce myself. - Nice to meet ya.
-你叫什么  -我叫阿尔
- What's your name? - My name's Al.
阿尔  很高兴认识你
Al. Nice to meet ya, Al.
-一点心意  -不  不用
- A little something... - No, no. Don't need it.
-确定吗  -当然
- Sure? - Yeah.
只是过来问个好  自我介绍一下
Just came here to say hello, introduce myself.
有什么需要  只管联系我  好吗
You need anything, just get in touch with me. Okay?
-你确定吗  -当然
- You sure? - Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
弗兰克·希兰  326号地方工会主席
所以  我们假设  如果他们能证明
So, hypothetically, if they can prove
你从他们那偷了东西
that you stole from them,
他们会想要你供出同伙的名字
what they're gonna want are names, so...
你愿意交代几个名字  免去牢狱之灾吗
Would you be willing to give up names to keep from going to jail?
不
No.
那你就没什么好担心的了
Okay. So you got nothing to worry about.
-律师会帮你摆平的  -谢谢  希兰先生
- The lawyers will take care of it. - Thank you, Mr. Sheeran.
沿80号州际公路西段开过宾州
The Interstate 80 West through the rest of Pennsylvania,
然后我们横穿俄亥俄州到托莱多
and then we'd go across Ohio all the way to Toledo,
接着我们沿着75号公路北上底特律
and then we'd go 75 North to Detroit.
依然能够准时到达
And we'd still get there on time.
法官阁下  法律顾问已经告诉我的委托人
Your Honor, my client had been advised by counsel
她妻子作为货运公司所有者之一
that it was perfectly legal for his wife
是完全合法的
to be part owner of a trucking business.
而在麦克莱伦委员会质询其合法性时
Still, when the McClellan Committee challenged its legality,
美国参议院针对工人
及管理层不当行为特别委员会
她第一时间退出了公司
she withdrew from the company immediately.
事情到此就该告一段落
That should be the end of the matter.
在十三次大陪审团调查中
There had been not one indictment served
我的委托人没有一次被判有罪
against my client in 13 grand jury investigations.
法官阁下  这是典型的
Your Honor, this is an example of
对我的委托人和他的家人的恶意报复
a personal vendetta against my client,
是令人失望的司法部和司法部长罗伯特·肯尼迪
against his family, by a frustrated Justice Department
在针对我的委托人
and the attorney general, Robert Kennedy.
他手上有枪
He's got a gun!
把枪先抢下来
Get that gun out of his hand!
别激动  小伙子
Easy, boy.
那不是真枪吧
That was not a real gun, was it?
枪是怎么进来的
How'd that gun get in?
怎么进来的
How'd it get in here?
又不是我的错
It wasn't my fault!
我也不知道
I don't know!
我的查奇
My Chuckie!
这是我儿子
Hey, it's my son!
这是我的孩子  我把他养大的
That's my kid. I raised this kid.
你们看见了吗  看见他的英勇之举了吗
You see him? You see what he did?
我告诉你们
I'll tell you this.
他冲我开了枪  感觉像是小弹丸似的
He shot at me, and it was like a pellet or something.
没什么感觉  就一点点冲击力
I didn't feel it, I just felt a little impact,
甚至还比不上被BB枪打了
like I was shot not even with a BB gun.
比BB枪更弱
Something even lighter.
但我冲向了他
But I charged him.
我和查奇都冲向了他  如果你们看见了的话
I charged him and so did Chuckie, if you noticed.
我把他教得很好
I taught him well.
遇到持枪的永远要冲上去
You charge a guy, always charge a guy with a gun.
如果是持刀的跑就行了
With a knife, you run away.
遇到持刀的就跑  持枪的就冲
Run away from a knife. So you charge with a gun,
-持刀的就跑  -没错
- with a knife, you run. - That's right.
我还押韵了
Hey! I rhymed!
我知道很难让人相信  但我收到了上头的消息
I know it sounds crazy, but I got a message from a higher power
田纳西州纳什维尔警局
让我杀了吉米·霍法
telling me to shoot Jimmy Hoffa.
跟我来
Come with me.
纳什维尔有很多疯子  弗兰克
A lot of nuts in Nashville, Frank.
快过来  弗兰克
Come on down, Frank.
现在我边上就有一个
Yeah, I got one of them with me now, you see.
快过来  弗兰克
Get down here, Frank.
艾迪·帕丁  巴顿鲁日的那家伙
Eddie Partin, you know the guy from Baton Rouge,
他也在这里
he's here with me.
好  我马上过去
Yeah. Yeah, I'll get right down.
别挡道  伙计们  让让
Out of my way, boys. Come on.
让让
Come on, come on.
布伦南先生是否先说了
Did Mr. Brennan first say,
或者你是否记得他首先说了
or do you remember him first saying
像是"我要更改交易条款
something about, say, "I had to change the deal.
我得让霍法也分一杯羹"这样的话
I have to cut Hoffa in on the new deal"?
这不就是整件事的源头吗
Wasn't that like the chronology of the whole thing?
我不知道他变更了交易条款
I don't know he changed the deal,
但我在电话这头的理解是
but it was my understanding over the telephone that Brennan
布伦南只代表了他自己
was speaking for himself.
她看上去很愤怒  这一看就很愤怒
She's an angry woman. That's an angry woman.
是啊
Oh. Yeah.
-我想她曾经是个老师  -没错
- She was a teacher I think. - Oh, that's right.
我们现在研究的是这个
What we're looking at is this one.
这个可不好搞定
This one is not approachable.
她很难攻破
No, she'd be a tough nut to crack.
有很多家族财产
There's a lot of family money there.
...将会截停搜查
...will hail, stop, and search
所有驶往古巴的船只
all ships bound for Cuba.
若船长不停船
If the ships' captains do not stop,
我们将采取武力截停
force will be used to stop them.
如果船停下...
If the ships do stop...
我觉得可以选这个
See, I think there's an in here...
你是否对大陪审团
Did you make this statement
做出过如下陈述
to the grand jury? I'll read it for you.
"布伦南过来跟我说了些
"Brennan came to me and said words
类似于他要继续的话..."
to the effect he's gonna go ahead..."
他开了家餐厅
He's got a restaurant.
你查过违法行为了吗
Did you look into violations?
查了  我更愿意选女人
Yeah. I'd rather stick with the women.
-她们更好搞定  -吉米  谢谢
- They're more approachable. - Jimmy, thank you.
...已在古巴部署可用的中程导弹
...in Cuba of operational medium-range missiles.
他还表示如果导弹发射
He added that if one of the missiles is launched,
可能会携带有核弹头
it would probably carry a nuclear warhead.
能够打击美国东南部任何地区
It could hit any spot in the southeast United States,
以及华盛顿南部
south of Washington.
而我们无法拦截
And that we would have no way of intercepting it
也无法提前预警
or issuing a warning about it.
这位嫁给了一个叫普莱切特的州警
This one's married to a state trooper named Plechette.
不错
That's good.
有门路吗
We know anyone?
有  地方工会有个当过警察的
Well, yeah, we got an ex-cop in the Local.
很好
That's good.
我们的所有部队都提高了警戒级别
All our forces have been put on increased alert.
过来跟我聊了几句  大意是
...came to me and said words to the effect
他打算开家公司出租卡车
he's gonna go ahead and set up a company to lease trucks.
但之后  他又打电话  他的原话是
But later, he called me on the phone and said quote,
"我要更改交易条款
"I gotta change the deal
因为我要让霍法也分一杯羹"
'cause I gotta cut Hoffa in on the deal."
是这样吗  先生
Is that accurate, sir?
这是另一个可以下手的对象
This one's another possibility.
-等等  -她有过情人
- Wait. - Well, she had a boyfriend,
她婚后还跟别人有一腿
she's seeing somebody else while she's married.
所以可以用这个要挟她
So it could be... It could grab her,
-抓着她不放  -对  但是...
- hold on to her. - Yeah, but...
但这家伙
But this guy,
开建筑公司的  做过一些违反的事情
the construction business. He has a couple of violations,
他的房子有留置权
there's a lien on his house.
车还没付钱
His car is unpaid.
很好  继续  别在领先的时候放弃
That's good. Keep going. Don't quit while you're ahead.
谢谢  回见  大艾迪
Thank you. See you, Big Eddie.
你是否向上帝发誓
Do you swear to tell the truth,
你所说的全是事实
the whole truth and nothing but the truth,
-没有任何隐瞒  -我发誓
- so help you God? - I do.
金先生  你是
Mr. King, you're a member of
国际卡车司机工会的成员  对吗  先生
the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, is that correct, sir?
恕我拒绝回答这个问题
I respectfully decline to answer that under the
我要行使第五修正案赋予我的权利
protection afforded me by the Fifth Amendment.
我只是问你是不是卡车司机工会的  先生
I just asked if you're a Teamster, sir.
恕我拒绝回答...
I respectfully decline to answer...
好  没问题  行
Okay. All right. Fine.
我要给你看张照片  行吗
I'm gonna show you a photograph, all right?
-恕我拒绝回答....  -等等
- I respectfully decline to answer... - Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait...
我要行使...
...under the protection...
田纳西州警
你还没看这张照片
You haven't even seen the photograph yet.
看着这张照片  好好看看
Look at the photograph, wait a smidge,
-然后你可以...  -根据我的理解
- and then you can... - I want to avail myself
我想援引宪法赋予我的权利
of my right under the constitution, as I understand it.
威廉·E·米勒法官阁下
-吉米  让他援引自己的权利  -好吧
- Jim, let him avail himself. - Oh, okay.
希尔德布兰特糖果冰淇淋店
是啊
Oh, yeah.
金是最棒的
That King's the best.
他是最棒的  他是个好人
He's the best. He's a good guy.
你看到他是怎样对付那个混蛋的吗
You see him stand up to that jerk?
看到了  看到了  我知道  他很棒
Yeah, yeah, I know. He was great.
我就喜欢他这么干
I love what he did.
他们想让他开口  他们尽了全力
They tried to get him, they tried their best.
-我们需要更多他这样的人  -天啊
- We need more like him. - Oh, my God!
我们刚刚收到更多详细信息
More details just arrived.
这些详细信息是最新的
These details are not the same as previously.
肯尼迪总统在车队
President Kennedy, shot today,
离开达拉斯市区时遇刺
just as his motorcade left downtown Dallas.
肯尼迪夫人上前
Mrs. Kennedy jumped up
抱住肯尼迪先生  大喊"不"
and grabbed Mr. Kennedy. She called, "Oh, no!"
车队加速驶离
The motorcade sped on.
合众社报道称肯尼迪总统受的
United Press says that the wounds of President Kennedy
可能是致命伤
perhaps could be fatal.
正在重播哥伦比亚广播公司新闻发出的简报
Repeating a bulletin from CBS News.
肯尼迪总统在得克萨斯州的达拉斯市
President Kennedy has been shot
被一名嫌疑刺客开枪击中
by a would-be assassin in Dallas, Texas.
请继续关注哥伦比亚广播公司新闻
Stay tuned to CBS News for
了解更多详细信息
further details.
什么
What?
要做出一杯真正的咖啡
It takes more than an instant
一瞬间可不够
to make a real cup of coffee.
因此雀巢咖啡研制出了一种新产品
That's why Nescafé has come up with a new kind of coffee.
这不只是一种即溶咖啡  而是新的雀巢分钟煮咖啡
It's more than an instant. It's new Minute Brew Nescafé.
人人都能做出...
Anybody can make a...
这显然是一则官方简报
The flash, apparently official,
肯尼迪总统于中部标准时间下午一点
President Kennedy died at 1:00 p.m. Central standard time,
东部标准时间下午两点去世
two o'clock, eastern standard time,
大约38分钟前
some 38 minutes ago.
副总统约翰逊已离开位于达拉斯的医院
Vice President Johnson has left the hospital in Dallas,
但我们不知道他将前往哪里
but we do not know, uh, to where he has proceeded.
预计他很快将宣誓就职
Presumably, he will be taking the oath of office shortly
成为第36届美国总统
and become the 36th President of the United States.
国际卡车司机工会
霍法先生  你会参加
Mr. Hoffa, will you be attending
总统的葬礼吗
the President's funeral?
我没有受邀
I wasn't invited.
不一定要受邀  上百万的美国人都会参加
You don't have to be invited. A million Americans will be there.
那...
Well...
我想我得查查我的日程
I guess I'll have to check my schedule.
如果你去参加并被请求发言  你会说什么
If you were to go and asked to speak, what would you say?
我会说
I'd say, uh,
鲍比·肯尼迪现在只是个普通律师了
Bobby Kennedy is just another lawyer now.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
国际卡车司机工会
很好  埃里克  非常感谢
Good, Eric. Thank you very much.
吉米说得对
Jimmy was right.
几乎是对的
Almost.
鲍比的刁难到此为止了
That was the end of it with Bobby.
他卸任司法部长了  事情了结了
So much for him being the attorney general. That was done.
鲍比跟我们的宿怨结束了
Bobby's vendetta was over, with us.
霍法先生
Mr. Hoffa,
你因损害了这个国家的灵魂
you stand here convicted of having tampered
被判有罪
with the very soul of this nation.
但纳什维尔那个陪审团的事情还没完
But there was still that jury thing in Nashville.
先生  这个国家的灵魂在于
The soul of this nation, sir,
它神圣的司法程序
lies in its sacred processes of justice.
正义必须得到伸张
Justice must be done.
你因为曾邪恶地企图破坏这套程序
And for your wicked attempts to corrupt these processes,
将会受到法律的制裁
justice will be done on you.
我们终于抓到他了
We got him now.
我们抓到他了
We got him.
女士们先生们  我们做到了
Ladies and gentlemen, we did it!
囚车不作鸣枪警示
但是吉米把一切都安排妥当了
But Jimmy, you know, he had it all set up.
虽然表面看起来是
Although you knew it was supposed to look like Fitz
菲茨在管事
was the one in charge.
但他通过比尔·巴法利诺和
He gave Fitz his orders through
詹姆斯·R·霍法
艾伦·多夫曼给菲茨下指令
Bill Bufalino and Allen Dorfman,
他们还替吉米放贷
and they ran Jimmy's loans.
在里面待得还好吗  一切都...
But things are good in here? Everything is...
一切都糟透了
Everything's terrible.
夜不能寐  因为担心
You don't sleep at night 'cause you're afraid
有人会拿刀捅你
someone's gonna knife you.
但你看上去不错  还不错
'Cause you look okay. You look okay.
菲茨在哪  他迟到了
Where's Fitz? He's late.
我们本来要在正门等他的  他...
Yeah. Well, we were gonna meet him in the front. He...
在正门等他吗
Meet him in the front?
他来了  他来了
Here he is, here he is.
你到底去哪了  你来这干什么
Where the hell have you been? What are you doing here?
你到底来干什么  菲茨
Why did you even come at all, Fitz?
你知道自己迟到了吗
You know, are you aware you're late?
我就想知道这个  你知道自己迟到了吗
That's all I want to know. Do you know you're late?
对不起我迟到了  吉米
I'm sorry I'm late, Jimmy,
但我们有很多事要做
but we got a lot going on.
我们有很多事要做
We got a lot going on.
我不想听这种话  我想听点具体的
I don't wanna hear that. I wanna hear something concrete,
我想听你直入正题
I wanna hear something straight on.
我只想请你耐心一点
I'm just gonna ask you to be a little more patient.
我觉得我们会...
I think we're gonna have...
我在坐牢  不会太耐心
I'm inside here. I'm not gonna be too patient.
尽管吉米对菲茨很不爽
As much as Jimmy was getting pissed off at Fitz,
其他人还是喜欢他  因为
everybody else liked him because
他们可以从他那里得到想要的一切
they could get anything out of him that they wanted.
这是他们不能从吉米那得到的
They couldn't do that with Jimmy.
如果进了监狱  难免会发生这种事情
That's what happens when you go away to college.
打得怎么样
How's that?
吉米生菲茨的气
Jimmy's pissed off with Fitz.
菲茨还不错  我们喜欢他
Fitz is okay. We like Fitz.
我告诉你问题出在哪
I'll tell you what the problem is.
吉米让那个难缠的多夫曼
Jimmy's got that ballbusting Dorfman
拖延菲茨已经同意的贷款
holding up loans that Fitz already okayed.
我讨厌那个多夫曼
I hate that Dorfman.
他是个令人头疼的犹太人
He's such a pain-in-the-ass fucking Jew.
你想让我怎么办
What do you want me to do?
不  先别那样  先别那样
No, not that. Not that.
你要做的就是
What you gotta do is, you know,
警告一下多夫曼
put a firecracker up Dorfman's ass.
菲茨会明白的
Fitz'll get the message.
他会明白的
He'll get the message.
你不能对菲茨下手  因为如果...
I mean, you can't do it to Fitz because if...
如果你对那个酒鬼下手
if you do it to that lush,
他会直接去找联调局  搞砸一切
he'll run right to the feds and screw up everything.
但多夫曼
But Dorfman...
你要对多夫曼下手
You gotta do it to Dorfman.
Cry - Johnnie Ray & The Four Lads
♪ If your heartaches ♪
♪ Seem to hang around ♪
♪ If your heartaches Seem to hang around ♪
菲茨  菲茨明白我们的意思了
Fitz... Fitz got the message.
从此以后  任何人想从养老基金里
After that, anybody who wanted anything
捞一笔  都能得偿所愿
from the pension fund, they got it.
老是翻到这张牌
The thing keeps comin' around. Keeps comin' around.
怎么回事
What's goin' on?
-搞什么  -这家伙是谁
- Fuck is this? - Who's this guy?
谁让你进来的
Who let you in?
普罗文扎诺先生
Mr. Provenzano.
我是联调局的迪格雷奥里奥探员
I'm Agent DiGregorio of the FBI.
我有你的逮捕令  请站起来
I have a warrant for your arrest. Please stand.
我能把手里的牌打完吗
Can I finish my hand?
不行  先生  请站起来
No, sir. Please stand.
反正我手气烂透了
I had a bad fucking hand anyway.
安东尼·加卡罗内  人称"托尼·杰克"
人缘很好  于2001年2月23日寿终正寝
牌才打到一半
Middle of the game.
让他一起打吧
Join the club. Deal him in.
请伸另一只手
Other arm, please.
-我能拿我的包吗  -不行  先生
- Can I get my bags? - No, sir.
我口袋里什么都没有  我穿着短裤呢
I got nothing in my pocket. I got fucking shorts on here.
看看那边那只企鹅
Look at this penguin over there, huh?
托尼  你能帮我拿下包吗
Hey, Tony, will you get my bags?
行  我会帮你拿包
Yeah, I'll get your bags.
这就像在看电视
This is like watchin' TV.
普罗因为敲诈被抓  判了七年
They got Pro for extortion and gave him seven years.
把他送去了路易斯堡监狱
And they sent him to Lewisburg prison.
他和谁落在一起了
So who does he end up with?
吉米
Jimmy.
瞧瞧这个
Look at that.
简直是艺术品
A work of art.
谢谢  皮特
Thank you, Pete.
我要跟你谈谈养老金的问题
I gotta talk to you about a problem I got with my pension.
我知道
I know.
你知道
You know?
你知道什么
What do you know?
我知道
I know
你有120万
you got a million two
而且出了问题
and, uh, there's a problem with it.
那你会帮我查查吗
So you'll look into it for me?
我要怎么查  我能查什么
How am I going to look into it? What am I gonna look into?
就这么回事
It is what it is.
怎么回事
Well, what is it?
这笔钱没了
You lost it.
你进来时它就被没收了  就是这样
You forfeited it when you came in here. That's it.
所以你的也被没收了吗
So is yours forfeited too?
没有
No.
我们先理清楚  你的钱还在
Ok, let me get this straight. So yours is still there,
你的150万什么的
your million five, whatever it is,
但我的钱没了
but mine's gone?
对  我的钱还在
Yeah. Mine's still there.
但我俩现在都在牢里
But we're both sitting here.
我俩都在牢里  没错
We're both sitting here. That's right.
不过我俩坐牢的原因不同
Only we're sitting here for different things.
你是因为敲诈
You're sitting here for extortion.
我是因为欺诈
I'm sitting here for fraud.
-那又怎样  -怎样  是有差别的
- So? - So? So there's a difference.
什么差别
What's the difference?
我没威胁任何人  但你威胁了
I didn't threaten anybody, you did.
那又怎样  根本说不通
So what? That makes no sense.
当然说得通
What do you mean? It does.
不  我不想跟你辩论
No, it doesn't. I don't want a debate.
-想想看  -我在想了  吉米
- Think about it. - I'm thinking about it, Jimmy.
别唬我  吉米
No, don't fuck with me, Jimmy.
做点什么
Just do something about it.
"做点什么"是什么意思
What do you mean, "do something about it"?
我能做什么
What am I gonna do?
拜托  你总有办法
Come on, there's always something you can do.
不  联邦法律我没办法
No. It's federal law.
-我不管  -你不管
- I don't care. - You don't care?
你还是能做点什么
No, you can still do something about it.
我无能为力  我能做什么
There's nothing I can do. What can I do?
把我的钱拿回来
You can get my fucking money.
怎么拿
How?
-找个办法  -什么办法
- Some other way. - What way?
你怎么拿回你的钱  你就怎么帮我
The same way you got your money.
小点声
Lower your fucking voice.
你让我小点声
You telling me to lower my voice?
我让你小点声
I'm tellin' you to lower your fucking voice.
鳖孙
Cocksucker.
-别叫我鳖孙  -去你的
- Don't call me a cocksucker. - Fuck you.
你再骂我试试
Don't you fucking dare.
你是因为欺诈进来的
Look, you're here for fraud.
-你偷钱  -我偷钱
- You stole money. - I stole money?
我也偷钱
Yeah, I stole money.
好吧  偷的手段不同  尽管如此
Okay, fine, in a different way, but still,
我要我应得的那份
I want what I'm fucking owed.
你们这些人
You people. You people.
-你说什么  -天啊
- What did you say? - Oh, my God!
你说什么
What did you say?
得了吧  还我说什么
Oh, come on, what I said.
我说什么
What the fuck did I say?
你说了"你们这些人"
"You people." You said "You people."
那是什么意思  "你们这些人"
What does that fucking mean, "You people"?
我不想
I'm done
再谈这事了
talking about this.
-解释一下"你们这些人"  -我不谈了
- "You people"? - I'm done!
你不谈了  看我不把你脑袋拧下来
You're done? I'll rip your fucking head off!
你个人渣
Fucking piece of shit!
我要杀了你
I'll fucking kill you!
我要杀了你  混账
I'll fucking kill you. Motherfucker!
搞什么
What the fuck...
那时候你就知道一切将分崩离析
Right then, you knew it was all gonna fall apart.
我不敢相信那个疯狂的王八蛋
I can't believe that crazy bastard
竟然觉得自己
thought he could do that
能在哥伦布广场当着五千人的面得逞
right there at Columbus Circle, in front of 5,000 people
还能逃脱
and get away with it.
我不敢相信  那可不对  弗兰克
I can't believe it. That is not right, Frankie.
那可不对
That is not right.
那人是个彻头彻尾的混蛋
That is a total piece of shit.
那人是个混蛋
That's a piece of shit.
只有一个人有胆量
There's only one guy who would have the balls,
有勇气那么做
the nerve, the audacity to do that.
城里叫他金发乔伊
He was known Downtown as "Joey the Blond,"
但所有人  尤其是报纸
but everybody, especially the newspapers,
都叫他疯子乔
called him "Crazy Joe."
...向上帝发誓
...shall be the truth,
你所说的全是事实  没有任何隐瞒
the whole truth and nothing but the truth, so help you God?
-我发誓  -请坐
- I do. - Be seated.
加洛先生  你要做开庭陈述吗
Mr. Gallo, do you have an opening statement?
要
Yeah.
这地毯特别适合玩掷骰子
This carpet would be great for a crap game.
罗素说得对
Russ was right.
还有谁会像他那样和娱乐圈的人鬼混
I mean, who the hell else runs around with show business people like that,
成天到晚让报纸记者给他拍照
getting his picture taken in the papers all the time,
卡巴纳宫酒店
想方设法吸引大家的注意力  搞什么
drawing attention to himself and everybody. What is that?
他以为自己是谁  明星埃罗尔·弗林吗
Who does he think he is, Errol Flynn?
他跟所有人和事对着干
He went against everything and everybody.
什么都不在乎
Just didn't give a shit.
年轻的时候  他绑架了自己的老大
And, growing up, he kidnapped his own bosses.
我不知道他是怎么逃脱的
I don't know how he got away with that.
一般人没法逃脱  绑架老大就是死路一条
You don't get away with that. You do that, you die.
就这么简单
That simple.
他坐牢的时候
When he went away to the can,
招募了黑人而不是白人
he recruited black guys instead of his own kind.
等他出狱  没人知道他在做什么
And when he got out, nobody knew what he was doing,
跟谁一起做
or who he was doing with it.
我们不知道是什么情况  没人知道
We didn't know what the hell was going on. Nobody did.
如果你不喜欢他的做法
And if you don't like what he's doing,
你出声抱怨
and you say something,
然后你就等着看会发生什么吧
then you see what happens.
意大利裔美国人人权联盟
谁会做那种事  谁会那么办事
Who does something like that? Who does things like that?
我告诉你
I'll tell you. I'll tell you.
这个无赖
This disgraziato.
他和奥斯瓦尔德是一类的
Him and Oswald. Two of a kind.
至少在达拉斯  那些孩子不在
At least in Dallas, the kids weren't there.
只有杰姬
It was just Jackie.
乔伊  你的医生打来电话  你一小时之前死了
Joey, your doctor called. You died an hour ago.
你是犹太人吗
You a Jewish fellow?
你想当犹太人吗
Would you like to be?
别担心割礼  现在不会那么做了
Don't worry about the operation. We don't do that no more.
现在会先打麻药
We freeze it.
你就站着什么都不用做
And you stand there and don't do anything
一个墨西哥婆娘拿着块湿石头走过来
and a Mexican broad comes over with a wet rock.
啪
Thwack!
大笑没问题  我开所有人的玩笑
See, it's okay to laugh. I make fun of everybody.
上帝带我们来到世上就是为了让我们笑
That's why God put us on this earth, to laugh.
所有人都是我的讽刺对象
I work everyone.
我开黑人玩笑  我开犹太人玩笑
I make fun of blacks, I make fun of Jews.
吉普赛人  意大利人
I work Gypsies, I work Italians.
那些意大利人可不行
Well, not those Italians.
不不不
No, no, no, no!
没事的  乔伊  我有钱  别开枪
It's okay, Joey. I got the money. Don't shoot.
他们今天告诉我
I was told today,
"说话千万小心"
"Be very careful about what you say."
但抛开那些玩笑  生日快乐  乔伊
But, uh, all kidding aside, happy birthday, Joey.
罗素
Russ.
你戴那个干什么
What are you doing with that?
意大利裔美国人人权联盟
你真相信那个狗屁联盟
You really believe in that bullshit league?
不是因为那个
Well, it's not that.
是意大利裔
It's Italian.
乔伊  乔伊
Joey. Joey.
-我说什么了  -不不不
- What did I say? - Oh, no, no.
-我说什么了  -乔伊  乔伊
- What did I say? - Joey, Joey. Joey. Joey.
听我说
Now, listen.
你不能在这儿说那种话  明白吗  不行
You can't say that stuff like that here. Okay? You can't do that.
为什么  只有瑞克斯能开玩笑吗
Why not? Rickles is the only one who can make jokes?
他是老大
The man's a boss.
我也是老大  他是老大
So I'm a boss. He's a boss.
那我们应该是兄弟  对吧
We're all supposed to be brothers, right?
我知道你是老大
I know you're a boss.
我知道  但我们现在不想吵  对吧
I know, but we don't wanna have a beef now. Okay?
-我们是兄弟  对吧  -没错  兄弟
- We're brothers, right? - That's right, brothers.
-我们是兄弟吧  -你们是兄弟
- We're brothers? - You're brothers.
-我们是兄弟  -我不跟你争
- We're brothers. - I'm not arguing with you.
大家都是兄弟
Everybody's a brother.
没错  你是兄弟  你是他兄弟
That's right, you're a brother. You're his brother.
我不是  但你们是
I'm not, but you guys are.
所以如果你能给点面子就好了
So that's why I would like it if you just...
-好  -好吗
- All right. - Okay?
-我们是兄弟  -对
- We're brothers? - You're brothers.
对  今天我过生日
Yeah. It's my birthday.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
赶紧滚吧
Get the fuck out of here.
要做这种活儿
Now, for something like this,
你需要两把枪
you're gonna need two guns.
一把是用的  一把是后备
The one you're gonna use and a backup.
要比点22口径的更有威慑力
You want something with more stopping power than a .22.
绝对不用消音器
You definitely don't want a silencer.
要弄出很大响声  吓得目击者逃走
You want to make a lot of noise to make the witnesses run away
这样他们就不会看你了
so they ain't gonna be looking at you.
但点45口径的响声可不行
But not the noise a .45 makes
那样动静就太大了
'cause that makes too much noise,
几个街区外的巡逻警车都能听到
and a patrol car can hear it a few blocks away at least.
警察管点32口径的叫女士枪  因为它比较好控制
The cops call a .32 a woman's gun because it's easier to handle
没有点38口径的破坏力
and don't do the damage a .38 does,
但是足够了
but, you know, it does enough.
安贝特蛤蜊餐厅
到时候是深夜  爱达荷州的游客不会在那儿
It would be late, so the tourists from Idaho
他们已经睡觉了
wouldn't be there. They'd be in bed.
他在小意大利区
And him being down there in Little Italy,
也许会更自在  更放松
maybe he'd be more comfortable, more relaxed.
那天是他生日  所以他会带着老婆孩子一起去
It was his birthday so he'd be there with his wife
这样正好
and his kid which, in this case,
因为这正是我们的目的
that's good because that's the point.
应该让他们亲眼见识
They should have to see what it's like.
他已经喝了不少酒
He'd already been drinking,
这样他会迟缓很多
which would have slowed him down a lot.
他的保镖会跟着他
His bodyguard would be with him
乔伊自己也应该是带着枪的
and Joey himself could be carrying, too,
但他的枪可能在他老婆的包里
but then the piece would be in his wife's purse probably.
从来不会事先对你透露多少
You never got a lot of advance notice.
你只知道你到时候要做什么
All you knew was your part of it.
红发约翰只知道
John the Redhead knew only one thing:
他要开车送我过去
he was gonna drop me off,
绕着街区转  然后再接我
circle the block and pick me up.
安贝特蛤蜊餐厅
你得先解决掉保镖
You wanna take out the bodyguard first.
不是杀他  别杀他  让他失去行动能力就好
Not kill him. Don't kill him, just disable him.
你跟他无冤无仇
You got no argument with him,
所以别照着脸或者胸膛来一枪
so, not in the face or the chest.
有时  干这种活儿
Sometimes, with something like this,
你可能想先去趟厕所
you might want to go to the bathroom first.
好确定没人跟踪你进来
It gives you a chance to make sure nobody followed you in.
也能让你确定
It also gives you a chance to make sure
无需担心厕所里的人
nobody is in the bathroom you have to worry about.
也给你机会上趟厕所
It also gives you a chance to go to the bathroom.
干活的时候你不想不舒服
You don't want to be uncomfortable.
但我之前去过  深夜在这么个小餐厅
But I went before, and in a place this small, this late,
直接干活就行了
you might as well just get to work.
再来点红酒
We need more wine, all right?
汤米  再来点红酒
Tommy, some more wine.
之后呢
So how about after?
-蛋糕  蛋糕  蛋糕  -现在还不行
- Cake, cake, cake! - Not yet.
你还没吃完饭呢
You're not even done eating the meal yet.
你要蛋糕  得了吧  不能这样
You want the cake? Come on, you can't do that.
靠
Shit!
操  操
Fuck! Fuck!
此事发生在纽约的小意大利区
It happened in New York's Little Italy,
传言这里是黑帮的中立地带
an area rumored to be neutral territory among mobsters.
安贝特蛤蜊餐厅
凶杀之后
After the killing,
警方找到了几把枪以及一些指纹
police found several guns and some fingerprints
今日正在追查
which they were tracing today.
"疯子乔"乔瑟夫·加洛
Joseph "Crazy Joe" Gallo
晚间来到这家温馨的海鲜餐厅
had come to the intimate seafood restaurant to cap an evening of celebration
与他结婚不满一个月的妻子
with his new bride of less than a month,
以及与前妻所生的十一岁女儿一起庆祝
and his 11-year-old daughter by a previous marriage.
他们在庆祝乔的47岁生日
They were, uh, celebrating Joe's 47th birthday.
那晚他们先去了一家夜店
They had been to a nightclub early in the evening.
他们坐在餐厅后面的一桌  总共六个人
They were sitting at a rear table, this group of six people,
然后
when a, uh...
一个男人从后门进来
a man walked in from the back door,
直接走到
and he walked up, uh,
走到桌子边上  开了三枪
to the side of the table. He fired three shots.
他打了乔两枪
He hit Joe twice
-还打了他的保镖  -佩琪  走吧
- and he hit his bodyguard... - Peggy, let's go.
希腊人皮特一枪
...Pete the Greek, one time.
一共开了十四枪
There was a total of 14 shots fired.
佩琪  走吧
Peggy, come on.
乔伊·加洛的地盘总统街上
It's quiet here on President Street,
非常安静
Joey Gallo's turf.
甚至有些太安静了
In fact, it's too quiet.
在布鲁克林
Out here in Brooklyn,
乔伊·加洛是个英雄
Joey Gallo was a hero.
据猜测  他的死亡或将引发一场帮派战争
Speculation has it that his death may start a gang war,
可能已经悄然开始
if it hasn't already begun.
普通汽油
电话亭
-你好好的  吉米  -你也是  麦奇
- Take it easy, Jimmy. - You too, Mikey.
保重了  吉米
Take good care, Jimmy.
以防再也不见  问个好
If I don't see you again, hello.
四年后  花了五十万美元
Four years later and $500,000 under the table
贿赂尼克松的连任委员会
to Nixon's re-election committee,
吉米终于得偿所愿
Jimmy finally got what he wanted.
抱歉  不过我不会再回来了
Sorry, but I won't be back.
总统特赦以及假释
A presidential pardon and his parole.
吉米
Jimmy!
你现在打算做什么  吉米
What are you gonna do now, Jimmy?
我要做的第一件事就是
Well, the first thing I'm gonna do is register
去联邦缓刑办公室登记
with the Federal Probation Office,
然后就和我妻子一起去佛州晒太阳
and then I'm going down to Florida with my wife to get some sun.
那之后有什么计划吗
Any plans after that?
我要夺回我工会的控制权
Yeah, I'm gonna take back control of my union.
你要怎么做  吉米
How're you gonna do that, Jimmy?
菲茨也要竞选  你感觉怎么样
How do you like Fitz running against you?
感觉不好
I don't.
吉米  被关这么久是什么感觉
Jimmy, what was it like being locked up all that time?
非常好  我很开心
It was wonderful. Had a great time.
卢姆餐厅
我做的第一件事就是
The first thing I did was,
去卢姆餐厅买了几个辣味热狗
I picked up some chili dogs from Lum's,
吉米爱热狗就像爱冰激淋
which Jimmy loved almost as much as ice cream.
理查德·尼克松总统
A consultant to President
连任竞选委员会的一名顾问
Richard Nixon's re-election campaign committee...
他们的秘诀就是用啤酒蒸香肠
The secret is they steam them in beer.
这是全美最好吃的热狗
There ain't a better hot dog in America.
警方称麦考德和他的同谋
Police say McCord and his accomplices
随身带了电子监听设备
brought electronic listening devices with them
还卸下了两块天花板
and had removed two ceiling panels...
卢姆餐厅
以便在民主党全国委员会
...while installing eavesdropping equipment
安装窃听设备
at the Democratic National Committee.
卡车司机工会
你看看  他还真有胆子竞选工会主席
Look at this. He's got the balls to run for President of the Teamsters.
你看看  托尼·普罗还给他颁奖了
Look at this. And Tony Pro giving him an award.
这混蛋  你信吗
This fuck... Do you believe it?
卡车司机工会
菲茨很受特定人群的欢迎
Look, Fitz is very popular with certain people.
卡车司机工会
他当然受欢迎  能不受欢迎吗
Of course he's popular. Who wouldn't be popular?
哪个弟兄问他借钱他都给
He loans money to every goombah who asks.
所以托尼支持他  他把选票都给菲茨了
That's why Tony's behind him. He's given Fitz all his votes.
你受工会大多数人的支持
You got great support from most of the union.
你只需要托尼·普罗
All you need is Tony Pro's
在东北部的选民  你就能赢
voters in the Northeast, and you can win.
-你真不要吃一个吗  -不了  谢谢
- You sure you don't want one of these? - No, thank you.
我就是不敢相信我要去找托尼·普罗要选票
I just can't believe I gotta go to Tony Pro to get votes.
这都什么跟什么
What is that?
托尼牢牢控制着菲茨  吉米
Tony has Fitz in his pocket, Jimmy.
工会不受黑帮控制
Wise guys don't run the union.
有菲茨就行
With Fitz, they do.
吉米  等你重新当上主席
Jimmy, listen, as soon as you're back as president,
你想做什么就做什么
you can do anything you want to.
你想解雇谁就解雇谁
You can fire anybody you want to.
你把托尼·普罗解雇了都行
You can even fire Tony Pro.
你可以盯着他  让他清空桌子
You could stand over him, watch him clear out his desk.
还可以让他脱光  搜他的身
You could strip-search the guy.
确保他走的时候连个回形针都带不走
Make sure he doesn't walk off with a paper clip.
对  听见没  你听见没
Yes. See that? Did you hear that?
所有人都以为乔是白脸
See, everybody thinks Jo's the nice one
我是黑脸
and I'm the bad guy.
但其实是反过来
But it's opposite.
她是大灰狼  我是小绵羊
She's the killer and I'm the sweetheart.
现在我要去和狗杂种讲和了
Now I gotta make peace with the cocksucker.
我想和你重归于好
I want to make up with you.
我需要你支持我  拜托了  托尼
I need you to endorse me. Please, Tony.
求你了
Please.
该死
Fucking...
这事我做不来
I'm not gonna get through this.
你跟他谈谈就可以了
You gotta talk to him, that's all. Just...
你得处理好
You gotta deal with it, that's all.
顺其自然吧
Let the chips fall where they may.
不过他真是个狗杂种
He is a cocksucker, though.
要是我坐下和他谈  你一起来吗
If I sat down with him, would you come along?
你说什么呢  当然了
What are you talking about? Of course.
我怎么会不跟你去
How am I not gonna go with you?
妈的  走吧
Fuck it. Let's go.
吉米  吉米  给个机会
Jimmy, Jimmy. Give it a chance.
给个机会  再等几分钟
Give it a chance. Give it a few more minutes.
-就  -这样不行
- Just... - This isn't right.
这样不行  怎么能这样
This isn't right. You don't do this.
怎么能让人干等
You don't keep a man waiting.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
真要让人等
The only time you do
就代表你有话要说
is when you want to say something.
-我知道  -你想说"去死"
- I know. - When you want to say "Fuck you."
只有这种解释
That's the only time.
来了
Here they are.
你能相信这天气吗  弗兰克
Can you believe this weather, Frank? Huh?
外面快三十度了  真好
It's 85 degrees outside. Perfect.
我是托尼·杰克
Tony Jack.
我是吉米
Jimmy.
纽约的人都要冻死了  看看我们
People freezing to death in New York and look at us, huh?
我就想知道  我们干嘛不一直住在这里
Why we don't live here all year round is what I wanna know.
太棒了
Beautiful.
-这是夏天  -什么
- It's summer. - What?
这是夏天
It's summer.
纽约的人没要冻死
People aren't freezing to death in New York.
现在是夏天
It's summer.
在我心里  纽约一直零下十三度
In my mind, it's always eight degrees in New York.
我就想表个态
I'm making a point.
你想表个态
You're making a point.
穿成这样表态
Making a point dressing like that?
你开会就穿成这样吗
Is that how you dress for a meeting?
你在佛州就穿成这样吗  穿西装
This is how you dress in Florida? In a suit?
去开会吗
For a meeting?
别说佛州  不管在什么鬼地方
Anywhere. Florida, Timbuktu, I dress in a suit.
我开会都穿西装
For a meetin'.
-而且你迟到了  -什么
- And you're late. - What?
你迟到了
You're late.
嗯  路上堵车
Yeah, there was traffic.
是啊  堵车
Yes, traffic.
是不是堵车了
Wasn't there traffic?
-来堵车这一套  -的确堵车
- You give me traffic? - There was traffic.
你想要我们怎么办
What do you want from us?
保险杠都抵着保险杠了
It was bumper to fuckin' bumper.
是啊  堵车确实严重
Yeah, yeah. No, it's bad, you know?
堵车
Traffic.
我这辈子从来没有
I never waited for anyone who was late
等人超过十分钟
more than ten minutes in my life.
十五分钟吧  比较合适
I'd say fifteen. Fifteen's right.
不  十分钟
No, ten.
我觉得不行  十分钟不够
I don't think so, ten's not enough.
你得算上堵车的时间
You have to take traffic into account.
我算了  堵车的时间算进去了
That's what I'm doing. I'm taking traffic into account.
所以给了十分钟
That's why it's ten.
-我还是坚持十五分钟  -十分钟
- I still say 15. - No, ten.
行吧  这点我们保留意见
Fine. We disagree on that.
要不就十二分半
How about twelve and a half minutes?
这就对了  十二分半
There we go, 12.5.
中间值  正中间  太好了
The middle. Right in the middle. Beautiful.
超过十分钟
More than ten...
你就是有话要说了
you're saying something.
-你有话要对我说吗  -我来了
- You saying something to me? - I'm here.
就这个意思
It says what it says.
那就这样吧
So there it is.
接下来怎么谈
Where do we go from here?
我能为你做什么
Well, what can I do for you?
我希望你
I want you...
我
I...
我希望你支持我
I want you to endorse me...
支持什么你也清楚
for you know what.
在我们谈那个之前  先把另一件事讲清楚
Before we get to that, let's straighten that other thing up.
不  另一件事与我无关
No. The other thing is none of my business.
你的养老金我做不了主
I can't do anything about your pension.
不行  菲茨在就不行  菲茨是主席
I can't. Not with Fitz in there. Fitz is in there, you know.
-你去找菲茨  -找了
- You go to Fitz. - I did.
-他会帮你  -我找了
- He'll help you out. - I did.
他说会帮我解决  没问题
He said he'll take care of it, no questions asked.
你不愿意  但是他愿意
You wouldn't do that but he will.
我是说另一件事
I meant the other thing.
哪件事
What other thing?
你很清楚
You know.
我不清楚
I don't know.
你要道歉
Your apology.
我要道歉
My apology?
我道什么歉
My apology for what?
就是那时你像个国王一样
For what you said when you were sitting there
吃着冰激淋说出的话
eating your ice cream like some fucking king.
那可是种族污蔑  "你们这些人"
That was an ethnic slur. "You people."
-你知道他说了什么吗  -不  我听说
- Did you know what he said? - Nah, I mean, I heard...
我听说你们在牢里吵了一架  但我不清楚
I heard you had an altercation in the can, but I don't know.
对  "你们这些人"
Yeah, "You people."
你就这么说的  对吧  吉米
That's what you said. Right, Jim?
"你们这些人"  我是不如你吗
"You people." Am I beneath you?
一点没错
Definitely.
-吉米  别这样  -吉米  你干嘛
- Jimmy, come on. - Jimmy, what're you doing?
别忘了  你今天的地位全靠"我们这些人"
Don't forget, "You people" got you where you are.
别  别跟我说这种话  你个狗东...
Don't...don't tell me that, you fucking...
那就是你的问题所在  吉米
That's your problem, Jimmy.
你的问题在于你是个人渣
Your problem is you're a piece of shit.
吉米  拜托
Jimmy, come on.
-吉米  你在干什么  -天呐  吉米  别这样
- Jimmy, what are you doin'? - Jesus, Jimmy, come on.
我叫你支持我  你却跟我说这么多废话
I asked for your endorsement and you're giving me all this crap.
我叫你向我道歉
I asked for your apology.
你他妈算老几  我为什么要向你道歉
Who the fuck are you to apologize to?
吉米
Jimmy...
你他妈算老几啊
Who the fuck are you?
和气点
Be gentle.
-我不需要跟你谈  -坐下吧  托尼
- I don't need this. - Let's just sit down. Tony.
我就需要吗  难道我需要你
I need this? I need you?
-没错  你需要我  -得了吧
- Yeah, you need me. - Oh, please.
吉米  拜托  你对他有所求
Jimmy, come on. You're asking him for something.
这家伙让我紧张  他总是说些让我生气的话
The guy gets me nervous. He talks about things that get me upset.
-冷静点  -既然大家都来了
- Take it easy. - Everybody's here.
我们就赶紧开会吧  来吧
Let's have the fucking meeting. Come on.
-我们好好谈谈  -仅此而已
- Let's talk. - That's all.
他人来了
He's here.
你们在牢里吵的就是这个吗
Was this the altercation youse had in the can?
嗯  跟这差不多吧
Yeah, it was something like this.
我们  我们最后打了起来
We... We got to arm wrestling.
他输了
He lost.
有脸说我输了  你该瞧瞧他的肋骨
I lost. You should see his ribs.
你们还是谈正事吧  别扯其他的
Why don't you just talk about what you need to talk about.
-没错  -就是啊
- That's right. - Yeah.
你希望我怎么做
What do you want me to do?
我的确说了"你们这些人"
I said, "You people."
你希望我怎么做  为此道歉吗
What do you want me to do, apologize for it?
那正是我想要的  吉米  一句道歉
That's exactly what I want, Jimmy. An apology.
那我就为此道歉
I'll apologize for it.
我也别无他求
That's all I want.
前提是你先为这次迟到道歉
After you apologize for being late,
你个狗娘养的外国佬
you motherfucking wop cocksucker.
吉米  你他妈是疯了吗
Jimmy, are you out of your fucking mind?
我可以为迟到道歉
I'll apologize for being late
但我会先绑架你孙女  把她的内脏挖出来
after I kidnap your granddaughter, rip her guts out,
然后装在信封里寄给你
and send them to you in a fucking envelope!
把他拉开  快
Get him off! Come on!
我要杀了他
I'll fucking kill him!
-别打了  托尼  -天呐
- Come on, Tony! - Jesus!
你觉得罗素...
You think Russ would...
会不会解决掉那家伙
would do something about this guy?
那很复杂
That's complicated.
是啊  的确很复杂
Yeah. It's complicated.
我倒是想亲手宰了那个狗东西
I'd like to clip the motherfucker myself, you know,
-获得他们的同意  但是...  -我懂
- Get the okay from them. But... - I know.
必须除掉这家伙
This guy's gotta go.
必须除掉他  弗兰克
He's gotta go, Frank.
他们不可能同意我这么做的
I'm not gonna get the okay to do that.
弗兰克  跟那家伙谈谈
Frank, just talk to the guy.
好吗  找他好好谈谈
Okay? Just talk to him.
纽约  东哈莱姆区
第115大街
泽西的那些家伙不停给我打电话
These guys from Jersey keep fucking calling me
跟我说这两人之间的矛盾
about this bullshit between these two guys.
我把我对他们说的话再跟你们说一遍
I'm gonna tell you the same thing I told them.
我不认同普罗针对吉米说的那些话
I don't approve of what Pro said about Jimmy.
是啊
No.
谁会那样去威胁别人的孙辈啊
I mean, who talks like that about a person's grandchildren?
-那是不对的  -是啊
- It's not fucking right. - No.
托尼·萨雷诺  绰号"胖子托尼"
被判一百年徒刑
1992年死于狱中  享年80岁
但普罗也不是无名小卒
But Pro isn't nobody.
吉米应该明白这点的
Jimmy should know that.
我能怎么办
What am I gonna go?
我又没办法告诫那家伙能说什么  不能说什么
I'm not gonna tell this guy what he can or can't fucking say,
把他当小孩管教
like he's a child.
听着
Well, listen.
吉米其实没什么恶意  他只是很生气
Jimmy don't mean nothing. He just gets upset.
罗素  拜托  我们都知道他暴躁易怒
Russ, come on, we all know he's a fucking hothead.
我们都曾有过暴躁易怒的时候
We're all hotheads once in a while.
是没错  但吉米有时会说些不该说的话
Yeah, but Jimmy says things he shouldn't say sometimes.
是  我们有时也都会那样
Yeah. We all do that too.
该有人让他冷静下来
Well, somebody should just calm him down.
好吧  我会...
Yeah, well, that... I'm gonna...
我会让他冷静下来的  他很不好搞  但...
I'm gonna calm him down. He's difficult, but...
或许这能帮他冷静下来
Maybe this could help him calm down.
你可以告诉他  我向来都很喜欢他
You could tell him that I always liked him.
并且我不会阻拦他夺回他的职位
And I won't stand in his way of him trying to get his job back.
我会的  我会告诉他这点的  托尼
I will. I will tell him that, Tony.
-好吗  -好的
- Okay? - Yes.
那可无法让我冷静下来
That's not making me calm down.
站我这边
Standing by me.
那他妈是什么意思
What the fuck does that mean?
站我这边跟采取措施
Standing by me ain't the same thing as doing something
处理一个失控的疯子  可不是一回事
about some out-of-control fucking psycho!
吉米  矮子可不是无名小卒
Jimmy, the Little Guy ain't a nobody.
你必须明白这点
You gotta understand that.
-他可不是无名小卒  -他是个龟孙
- He ain't a nobody. - He's a cocksucker.
菲茨也是个龟孙
Fitz is a cocksucker.
我要把这些龟孙全都解决掉
I'm gonna deal with both these cocksuckers...
我亲自动手
myself!
这里以前是我的办公室
This used to be my office.
进去找弗兰克·菲茨西蒙斯吧  你们是找不到他的
Go look for Frank Fitzsimmons there. You're not gonna find him.
国际卡车司机工会
因为他在全国各地旅游
That's because he travels all over the country
寻找好的高尔夫球场  他就只会干这个
looking for goddamn golf courses because that's what he does.
他喜欢打高尔夫
He plays golf.
他算老几  能跟在尼克松身边
Who is he to run around with Nixon,
跟在司法部长身边
run around with the attorney general?
他整天就知道打高尔夫  还能领全额薪水
He does this and collects full-time salary while he's doing it.
那是怎么做到的
Now, how do you do that?
这份工作  一天24小时都不够忙活的
There's not enough hours in a day to do this job.
我因为欺诈罪被判刑入狱
I was sent to prison for fraud.
他的所为  才叫欺诈呢
This is fraud, what he's doing.
那么菲茨对吉米的回应是怎样的呢
So what's Fitz's answer to Jimmy?
他给吉米的老朋友
He does it by sending a message
戴夫·约翰逊传达了一条信息
to Jimmy's old friend, Dave Johnson.
戴夫·约翰逊  他是299号地方工会的主席
Now, Dave Johnson, he ran Local 299.
信息是这样的
This was the message.
菲茨就是以这种方式表明
So this is how Fitz says
他希望我的老朋友戴夫·约翰逊退位
he wants my old pal Dave Johnson to step down
好让他的儿子接管299号地方工会
so he can have his son take over Local 299.
那么我打算用接下来的方式拒绝他儿子小菲茨
This is how I'm gonna say no to his son, little fucking Fitz.
她长得很像你妈
She looked a lot like your mother.
体型都差不多
About the same size.
爸  拜托  你都说了上千遍了
Pops, come on, you told me like a thousand times.
长得漂亮  她长得很漂亮
Good-looking girl. She was a good-looking girl.
但我当时真不知道那不是你妈
But I had no idea that it wasn't your mother.
当时那里很暗...
It was dark and...
霍法
约·霍法
运输部  女助理
接下来菲茨用这种方式表明他不喜欢
This is how Fitz says he doesn't like
我选定的299号工会负责人
who I say runs the 299.
他开除了我老婆
By firing my wife
让她失去了年薪4.8万美元的工会工作
from her forty-eight-fucking-thousand- dollar-a-year union job!
卡车司机299号地方工会
狗娘养的  他去死吧
Son of a bitch. Fuck him!
他事先在水门大厦
He had previously taped the locks
大门的锁上贴了个胶带
on the entry door of the basement of the Watergate...
-你在看什么  -就...
- What are you looking at? - Uh, it's...
是大耳朵
It's Big Ears.
小埃弗雷特·霍华德·亨特
前中情局探员
他注意到那个胶带被人撕掉了
He had noticed that the tape had been removed,
于是他又重新贴了胶带
and he re-taped the door.
大耳朵
Big Ears?
那是...
That's, uh...
我很多年前认识的一个人
Somebody I met a long time ago. Just...
他的耳朵也没那么大啊
His ears ain't so big.
那个时候  我就说  "收工吧"
...at that point, I said "Let us junk it,"
也就是放弃行动
meaning let us scrap the operation.
利迪先生和麦考德先生私下谈了谈
Mr. Liddy and Mr. McCord talked between themselves
就做出了决定  继续行动
and the decision was made to go.
我当时觉得这很鲁莽...
I thought it was very foolhardy...
那么  在你看来  弗兰克·菲茨西蒙斯
So, Frank Fitzsimmons, in your opinion,
媒体见面会  直播
应该继续担任卡车司机工会的主席吗
should he remain president of the Teamsters?
绝对不能
Absolutely not.
詹姆斯·霍法
弗兰克·菲茨西蒙斯已经将他的工会
Frank Fitzsimmons has sold his union out
卖给了他的黑社会朋友
to his underworld pals.
黑帮控制着他
The mob controls him,
那意味着他们也控制着我们的养老金
which means it controls our pension fund.
我说的是上十亿美元的低息或无息贷款
I'm talking about a billion dollars in low or no-interest loans
都被他借给了已知的黑帮分子
this man has given to known racketeers
用到他们非法勾当中
for their illegal enterprises.
再也不可能了
Not anymore.
船将沉  老鼠该弃船而逃了
It's time for the rats to abandon ship.
他是认真的吗
Is he serious?
吉米才不是认真的  这都是宣传手段
Not Jimmy. This is all publicity.
他在竞选公职  只是做做样子罢了
He's running for office. He's putting on a show.
是啊  都是空口号  没有实质
Yeah, it's all puff. It's got no substance, nothing.
或许他就是认真的
Maybe he means what he says.
-托尼  他在竞选  -罗素
- Tony, he's campaigning. - Russ.
他可以信口开河
He's liable to say any fucking thing.
我才不管他是不是在竞选
I don't care if he's campaigning.
他不能说这种话
He can't talk like that.
那可不好
It's no fucking good.
我明白你的意思
I understand what you're saying.
你知道他该做什么吗  罗素
You know what he should do, Russ?
他应该将他那一大笔养老金提现
He should cash in that big pension of his.
多陪陪他的孙辈们
Spend more time with his grandchildren.
他有幸福美满的家庭  不是吗
He got a beautiful family, no?
是啊  是啊  没错
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, right.
或许他应该放轻松
Maybe he should relax.
该让人给他传个话
Word should get back to him.
我  我只想说
I... I just wanna say...
我不希望你误会我接下来的话
I don't want you to take this the wrong way.
但我之前跟一些人在一起
But there I was with some people
你也知道是哪些人  他们说...
and they were saying, and you know who they are...
他们说...
They were saying...
"请转告吉米我们爱他
"Please tell Jimmy we love the guy.
我们并不想惹麻烦
We don't want any problem.
我们只是认为他应该...
We just think that he should...
享受陪伴孙辈的日子
maybe enjoy his grandchildren,
享受养老金  享受目前的生活"
enjoy his pension, enjoy his life as is."
不用再说了  弗兰克
Go no further, Frank.
是谁说的
Who said it?
-是谁说的并不重要  -当然重要
- It don't matter who said it. - Oh, it matters.
-是罗素吗  -不是
- Was it Russell? - No.
当然不是罗素
Of course it's not Russell.
是迈阿密那事儿的那个龟孙吗
It's that little cocksucker from the Miami fiasco?
-不是吗  -不是
- No? - No.
不是他吗  真不是吗
Not him. No?
那是谁
Then who?
我还是告诉你吧
I'm gonna tell you.
是托尼
Tony.
托尼
Tony?
哪个托尼
Which Tony?
那么多人叫托尼
They're all named Tony.
意大利人是怎么回事
I mean, what's the matter with Italians?
他们难道没别的名字取了吗
They can only think of one name.
另一个托尼
The other Tony.
哪个
What Tony?
萨雷诺
Salerno.
我能说什么呢
Well, what can I say?
吉米  我这是在帮你
Jimmy, I'm trying to help you.
-让你明白一些事  -我知道
- I'm trying to tell you something. - I know you are.
弗兰克  想都别想
Frank, don't even think about it.
我向来是有话直说
I don't keep my mouth shut...
-我知道  -对谁都是如此
- I know that. - ...for anyone.
我知你知  但他们不知道
I know that, you know that, they don't know that.
这就是我的为人本性  我也不会做出任何改变
That's who I am, that's what I am and that's what I'm gonna do.
可以找人转告他了
Somebody can tell him that.
他这么说了
He said that?
我只说了个大概  你懂的
In so many words, you know.
那他在口出狂言之前
Well, before he says something like that,
就应该想到乔·加洛
he should remember that Joe Gallo liked to make
也是老管不住自己的嘴巴
a lot of fucking noise, too.
找个人转告他吧
Somebody should tell him that.
又是谁说的
Who said?
-托尼  -他说的
- Tony. - He said that?
行了  我决定了
That's it. That does it.
我到死都不会退休
I'm never gonna retire now.
找个人转告他吧
Somebody can tell him that.
吉米  我跟他说了  说了不知道多少遍
Jimmy, I did tell him. I told him over and over.
那这样  你跟他说别再传来传去了
All right, you told him. Let's stop this, then.
算了吧  不谈了
Forget it. Enough.
让我好好享用我的冰淇淋
Let me enjoy my ice cream here.
怎么了
What's the matter?
没事
Nothing.
说啊
What?
-真没事  -怎么可能没事
- Nothing. - What do you mean, nothing?
你想说什么  告诉我
Come on, you're thinking something. What?
我只是...
I just...
怎么了  说啊  别扭扭捏捏的
What? Come on. What are you doing?
-现在说不太合适  -你什么意思
- It ain't the right time. - What do you mean it ain't the right time?
现在就很合适  什么时候说都合适
It is the right time. What isn't the right time?
快说
Say it.
地方工会正在筹备一场
The Local's putting together
给我的答谢晚宴
a testimonial dinner for me and...
给你的答谢晚宴  那很好啊
A testimonial dinner for you, that's good.
是的  不过之后有...
Yeah. But later... Later, when...
你想说什么
What's the matter?
我打算问你愿不愿意
I was gonna ask you if you would...
为我颁奖
present the award to me.
这个嘛
Well...
有心了  弗兰克
That's nice of you, Frank.
真的  你能想起我真好
Really. That's nice of you. And, you know...
还有谁会参加
Who's gonna be there?
都会来
Everybody.
是一大群叫托尼的吗
Tony, Tony, Tony, Tony, and Tony, huh?
下城的都会来
Everybody from Downtown.
算了  还是不太好  到时候所有人都会来
Nah. Nah, it ain't a good idea. Everybody's gonna be there.
你会不自在的
People... You're gonna be uncomfortable.
我才不管谁去谁不去
I don't give a fuck who's there.
难道那群狗杂种在
We gonna let those cocksuckers
我就不能出席你的重大晚宴了吗  休想
keep me from your big night? There's no way.
不可能
No.
我会去的  而且是我荣幸之至
I'm gonna be there. And I'll be honored to be there.
你当之无愧
You deserve this.
-谢谢你  吉米  -没事
- Thank you, Jimmy. Thank you. - Yeah.
-看那个内奸迪恩  -是啊
- That mole Dean. - Yeah.
-这婆娘挺漂亮  -确实
- She's a good-looking broad. - She's nice.
直到六月份
I did not realize
我才知道霍华德·亨特先生
that Mr. Howard Hunt worked most of the time
在白宫的大部分时间
while he was at the White House
前白宫法律顾问
约翰·W·迪恩三世
都是在管工部门工作
in the plumbers unit until after June...
他就是个叛徒  不过...
He's a rat, but that's, you know...
确实是  但他是个精明的叛徒
He's a rat. But he's a smart rat.
拉丁赌场  剧院  餐厅
今晚这么多人都是来给弗兰克捧场的吧
We've got a great crowd for Frank tonight, huh?
弗兰克·希兰
答谢晚宴
1973年10月18日
给他来点掌声
Come on. Give it up.
这是因为弗兰克广结好友
That's because Frank is a man with a lot of friends.
有在乔治·巴顿将军的带领下
From his war buddies who fought with him in Italy
与他在意大利并肩作战的战友
under General George Patton...
还有司机  全国工会组织者
to the drivers, national organizers,
屋顶工工会主席
约翰·麦卡洛
1980年在自家厨房头中六枪身亡
代理商  地方工会主席
business agents, local presidents,
联合委员会主席  以及区域受托人等等
joint committee chairmen, and regional trustees,
今晚到场的都是弗兰克的好友
we are all friends of Frank's tonight.
弗兰克的好友
Friends of Frank.
比如全国有色人种协进会主席塞西尔·摩尔
Like NAACP president Cecil Moore.
地方检察官艾米特·菲茨帕特里克
District Attorney Emmett Fitzpatrick.
费城市长弗兰克·里佐
Philadelphia mayor Frank Rizzo.
他们都喜欢你呢  弗兰克
Hey, they like you, Frank.
当然  还有我们的特邀发言人
And, of course, our featured speaker,
詹姆斯·里德尔·霍法
James Riddell Hoffa.
同时呢  在外面的树上
And meanwhile, outside in the trees,
还藏着联调局的人
we got the FBI.
有谁要去看看吗
Somebody wanna check on them?
我来分享一下我第一次见到弗兰克时的场景吧
Now, let me tell you about the first time I met Frank.
他带我去吃牛排晚餐
He took me out to a steak dinner,
他问我说  "你的牛排要几分熟"
and he asked me, he said, "How do you like your steak?"
我说"我喜欢一分熟"  他说"我也是"
I said, "I like it rare." He said, "Me too."
然后就开始上牛排了  我的是一分熟
Well, they bring out the steaks. Mine's rare.
弗兰克的那份正从厨房里走出来
Frank's was still walking from the kitchen.
他转身对我说  "其实吧
He turns to me, he said, "Well, you know,
我喜欢动物  我不想杀生"
I'm an animal lover. I don't wanna hurt it."
他居然喜欢动物
He's an animal lover.
这家伙连主席都没当上
This guy is not even the goddamn president
就在拖延别人的贷款了
and he's holding up people's loans.
-你确定吗  -我确定
- Are you sure? - I'm sure.
他是怎么办到的
And how's he supposed to do that?
因为他的手下拖延了
Because his guys are holding 'em back loans
卡洛斯在新奥尔良建新酒店的钱
on Carlos's new hotel in New Orleans,
我们在凯撒酒店扩建的钱
the add-on that we're doing at Caesars.
-菲茨都在做些什么  -菲茨吗
- And what's Fitz doing all this time? - Fitz?
是啊  这事应该他管的
Yeah, he's supposed to help with this shit.
钱是养老基金的受托人出的
The money comes from the Pension Fund trustees.
他们应该要签字同意
They gotta sign off on it.
他们本应该听菲茨的安排开绿灯
They're supposed to be rubber-stamping what Fitz says.
-没错  -只是吉米
- Right, right. Yeah. - Except Jimmy
让其中几位拒绝开绿灯了
has a couple of them to stop rubber-stamping.
这个王八蛋
The son of a bitch.
我以为已经处理好了
I thought we took care of that.
你知道他怎么跟人说的吗
You know what he told somebody?
他说一旦菲茨下位  他成功上台
He goes, once Fitz is out and he's in,
他就要收回以前的债款
he's gonna call in the old loans.
酒店  赌场  房地产之类的
Hotels, casinos, real estate, no matter what it is.
而且你要是没有马上连本带利还钱给他
And if you don't have his money and interest in two seconds,
他就要全部接管
he's taking 'em over.
不能让他得逞
We can't have that.
-这是他说的  -是他说的
- He said that? - He said that.
你确定这是他的原话吗  托尼
You sure he said that, Tony?
是他的原话
He said that.
我跟你说的这些全都是他的原话
Everything I'm telling you, yeah, he said.
他以为他是谁啊  卡斯特罗吗
I mean, who does he think he is? Castro?
♪ 就是现在 ♪
♪ The time is now ♪
♪ 一同起立欢呼 ♪
♪ The time to stand and cheer ♪
♪ 因为留下的都是美好时光 ♪
♪ 'Cause better times are here to stay ♪
♪ 昨日已远去 ♪
♪ Oh, yesterday is over ♪
♪ 明日要到来 ♪
♪ Tomorrow's on its way ♪
♪ 但快来看看今天有什么在等待着你 ♪
♪ But look what's new and made for you today ♪
♪ 今天 ♪
♪ Today ♪
你要的不是钱吧
You don't need money, do you?
与钱无关
It's not about money.
如果不是为了钱
If it's not about money,
那我就真的有点搞不懂了
then I'm really having trouble understanding,
我们谈了那么久到底是为了什么
because I don't know what all the talk is about.
这是我的工会
It's my union.
-这很难理解吗  -不是
- Is that hard to understand? - No, no.
这是你的工会  没问题  永远都是你的工会
It's your union, that's right. It'll always be your union.
你完全可以下台在幕后管理
You could step down and still run it.
-我才不会下台  -你这话什么意思
- No, you don't step down. - What do you mean?
罗素  下台是管不了工会的
Russ, you don't step down to run a union.
下台是直接进坟墓
You step down to go to your grave.
听好了
Well, listen.
我还是在想...不好意思
I still think... I can't help but think, I'm sorry,
你这么迫切是出于什么其他理由吗
but is there another reason or something?
这是我的工会  "其他理由"又是什么意思
This is my union! What do you mean, "another reason"?
这是我的工会
This is my union.
好吗  你先明确好这一点
All right? Let's start with that
再去弄清楚别的事情
and then try to understand things.
听我说  有人
Listen, some people,
不是我  但有人
not me, but some people,
他们有点顾虑
they're a little concerned.
有人  不是我  他们觉得你可能...
Some people, not me, they think that you might...
我可能什么
I might...
你可能没有表达出应有的感激之举
You might be demonstrating a failure to show appreciation.
我没有表现出感激
I'm not showing appreciation?
有人是这么说的
According to, you know, some people.
我蹲了五年牢房
I went to school for five fucking years.
-我知道  -整整五年
- Yes, you did. - Five fucking years.
我没有供出任何一个人
I didn't name one fucking name.
-你做得对  -我做得对
- You did the right thing. - I did the right thing.
你做得很对
You did the right thing.
我每天都要跟那个
I sat there every day with that
爱发牢骚的新泽西狗杂种坐在一起
whining cocksucker from New Jersey,
听他说有他多么不幸  有多困难
talking to me about his woes, his problems,
而我只是想安安静静地吃个冰淇淋
and all I wanted to do was finish my ice cream in peace.
这个狗杂种开会迟到了十五分钟
This cocksucker shows up at a meeting 15 minutes late,
还穿着他妈的短裤
wearing fucking shorts!
-谁会穿短裤去开会  -谁都不会
- Who wears shorts to a meeting? - Nobody.
-没错  -没人会这么做
- That's right. - Nobody.
还说我没有表示感激
I'm not showing appreciation?
不是我说的
It's not me.
是有人这么说
According to some people...
我知道不是你  是另有他人
No, I know it's not you. Some people...
另有他人说我没有表示感激
Some people say I'm not showing appreciation?
那就去他们的吧
Well, then fuck them.
我这是在帮你  吉米
I'm trying to help you, Jim.
我知道
I know you are.
但是谁都别想威胁霍法
But nobody threatens Hoffa.
♪ 就是现在 ♪
♪ The time is now ♪
♪ 就是当下 ♪
♪ 就是此刻 ♪
♪ The time is now ♪
他当过司机
He has done it as a driver,
当过工会组织者
he has done it as an organizer,
还有可能在场的大多数来宾都不知道
and I don't think many of you here know this,
弗兰克手握一项记录
but Frank holds a record.
在罢工纠察线上被逮捕次数最多的人
It's most arrests on the picket line.
一天内26次
Twenty-six times in 24 hours,
打破了我的记录
beating my record.
没错  女士们先生们  我没有夸大其词
There it is, ladies and gentlemen. There's no exaggeration.
他是彻头彻尾的工会人
He is a union man to his bones.
你们选择站在哪一边
Which side are you on?
你这边
Your side!
哪一边
Whose side?
你这边
Your side!
我这边
My side.
你这边
Your side.
-他那边  -没错
- His side. - Yeah!
就是这样
There it is.
所以今晚我很荣幸在这里
And so, it is an honor for me to be here tonight
将这份奖
to present this award
颁给我亲爱的朋友  弗兰克·希兰先生
to my dear friend, Mr. Frank Sheeran!
谢谢你  吉米  非常感谢
Thank you, Jimmy, thank you so much.
也谢谢我亲爱的妻子琳妮
And thank you to my lovely wife Reenie
陪我来这里
for being here with me.
感谢我甜美可爱的女儿们
My lovely, sweet, adorable daughters,
玛丽安  多洛莉丝  康妮  佩琪
Maryanne, Dolores, Connie, Peggy,
这么多年一直容忍我
for putting up with me for all these years.
还有吉米  我无法表达你给我颁发这份荣誉
And, Jimmy, I can't tell you what this means to me
对我意义多么重大
to get this honor from you.
我人生最重要的时刻  非常非常感谢你
It's the highlight of my life. Thank you very, very much.
这个人  詹姆斯·里德尔·霍法
And this man, James Riddell Hoffa,
是最能成事的人
is the guy that gets the job done.
我就在你身后  吉米
I'm behind you, Jimmy.
一路随行
All the way.
总之
In any case,
我衷心感谢你们所有人
from the deepest part of my heart, I thank you all.
我并不该获得这一切
'Cause I don't really deserve all this.
但我得了滑囊炎  我也不该得那个
But I have bursitis and I don't deserve that either.
今晚感谢你们所有人  感谢前来
Thank you all tonight and thank you for coming.
晚安
Good night.
怎么不喊"说茄子"
What happened to "Say cheese"?
茄子
Cheese!
♪ 让我的爱盈满你的心 ♪
♪ Bringing you all the love your heart can hold ♪
♪ 请说"我愿意" ♪
♪ Please say "sí, sí" ♪
♪ 说你及你那西班牙眼眸会为我等待 ♪
♪ Say you and your Spanish eyes will wait for me ♪
♪ 蓝色的西班牙眼眸 ♪
♪ Blue Spanish eyes ♪
♪ 墨西哥最美的双眼 ♪
♪ Prettiest eyes in all of Mexico ♪
♪ 真诚的西班牙眼眸 ♪
♪ True Spanish eyes ♪
♪ 请在我离开前再为我展开笑颜 ♪
♪ Please smile for me once more before I go... ♪
世上只有三个人有这个
Only three people in the world have one of these.
其中只有一人是爱尔兰人
And only one of them is Irish.
我有一枚
I have one.
安吉洛有一枚
Angelo has one.
现在你也有了
Now you have one.
真漂亮
This is beautiful.
我不知道该说什么  罗素  这...
I... I don't... I don't know what to say, Russ. It's...
快戴上  看看怎么样
Slip it on. See how it looks.
-感觉好吗  -好
- Feel good? - Yeah.
你知道我让你变得多强吗  知道多强吗
You know how strong I made you? You know how strong?
你是我的小子
You're my kid.
没人...没人能搞你
Nobody... Nobody can fuck with you.
没人
Nobody.
听着  弗兰克
Listen, Frank.
我们的朋友又失控了
Things have gotten out of hand with our friend again.
有些人对他意见很大
And some people are having serious problems with him.
到现在这个地步
And it's at a point where
你必须找他谈谈  告诉他
you're gonna have to talk to him and tell him
到此为止了
it's what it is.
到此为止
What it is?
是的  这是他们的意愿
Yes. It's what they want.
已经到这步了
It's where it's gotten.
你和他亲近  或许他会听你的
You're close to him. Maybe he'll listen to you.
你知道我和他谈过
You know I talked to him.
他这人很固执  你了解他的
He's a tough guy to talk to. You know him.
他没得选
He has no choice.
这些是大人物
These are the higher-ups.
他也是个大人物  不是吗
Well, he's a higher-up too. I mean... No?
和他们不同  你知道的
Not like this. You know that.
拜托  弗兰克
Come on now, Frank.
如果他们能干掉一个总统
If they can whack a president,
他们就能干掉一个工会主席
they can whack a president of the union.
你知道  我也知道
You know it and I know it.
我和他谈过一次又一次
I talk to this guy, I talk to him, I talk to him,
他就是不听
I talk to him, he don't listen.
但他现在必须听  我得让他听进去
But he's gotta listen now. I gotta make him listen.
这样不对  他就是个傻瓜
That ain't right. He's... he's a fucking knucklehead.
吉米  我和罗素谈了
Jimmy. I talked to Russ.
他和托尼谈过
He talked to Tony.
他说的话是认真的
He means what he's saying.
-谁  罗素吗  -不  托尼
- Who? Russ? - No, Tony.
-托尼  -是的
- Tony? - Yeah.
我说的话也是认真的
Well, I mean what I'm saying.
他那该死的西西里肥脑袋似乎就是不明白
He can't seem to get that through his fat, fucking Sicilian head.
对不对  别担心
Can he? Don't worry about it.
你怎么了
What's the matter with you?
你看起来...
You... you look...
-我很担心  -我知道
- I'm concerned. - Yeah, I know.
你看起来就在担心  你担心什么
You look concerned. What are you concerned about?
我...
I'm... I'm...
该担心的是他们
They should be concerned.
-他们确实担心  -那就让他们担心去
- They are. They are. - Well, let them be.
他们不止有一点点担心
They're more than a little concerned.
他们担心颇多
There's widespread concern.
这是个大问题
It's a big problem.
托尼让老爷子叫我告诉你...
Tony told the old man to tell me to tell you...
"到此为止了"
"It's what it is."
到此为止
What it is?
到此为止了
It's what it is.
拜托  听我说
Please, listen to me.
他们不敢
They wouldn't dare.
-别...  -他们不敢
- Don't... - They wouldn't dare.
-吉米  -得了吧  弗兰克
- Jimmy... - Please, Frank, come on.
-别说他们不敢  -不
- Don't say they wouldn't dare. - No.
别跟我说这种话...都是胡扯
Don't... don't tell me that kinda... That's fairy tales.
别说他们不敢
No, don't say they wouldn't dare.
如果我出了什么事
If something funny happens to me...
他们就完了
they're done.
你明白吗  他们也清楚这点
You understand that? And they know it.
因为我有文件  我有证据
Because I got files. I got proof.
我有记录  我有录音带
I got records. I got tapes.
只要我想  他们随时会完蛋
Any time I want, they'll be gone.
这些几内亚混蛋
These Guinea motherfuckers
余生都会在监狱度过
will spend the rest of their lives in jail,
他们清楚
and they know it.
They know it.
但你现在说的正是他们担心的
But what you're saying is what they're concerned about.
我在说的是我知道他们的事
What I'm saying is I know things.
我知道他们不知道我知道的事
I know things they don't know I know.
-拜托  -你真的要冒那个险吗
- Please... - Are you gonna take that chance?
我冒什么...我为什么要冒险
What chance am I... Why should I be taking a chance?
他们说到此为止了
They're saying this is it.
他们说到此为止  那就到此为止吗
They're saying this is it, and then it's it?
-胡说  胡说  弗兰克  -别这样
- Bullshit. Bullshit, Frank. - Come on.
吉米  我是想告诉你
Jimmy, I'm trying to tell you something.
我知道你是  你在告诉我他们威胁我
I know you are. You're telling me that they're threatening me
我必须照他们说的做
and I gotta do what they say.
那不只是威胁  那是底线
It's more than a threat. It's the bottom line.
底线
The bottom line.
到此为止了
It's what it is.
他们搞我  我就搞他们
They do something to me, I do something to them.
我就知道这个  别的我不知道  你知道吗
That's all I know. I don't know anything else. Do you?
那我要怎么做  我该怎么跟麦基说
So what am I gonna do? What am I gonna tell McGee?
说你不肯听吗
That you're not gonna listen?
他不习惯有人不听他的
He ain't used to people not listening to him.
我也是
Well, neither am I.
-什么  -我也是
- What? - Neither am I.
那我不知道该怎么办了
Then I don't know what to do.
或许你该找些保镖
I mean, maybe you should get some bodies around you
-保护你  -得了吧
- for protection. - Come on. Please.
我不会选那条路
I'm not gonna go that route.
别这么对我  弗兰克
Don't do this to me, Frank.
你说"找些保镖"是什么意思  我不需要
What do you mean, "bodies around me"? I don't need...
你找保镖  他们就会找上你的家人
You put bodies around you, then they go after your family.
-这不重要  你担心吗  -我担心
- It doesn't matter. You worried? - I'm worried.
你去找些保镖吧  我告诉你为什么
Get some bodies around you. I'll tell you why.
这事可能落到你身上
This could happen to you.
他们可能找上你
They could come after you
因为你支持我
since you're with me.
不是吗
No?
我很担心
I'm worried.
告诉罗素我对他只有尊重
Tell Russ I got nothing but respect for him.
我和他有点小摩擦
I got a little trouble with him.
我们之前谈的时候  我有点失控
We were talking before and I just got a little crazy.
-你知道我什么样  有时会发脾气  -是的
- You know how I am. I just blow. Sometimes. - Yeah.
气得扭头就走
I just walked away like that.
但我就是这样的人
But I get that way. I get abrupt.
或许你能告诉他我多么尊重他
Maybe you could tell him how much I respect him.
我对他只有尊重
I have nothing but respect for this guy.
我永远不会伤害他
I would never hurt him,
不管我手上有什么文件  不管我做什么
no matter what I do with files, or whatever I do with anything.
你应该亲自告诉他
But you should tell him. Yourself.
不  我不要亲自告诉他
No, I'm not gonna tell him myself.
-拜托  -算了吧
- Please. - Come on.
-亲口说更有意义  -他是你的导师
- It would go a long way. - He's your rabbi.
你有今天全靠他
Because of him, you're here.
你告诉他
You tell him.
听我说
Listen to me.
最终只有一件事是真的
At the end, there's only one thing that's real.
这是我的工会
This is my union.
这是我的工会  弗兰克
This is my union, Frank.
明确这一点  其他就简单了
Very simple when you say it that way.
佩琪
Peggy!
我们跳舞吧
Shall we dance?
失陪
Excuse us.
距离底特律几小时车程
A couple of hours outside Detroit,
我们决定住一晚
we figured we'd spend the night,
早上再赶路
drive up in the morning.
我们要去参加婚礼
I mean, the wedding, that was the thing.
比尔·巴法利诺要把女儿嫁给一个好男人
Bill Bufalino, you know, was giving his daughter away to a hell of a guy.
比之前那个无赖好
Better than the bum she was with before.
这是件好事
And that was all well and good.
但婚礼实际是求和任务
But the wedding was really a peace mission.
那才是我们参加的目的
And that's what we were there for.
哥伦布
代顿
底特律
大家差不多都知道
And everybody kinda knew that,
我们是去理清这件事的
and we were there to straighten it all out.
-吉米  -是我
- Jimmy? - Yeah.
我和老爷子在一起  我们开车过去
I'm with the old man, we're driving up.
他希望我们能把整件事理清楚
He hopes we can straighten this whole thing out.
他说了什么
What did he say?
他说希望我们能理清这事
He said he hopes we can straighten it out.
婚礼之后  我们坐下谈谈
After the wedding, we sit down, we talk,
理清这事
we straighten it out.
婚礼啊
Right, the wedding.
我不准备参加婚礼
I'm not going to the wedding.
太多我不喜欢的人会到场
Too many people I don't like are gonna be there,
所以我不准备去
so I'm not going to the wedding.
你不去参加婚礼吗
You're not going to the wedding?
我不会去
I'm not gonna be there.
那我们可以...
Well, then we could...
吉米  你想在哪里谈都可以
Jimmy, then we could do it anywhere you want.
可以在你家
We can do it at your house.
你想在哪里都行
We can do it anywhere you want.
地点任你选择
Wherever you're comfortable.
湖边怎么样
The lake?
好  湖边  你想在那里谈吗
Yeah, the lake. You wanna do it at the lake?
我一开始就想把这事谈妥
From day one, I wanted to work this out.
-我知道  我知道  -从他妈的一开始
- I know. I know. - From day fucking one.
我明白  我比任何人都清楚  我知道
I know. Nobody knows better than me. I know that.
好  就你们俩来吧
All right, uh... Just you two, right?
别带上那个矮子
I mean, not the Little Guy.
-不  他当然得去  -不行
- No, of course, the Little Guy. - No.
我不要跟他谈
I'm not doing it with him.
吉米  只有我们三个人谈没有用
Jimmy, there's no point just the three of us.
不  不  不
No, no. No, no.
就我们三个人谈  就这样...
Just the three of us. That's the way it's...
只有我们三个人谈没有用
There's no point just the three of us.
矮子必须得在场
It's gotta be the Little Guy with us.
不  我不要再跟那个小龟孙谈了
No, I'm not sitting down with that little cocksucker again!
你明白吗  我做不到  弗兰克
Do you understand? I can't do it, Frank!
你必须跟他谈
You have to.
不  吉米  你得跟他谈谈
No, Jimmy, you gotta sit down with him.
-什么都不必做  -大家都说...
- We don't gotta do anything. - Everybody says...
我这是出于对他们的礼貌
This is a courtesy with these people.
完全是给他们面子
A complete courtesy.
-你懂的  -我明白
- You know that. - I understand.
但你得试着让这事过去
But you gotta try and move past that.
我已经让这事过去了
Get past it? I am past it!
我再也不会见那个混蛋了
I'm never seeing that motherfucker again.
-这就是...  -吉米  你得坐下来好好谈
- You see that's... - Jimmy, you gotta sit down.
大家都这么说
Everybody says so.
但这没有意义  只有一点
But there's no point. There's only one point,
我不想这么做  我也不会这么做
I don't wanna do it and I'm not gonna do it.
弗兰克  我要挂你电话了
Frank, I'm gonna hang up on you now.
拜托  理解一下  好吗
Please. Understand this. Okay?
-他怎么说  -他在考虑
- What did he say? - Uh, he's thinking about it.
-考虑  -对
- Thinking about it? - Yeah.
豪生冰餐厅  冰淇淋  鸡尾酒
豪生汽车旅馆
客人登记及收据
弗兰克·希兰
给你的
That's for you.
很好  好的
Well, that's good. Okay.
几点了  弗兰克
What time you got, Frank?
大概五点
About five.
五点吗
Five, huh?
也许你该给吉米打个电话
Maybe you should give Jimmy a call.
他说他会考虑的  对吗
I mean, he said he was gonna think about it, right?
好
Okay.
你们什么时候来
So when are you getting in?
明天早上
Tomorrow morning.
那挺好  挺好  因为...
That's good. That's good, 'cause, uh...
另外那件事我改变主意了
I changed my mind about the other thing.
-是吗  -嗯
- You did? - Yeah.
我明天下午会跟矮子见面
Yeah, I'm gonna meet, uh, with the Little Guy tomorrow afternoon.
跟矮...
With the lit...
-跟矮子见面吗  -嗯
- With the Little Guy? - Yeah.
托尼·杰克安排好了  我喜欢杰克
Tony Jack set it up. I like Jack.
他很不错
Jack's good.
迈阿密那事儿之后  我见过他几次
I met with him a few times after that, you know, Miami fiasco.
在哪里和矮子见面
With the Little Guy. Where?
老地方  你知道在哪里
Same place as before. You know where it is.
在公共场合
In public.
你知道托尼·杰克是普罗的表亲吧
You know Tony Jack is Pro's cousin?
嗯  那又怎样
Yeah. So?
他们全都是亲戚  你能怎么办
They're all fucking cousins. What're you gonna do?
吉米  我觉得我应该过去
Jimmy, I think I should be there.
好  我想让你在场
Yeah, I want you there.
所以我问了你什么时候过来
That's why I asked when you're coming in.
你们几点见面
What time's the meeting?
两点半
Two-thirty.
那个龟孙可千万别迟到
And he better not be late, that cocksucker,
或是穿着该死的短裤
or wearing those fucking shorts.
我两点到那里
Listen, I'm gonna get there at 2:00,
你也应该两点到
so you should get there at 2:00.
-好吗  -我会两点到
- Okay? - I'll be there at 2:00.
好  很好  好的
Oh, good. Good. Okay.
两点见
I'll see you at 2:00.
-谢谢  弗兰克  -好  吉米
- Thanks, Frank. - Okay, Jimmy.
两点见
See you at 2:00.
他怎么说
What did he say?
他会跟普罗见面
He's gonna meet with Pro.
托尼·杰克安排好了
Tony Jack set it up.
很好
Very good.
-你们好  -你们好  晚上好
- Hello. - Hello. Good evening.
-我们饿死了  -快走  快走
- We're starving. - Oh, let's go, let's go.
跟安吉洛的人要来这瓶红酒醋
It was the best move we made,
是我们做过最明智的事
getting this red wine vinegar from Angelo's guy.
跟另一个混混要来的意大利橄榄油也不错
Great Italian olive oil we got from that other mooch was not bad either.
卡塔尼亚的橄榄油最棒了
Catania olives, what better.
顶级的
The best.
计划有变
There's been a change.
明天早上别那么早出发
Instead of, uh, going up early,
我们先待一会儿  然后再开车过去
we're gonna hang around tomorrow morning and then go drive up.
但我跟吉米说了  我们一早就出发
But... But I told Jimmy that we were gonna be up in the morning.
我跟吉米说了...
I told Jimmy...
我跟吉米说了我们一早就出发
I told Jimmy we're gonna be up in the morning.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
我说我会陪他去见普罗
That I would be there for that... meeting with Pro.
-什么  -我会...
- What? - That I'd be...
陪他去见普罗
be there for that meeting with Pro.
嗯  我知道  我知道
Oh, yeah. I know. I know.
那我要怎么做
But what I... What am I gonna do?
我们得过去  我得过去
We gotta go there. I mean, I gotta go.
我跟他说了我会去
I told him I'd be there.
弗兰克
Frank...
我们对他仁至义尽了
we did all we could for the man.
别打给他
Don't call him.
-早上好  -早上好
- Hey. Good morning. - Hey. Morning.
要咖啡吗
Want some coffee?
不用  我有了
No, I got it here.
-睡得怎么样  -挺好  你呢
- How'd ya sleep? - Good. You?
还行吧
All right.
要全麦片还是玉米片
Want some Total or Corn Flakes?
全麦片吧
Maybe Total.
够了  谢谢
That's good, thanks.
我们今天要去一趟克林顿港
We're gonna take a ride up to Port Clinton today.
我以为我们要待在这里
I thought we were staying here.
不  夫人们待在这里
No, the girls are gonna stay here.
我们俩去
You and me, we're going up and, uh...
最多三个小时就会回来
we'll be back three hours tops.
去克林顿港干什么
But... But what's in Port Clinton?
坐飞机
A plane.
坐飞机  去哪里
A plane? To where?
底特律
Detroit.
我们现在要去底特律吗
We're going to Detroit now?
不  你要去底特律
No, you're gonna go to Detroit.
你回来之后
And when you come back,
我们带上夫人们
me and you, we get together with the girls,
优哉游哉地上路
we take a nice slow drive up.
时不时停下来抽根烟
With cigarette breaks, you know.
弗兰克
Frank.
我必须让你去做这件事
I had to put you into this thing,
否则你绝不会袖手旁观
or you would never let it happen.
我知道你不会
And I know you wouldn't.
但事已至此
But it's gonna happen.
不管怎样  都得解决他
Either way, he's going.
我明白你的感受  弗兰克  相信我
I know how you feel, Frank. Trust me.
我明白你的感受
I know how you feel.
我之前跟你说过  我们已经尽力帮他了
I told you before, we tried everything to help him.
你知道的
You know that.
你尽力了
You tried.
这是他自找的
He brought this on himself.
还牵扯到了我们
And it's landing on us.
他们同意这样安排
The only reason they agreed to this
是出于对我的尊重
was out of respect to me.
你和琳妮不会有事的
But you and Reenie will be okay,
因为你是我的人
'cause you're with me.
你是我的人
You're with me.
把你的眼镜给我
Give me your glasses.
凯撒路83号
红狐餐厅
弗兰克
Hey, Frank.
小萨
Hey, Sal.
查奇迟到了
Chuckie's late.
是他吗
That him?
嗯
Yeah.
天呐
Jesus.
我是萨利
I'm Sally.
你好
Hi.
-小查  -弗兰克
- Chuck. - Frank.
快走  我不想你爸因为迟到对我大吼大叫
Let's go. I don't want your father yelling at me for being late.
弗兰克  你坐前面
Frank, you take the front.
-这他妈怎么回事  -怎么了
- What the fuck is this? - What?
湿漉漉的
It's wet.
我刚给朋友送了一条冻鱼
Yeah, I had a frozen fish I had to deliver for a friend of mine.
一条鱼
A fish?
座位是被鱼给弄湿了吗
The seat is wet from a fish?
对  你现在想让我怎么办
Yeah, I know. What do you want me to do about it now?
-老天啊  -我坐后面吧
- Jesus Christ. - I'll sit back there.
不不不  没关系  你坐前面
No, no, no, it's all right. You sit in the front.
我坐后面
I'll sit there.
我坐后面  你坐前面
I'll sit here, you take the front.
不  不
No, no.
我坐后面
I'll sit there.
-我不要坐前面  -你怎么就不...
- I'm not sitting there. - Why don't you...
我要坐后面
I'm sitting there.
好  随你便
All right, sit where you want.
要给你拿张报纸吗  弗兰克
You want me to get you a newspaper, Frank?
不用了  走吧  我们得快点
It's okay. Let's go. We gotta hurry.
是什么鱼
What kind of fish?
什么
What?
你送的是什么鱼
What kind of fish?
不知道  就是可以吃的鱼
I don't know. The kind you eat. A fish.
你不知道是哪种鱼吗
You don't know what kind?
不知道
No. I don't.
你从哪弄来的
Where did you get it?
你说呢  卖鱼的地方
What the fuck. At a fish place.
你就直接过去说"给我条鱼"吗
What, you just go in there and say, "Gimme a fish"?
差不多吧
Pretty much. Yeah.
你没说你要鲑鱼
You didn't say you want a salmon,
还是黑线鳕
you want a... haddock,
还是鳕鱼吗
you want a... a fucking cod?
是哪种鱼有什么关系吗
What the fuck does it matter what kind of fish it was?
你为什么那么关心那条鱼
Why are you so concerned about this fish?
我只是想搞清楚...
I'm just trying to understand how...
这...
Does it...
怎么能买到一条鱼  却不知道是什么鱼
...how a person can buy a fish and not know what kind it was.
那条鱼就在那里等着我
There was a fish waiting for me there.
我没问那是什么鱼  抱歉
I didn't ask what kind of fish it was. I'm sorry.
-就是说你朋友已经把鱼订好了  -对
- So your friend had already ordered this fish. - Right.
要是有人问起  我得能解释明白
'Cause I wanna be able to explain this if somebody asks me.
红狐餐厅
好  没问题
Yeah. Absolutely.
爸
Dad.
查奇
Chuckie.
-抱歉我迟到了  我得去送...  -迟到
- Yeah, sorry I'm late. I had to drop off... - Late?
你来这里干什么
What the fuck are you even doing here?
-谁让你来的  -吉米
- Who invited you? - Hey, Jimmy.
你是谁
Who the fuck are you?
我是普罗的人
I'm with Pro.
你是普罗的人
You're with Pro?
你是那个放我鸽子的龟孙的人
Are you with the cocksucker who just stood me up?
我不会等人超过十分钟
I don't wait for anybody more than ten minutes.
他在房子里
He's at the house.
什么房子
What house?
和罗素在一起
With Russ.
-罗素  搞什么  -看看谁在后面
- Russ? What the fuck is... - Hey, look who's here.
-弗兰克  -吉米
- Frank. - Jimmy.
到底怎么回事
What the fuck is going on?
我一直在等你  我两点就到了
I was waiting for you. I was there at two o'clock.
你应该到场的  出什么事了
You were supposed to show. What happened?
抱歉  但麦基来了  他决定过来
I'm sorry. But McGee's here, he decided to come.
但他不喜欢这里  他不想来这里
But he ain't comfortable here. He don't wanna come here.
他在房子里
He's at the house.
-麦基来底特律了  -对  他来了
- McGee's in Detroit? - Yeah, he's here.
他决定过来
He decided to come.
他是来帮忙理清这件事的
Yeah, he came to help straighten this all out.
房子
The house?
事后我们会带你来取车的
We'll bring you back after to get your car.
没错
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
-好  -嗯
- Yeah. - Yeah.
红狐餐厅
之前车里放了条鱼
There was a fish in here,
但我们已经清理干净了
but we cleaned it up.
鱼
A fish?
查奇在车里放了条鱼
Chuckie had a fucking fish in here.
他连是什么鱼都不知道
Didn't even know what kind.
但现在没事了  我擦干净了
But it's okay now. I wiped it up.
-我在座位上垫了块手帕  -我闻出来了
- I got the handkerchief here. - Yeah, I can smell it.
查奇
Hey, Chuckie.
你在车里放了条鱼吗
You had a fish in here in your car?
给鲍比·霍姆斯的
For Bobby Holmes.
你知道的  鲍比喜欢吃鱼
You know, Bobby likes fish.
我们清理干净了  吉米  没关系
We cleaned it up, Jimmy. It's all right.
你清理干净了
You cleaned it up?
-你清理干净了  -是的
- You cleaned it up? - Yeah.
你他妈了解鱼吗
What the fuck you know about fish?
你这辈子有抓过鱼吗
You ever caught a fucking fish in your life?
没有
No.
那你就不了解  对吧
Well, then you don't know. See?
小查
Chuck.
听我说  永远不要在车里放鱼
Listen to me. Never put a fish in your car.
味道是散不掉的
You never get the smell out.
-嗯...  -除非包装得很好
- No... - Unless you pack it tight, you know.
嗯  我知道
No, I... I know.
-你知道吗  记住了  -对
- You know? Remember that. - Right.
我知道
I know.
你会受益匪浅的
It'll help you in life.
弗兰克  你就不能两点来找我  告诉我这事吗
Frank, you couldn't come by at 2:00 and tell me this?
我傻傻地在那等了你四十分钟
I was waiting there 40 minutes like a fuckin' moron.
吉米  抱歉  我刚到就赶过来了
Jimmy, I'm sorry. I came as soon as I got here.
-你今天早上到的  -不是
- You got in this morning. - No, no, no.
我今天下午才到的
I got here this afternoon.
罗素在克林顿港办事  我得等他
Russell had business in Port Clinton. I had to wait for him.
他提醒了我  我忘记了
He reminded me. I forgot.
所以我们马上赶来  我刚到
So, we had to come and as soon as we got here,
就直接过来找你了
I came right here to see you.
没有对罗素不敬的意思
All due respect to Russ, you know,
但应该让人提前告诉我的
but somebody should have come tell me, you know.
最起码应该来告诉我时间推迟了
Just come tell me it's 2:30, 2:40, at the very least.
你说得对  我是说...
You're not incorrect. I mean...
普罗算哪根葱  还派个狗腿子过来
Who the fuck is Pro? He sends a fucking errand boy here.
他不会待太久
He ain't stayin'.
我知道他不会待太久
I know he ain't staying.
关键不在于他待多久
That's not the point, he's staying or not staying.
关键在于普罗派他过来
The point is Pro sent him.
知道吗
You know?
关键是他应该亲自来接我
Point is, he should've come picked me up himself.
这才是问题的关键
That's the point I'm makin'.
你戴着这副眼镜能看得清吗
Can you even see out of those glasses?
我什么都看不清
I can't see a fucking thing.
很好  幸好不是你开车
That's good. I'm glad you're not driving, then.
就在这...这边
Yeah, it's right... It's right up...
就在这边  这边
It's right up here. Right... Right up...
有楼梯的那房子
That building with the staircase.
你带家伙了吗
You got your friend with you?
-带了  -很好
- Right here. - Good.
谁知道这个龟孙会做出什么事
You never know with this cocksucker,
不管罗素在不在场
with or without Russ there.
快走  弗兰克  快
Let's get outta here, Frank. Come on.
♪ Before the light ♪
In The Still Of The Night - The Five Satins
♪ Hold me again ♪
♪ With all of your might ♪
♪ In the still of the night ♪
♪ So before the light ♪
♪ Hold me again ♪
♪ With all of your might ♪
♪ In the still of the night ♪
卡车司机工会前主席詹姆斯·霍法
James Hoffa, former president of the Teamsters Union,
于周三失踪
disappeared on Wednesday.
截至今晚  尚未发现他的踪迹
And as of tonight, no trace of him has been found.
霍法在监狱服刑四年  他坦承
Hoffa spent four years in prison and made no bones
-自己打算...  -弗兰克
- about his intention... - Frank.
从他的继任弗兰克·菲茨西蒙斯手上
...to get the presidency back from his successor,
夺回主席之位
Frank Fitzsimmons.
菲茨西蒙斯的儿子是副主席...
Fitzsimmons' son is the vice president of...
还没消息吗
Still nothing?
小菲茨西蒙斯的车被炸了  他当时不在车内
...young Fitzsimmons' car was bombed. He was not in it.
但底特律地方工会内确有不和
But there is bad blood in the Detroit Local.
霍法于周三下午失踪
Hoffa disappeared Wednesday afternoon.
目前已过去48个小时  仍然不清楚
Now, more than 48 hours later, with no word yet
霍法出了什么事  警方对此极为关切
on what happened to Hoffa, police are extremely concerned.
当局急于弄清楚
Authorities are most anxious to find whom
霍法在红狐餐厅外见的是谁
Hoffa was supposed to meet outside the Red Fox restaurant
那是最后有人看到他的地方
where he was last seen.
警方认为可能是安东尼·加卡罗内
Police think it could have been a man named Anthony Giacalone,
他被称为底特律黑手党的大佬
described as a big man in the Detroit Mafia.
霍法的儿子詹姆斯今天试图联系加卡罗内
Hoffa's son, James, tried to contact Giacalone today,
但没能联系上
but didn't succeed.
霍法的亲朋好友今天留在
Hoffa's family and friends stayed
位于湖口镇的家中
in the family home in Lake Orion today...
我应该打给约
I should call Jo.
你还没有打给约吗
You haven't called Jo yet?
为什么
Why?
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
什么为什么
Why what?
你为什么还没有打给约
Why haven't you called Jo?
有人索要赎金之类的吗
Has anybody come forward with a ransom demand or anything like that?
目前还没有
Not as of yet.
你认为这起绑架是为了索要赎金吗
Do you think the abduction was for ransom?
我现在打给她
I'm gonna call her now.
你认为这起绑架
Do you think the abduction
和他所在的299号地方工会
had anything to do with the recent conflicts
最近的内部冲突有关吗
within Local 299, his own Local?
我认为工会政治
I think the union politics
当然是需要进行调查的
is certainly something that has to be investigated.
国际卡车司机工会的一位高层人士
One high official of the Teamsters International
声称他担心发生了最坏的事
says he fears the worst,
即霍法可能已经被杀
that Hoffa may have been killed.
全国广播公司新闻频道的罗伯特·哈格
Robert Hager, NBC News,
在密歇根州布隆菲尔德为您报道
Bloomfield, Michigan.
底特律外的一处卡车休息站
At a truck stop outside Detroit,
霍法在这升任卡车司机工会主席
where Hoffa rose to the top in the Teamsters Union,
站内的卡车司机们众说纷纭
truck drivers had a variety of theories...
她自那天后就没和我说过话
She stopped talking to me that day.
1975年8月3日
August 3rd, 1975.
她现在有份好工作  住在费城外
She's got a good job now and lives just outside Philly.
但我的女儿
But my daughter...
佩琪
Peggy...
自那天后
disappeared...
就从我的生命中消失了
from my life that day.
喂
Hello.
-喂  -喂
- Hello. - Hello?
约
Jo.
Jo?
是关于...
It's... It's...
-弗兰克  是你吗  -是我
- Frank. Frank? - Yeah. Yeah.
-嗯  -我不...
- Yeah... - I don't...
-听着  我...  -弗兰克
- Look, I... - Frank...
你觉得他还活着吗
Do you think... Do you think he's alive?
他肯定还活着
He's gotta be.
你得乐观一点
You know, you gotta think positively.
还没过很久...
It's just, you know, it ain't that long. It's just...
但你...
But do you...
你知道他现在还好吗
Do you know he's okay?
不不不  你了解我的  我...
No, no, no, I mean, you know me, I...
他可能干了"香蕉乔"那样的事
He maybe did something like the Joe Bananas thing,
美国黑手党"第一教父"
约瑟夫·博南诺的外号
把自己绑架了
where, you know, he had himself kidnapped
然后毫发无损地回来了
and then came back, but he wasn't hurt, nothing happened.
也许他
Maybe he...
也许他只是想
Maybe he just felt, you know,
清理一下自己的思绪
he wanted to clear his head a bit.
但你得相信...
But you gotta just think that it's gonna be...
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay.
他不会...
He's gonna be...
你有什么需要的话尽管找我
If you need anything, I'm here for you.
任何事都行
Anything. Anything.
你可以...可以再打给我吗
Can you just... Can you call me again?
好  我会...会打给你的
Yeah, I'll call... I'll call you.
好  我会打给你的
Yeah, I'll... I'll call you.
我明早打给你
I'll check in with you tomorrow.
好  明天打给我
Yes, call me tomorrow.
好  我明早打给你  好吗
Okay. I'll call you in the morning, okay?
你保证吗
Promise?
别担心  坚强点
Don't worry. Be strong.
乐观点  好吗
Be positive, huh?
好了  约  好了
Okay, Jo, okay, okay.
好了
Okay.
-好  -我晚点再打给你  再见
- Okay. - Talk to ya a little later. Bye.
-再见  -再见  弗兰克
- Bye. - Goodbye, Frank.
就是这么简单
It was no more complicated than that.
希兰先生
Mr. Sheeran,
你知道是否有人  是什么人
do you know who, if anyone,
绑架了詹姆斯·霍法吗
was behind the disappearance of James Hoffa?
跟吉米有关系的人
Everybody who ever had anything to do with Jimmy
都被传唤进行问询
was hauled in and questioned.
根据律师的建议
On the advice of counsel,
恕我拒绝回答这个问题
I respectfully decline to answer that question
因为这可能会使我负罪
on the grounds that it might tend to incriminate me.
好吧  我换个问题
Okay, let me ask you this:
我的笔是什么颜色
what color is my pen?
所有人都行使第五修正案拒绝回答
And everybody took the Fifth.
在那种情况下  只能这么做
I mean, in that situation, that's what you do.
不然还能怎么做呢
What else are you gonna do?
然而所有人都因某件事被控告和定罪
Still, everybody got indicted or convicted on one thing or another,
但不是因为那件事
but not that.
不是因为吉米
Not about Jimmy.
如你所知  没有人因为这件事入狱
Nobody, as you know, even went to jail for that.
也没有人松口  这不常见
And nobody talked, which is unusual,
因为通常来说  三个人守不住秘密
'cause usually, three people can keep a secret
除非另外两人不在人世
only when two of them are dead.
布鲁诺·邓赞塔和马尔科·罗西
Bruno Denzetta and Marco Rossi,
他们因敲诈一家货运公司而分别被判刑二十年
they got 20 years each for shaking down a trucking company.
普罗和他们一起被判刑
Pro was convicted with them,
但他早就因为
but he was already back in school
我之前说过的另一件事进了监狱
for that other matter I talked about before.
还记得可怜的工会财务
Well, you remember that poor union treasurer,
"三指"托尼吗  就是比普罗获得更多选票的那个
Tony "Three Fingers," who got more votes than Pro?
他们因此把他做掉了
They got him on that.
小虫萨利动的手
Sally Bugs, you know, he did that one.
有一天  有人看见小虫走进了政府大楼
One day, Bugs was seen walking into the Federal building.
他做的事不是犯罪
What he did itself ain't no crime.
很多人都因为做了某事而被传唤
I mean, a lot of people get called in for things.
但萨利明白事理
But Sally knows better.
他怎么会什么都没告诉别人呢
How come he didn't say anything to anybody?
他一句话都没跟别人说
He didn't tell anybody one word.
一句话都没有
Not one word.
可以肯定的是
And one thing for sure,
他去那里不是为了吃午餐的
he didn't go there for fucking lunch.
萨利
Sally.
-你好吗  -你好啊  爱尔兰人
- What's good? - Hey, Irish.
后来才知道萨利确实跟别人说了
Turns out Sally did tell somebody
他要去那里办事
he had to go in there for something.
只不过对方忘了告诉别人
They just forgot to tell somebody else.
我们杀错人了
So it was a bad hit.
吉米的儿子查奇  他的养子
Jimmy's son, Chuckie, you know, his foster son,
也参与了这件事
was in the thing, too,
但他并不知情
but he didn't know it.
查奇只知道他要接
All Chuckie knew was he was pickin' up
我和一个普罗的人
one of Pro's guys and me,
然后我们要一起到红狐餐厅
and we was all gonna pick up his dad
接他爸去开会
at the Red Fox for a meeting.
他参与了这件事  没错
Well, I mean, he was in it, yeah,
可以这么说  但他是糊里糊涂的
you could say that, but stupidly.
我一直对查奇心怀愧疚
I... I always felt sorry for Chuckie in this whole thing.
我现在仍然很愧疚
And I... I still do.
联调局因为一台车的破事
And the Feds gave him ten months
让他被判刑十个月  事情大概就是这样
for some bullshit thing about a car, and that's about it.
谁知道是在搞什么
Who knows what the fuck...
胖子托尼·萨雷诺因为所得税的事情被抓
Fat Tony Salerno, they got on an income tax thing.
不久之后
A little while after,
他被查出患有前列腺癌
he was diagnosed with prostate cancer.
北加州有一家
There's a... a pork store up in...
猪肉店
northern California.
就在
Right around...
核桃溪市边上
Walnut Creek.
你是从那里来的  对吧
You're from up there, ain't you?
-对  -嗯
- Yeah. - Yeah.
你可能还认识店主
And you might even know the guy that runs it.
其实  我想让你帮个忙
Actually, I'm looking for a little favor...
帮他  不是帮我
for him, not for me.
你能不能帮他弄张机票  比如去澳大利亚的
But if you can get him a ticket, like, to Australia...
你懂我的意思
You know what I mean.
好
Yeah.
你愿意帮他出国吗
You want to help him get down there?
愿意
Ye... Yeah.
罗素被抓了
Now, Russell, he got pinched
因为杰克·拿波里从他那赊账
for telling Jimmy the Weasel to strangle Jack Napoli
拿走了价值两万五的珠宝却没还钱
over some beef about 25 grand of jewelry
于是他让黄鼠狼吉米
that Jack took on credit from Russell
去把杰克勒死
and then he never paid for.
你不能对罗素做这样的事
Now, with Russ, you don't do that.
问题在于  黄鼠狼叛变了
So, only thing is, the Weasel, he flipped.
他身上带了窃听器
He had a wire on him.
他们声称他"密谋杀害目击者"
They called it "conspiracy to kill a witness."
显而易见的是
It was obvious to everybody else
拿波里做得不对
that Napoli was clearly in the wrong.
这难道不明显吗
I mean, how could you not see that?
他陷害了他  这是诱捕
He set him up. It was entrapment.
难道不是吗
What else could you call it?
但这件事我现在也不想细说
But that's another thing I don't wanna get into now.
举起右手
Raise your right hand.
他们把我送上法庭  指控我行贿和工会诈骗
They brought me up on bribery and labor racketeering charges
还有其他一些我不知道的破事
and some other bullshit things I don't know.
谋杀  谋杀未遂  恐吓  挪用公款  纵火
你是否向上帝发誓  你所说的全是事实
the whole truth and nothing but the truth,
-没有任何隐瞒  -我发誓
- so help you God? - I do.
你是否还告诉他们巴法先生
Did you also tell them that Mr. Boffa
送了你和你妻子豪车
had given you and your wife luxury vehicles?
科尔先生  我工作了44年
Mr. Cole, I worked for 44 years,
我没收过巴法或者别人的任何不法之财
I never took one dime illegal off Boffa or nobody else.
你怎么想是你的事  跟我没关系
You can think whatever you wanna think. Don't matter to me.
但他们能落实的罪名  只有我炸了一家吊车公司
But all they got me for was blowing up a crane company
那家公司开除了我的两个工会谈判代表
that fired two of my shop stewards
却没有正当的理由
for no good reason.
还有我的林肯汽车
And... And my Lincoln.
我从尤金·巴法手里买下来的
I mean, I bought that car from Eugene Boffa.
他向货运公司出租卡车司机
He leased truck drivers to freight companies,
然后付给他们低于正常标准的工资
and then he paid them substandard wages.
他们说我买这辆车花的钱
They said I paid a lot less for the car
远低于其价值
than what it was worth.
他们说这辆车是贿赂
They said the car was a bribe.
我爱这辆车
I... I... I loved that car.
但它不值得我为它坐十八年牢
But it wasn't worth the 18 years they gave me for it.
这是肯定的
That's for sure.
罗素中风了
Russell, he had a stroke.
胖托尼尿失禁了
Fat Tony, he couldn't control his urine no more.
我在安齐奥的散兵坑里得上的关节炎
And my arthritis that started in the foxholes of Anzio
不断折磨着我的腰
was eatin' away at my lower back now,
我的脚已经没什么知觉了
and I couldn't feel much in my feet no more.
我需要拄拐杖
I needed a cane.
但他们不会在牢里给你配拐杖
But, you know, they're not gonna give you a cane in the can
因为他们怕你把它当作武器
because they say you're gonna use it as a weapon.
有一种叫诺立汀的药
There was this medicine, Neurontin,
对我有点帮助
it helped me a little bit,
但也会使你神经错乱
but it also made you loopy.
他要打中了
He's got it!
我们在严寒中
We were all falling apart right there
都要崩溃了
in the freezing fucking cold.
我在这里就能看到  你现在怕了吗
I can see it from here. You getting scared now?
你再练个十年
Yeah, you stay here another fucking ten years,
才有可能赢我
you'll beat me.
这是好喝的葡萄汁吗
Is this the good grape juice?
我吃不了这个
I can't eat it.
-吃一口  -我没牙  吃不了
- Take a bite. - I got no teeth. I can't.
给我一小块
Put a little piece.
一小块就好  谢谢
Just a little piece, thank you.
还要吗
That's it?
-好吃吧  -好吃
- E buono, no? - Buono.
好吃
Buono.
吉米是个好人
Jimmy was a good man.
他还有美满的家庭  不是吗
You know? He had a nice family too, huh?
是的  我知道
Yeah. Yeah. I know.
我从没想过要把事情做这么绝
I never wanted it to go that far.
我为了我们的利益而放弃了他
I picked us over him.
去他们的
Fuck 'em.
吃吧  小子  吃吧
Mangia che cresci... figlio mio, mangia.
罗素
Hey, Russ.
弗兰克
Hey, Frankie.
-你要去哪  -什么
- Where you goin'? - What?
-你要去哪  -我要去教堂
- Where you goin'? - I'm going to church.
教堂
Church?
别笑  到时你就知道了
Don't laugh, you'll see.
别笑
Don't laugh.
到时你就知道了
You'll see.
罗素去了教堂
Russell went to church.
后来他去了监狱的医院
Then he went to the prison hospital.
再后来他进了坟墓
And... And then he went to the graveyard.
主耶稣基督
Lord Jesus Christ...
我在那年的十月出狱了
I got out that October.
琳妮在十二月去世了
Reenie died in December.
准确地说是12月23日
On December 23rd, to be exact.
肺癌
Lung cancer.
一点也不意外
No surprise.
即使夺去了我们必死的身躯
...even as it claims our mortal bodies.
让我们的姐妹在此安眠
Grant that our sister may sleep here in peace,
直至您用荣光将她唤醒
until you awaken her to glory.
因为您就是复苏和生命
For you are the resurrection and the life.
然后她将与您面对面
And then she will see you face to face,
在您的光明中看见光明
and in your light will see light,
感受上帝的光辉  直到永远
and know the splendor of God for ever and ever.
阿门
Amen.
这个赛季他的击打率比生涯平均的29.6%
...six points shy of his career average of .296
低了六个百分点
coming into this season.
费城队阵容里前四位击球员
Top four batters in this lineup for Philadelphia
都是左右手都能打的
today are all switch hitters.
使一些政策制定者失望的是
Much to the frustration of some policy makers,
北约军事领导人不会冒险
NATO military leaders will not risk
对科索沃的塞尔维亚军队发动低空袭击
low flying attacks on Serb troops in Kosovo.
还需要进行多日的系统轰炸
It could take days more of systematic bombing,
尤其是因为塞尔维亚人
especially since the Serbs
将很多防空导弹藏了起来
have hidden so many of their anti-aircraft missiles,
想引诱北约军队进行低空空袭
in essence, daring NATO to fly low.
你去吧  去吧
You go... you go there. Yeah, yeah.
去吧
Yeah, yeah.
暂停营业
请到隔壁柜台
佩琪
Peggy.
佩琪  我只是想和你聊聊
Peggy. I just want to talk.
我只是  我...
I just, you know... I...
她走开了
She walked away.
我知道她生我的气  但我想...
I know she's mad at me and all, but I... I want...
打给她  打给她  我只是想和她聊聊
Call her. Call her. I just want to talk to her.
和她聊什么呢
Talk to her and tell her what?
什么
What...
我只是想跟她道个歉  仅此而已
I just want to say I'm sorry. That's all.
为什么道歉
For?
听着
Look...
我知道我不是个好父亲  我知道
I know I wasn't a... a good dad. I know that.
我知道  我只是想保护她
I know that. I was just trying to protect her.
保护你们每个人不受伤害
Protect all of youse.
那就是我做的事
I mean, that's what I was doing. That's...
受什么伤害
From what?
一切事情
Well, everything.
我是说
I mean...
某种程度上  你们以前过着受保护的生活
You... Youse had a sheltered life, in a way,
因为你们没见过我所见过的事
because you didn't see what I see
没经历过我所经历的事
and what I've been through.
外面有很多坏人
There's a lot of bad people out there.
我还能做什么
What else am I gonna do?
爸  你根本不知道我们以前的感受
Daddy, you have no idea what it was like for us.
我们出了问题没法找你
I mean, we couldn't go to you with a problem
怕你会做不好的事
'cause of what you would do.
我们没法向你寻求保护
You know, we couldn't come to you for protection
因为你会做可怕的事
because of the terrible things that you would do.
我只是  只是
I was just... I was...
不想看你们受到伤害  仅此而已
I didn't want to see youse get hurt, that's all.
我知道你们读到过  听说过很多我的事情
I know you read a lot of things about me, heard about me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我...
I...
我现在能做些什么来补偿你们吗
Can I do anything now to make it up to you?
如果你想要奢华一点的
If you're looking for something with a little bit more luxury,
我们有这两款
we have these two models over here.
它们就像棺材界的凯迪拉克
They're like the Cadillacs of caskets.
如果你要火化的话
Now, if we puttin' you in the fuckin' oven,
用什么棺材其实都无所谓
it really doesn't matter what you go in.
越便宜越好
The cheapest shit possible.
复合板就够了
Particle board, that's it.
后事打算怎么办  火葬吗
What are we doin' today? Are we doin' a cremation?
-土葬  -土葬
- A burial. - Burial?
是男人还是女人
Is it for a man or for a woman?
是我
Me.
靠
Shit.
有喜欢的吗
You see anything you like?
-那个绿色的  -那个很漂亮
- That green one. - That's a beauty.
如果你今天就买的话
That one'll set you back about $7,500
大概要七千五百块
if you take it home today.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
能便宜点吗
Can you do any better?
伙计  你想在这棺材里长眠是吧
I mean, buddy, this is what you want to go home in, no?
那就算你六千吧  怎么样
I think we could go six on that for you. How about that?
-六千现金  行吗  -可以
- Six flat cash work for you? - That's good.
可以
Good for me.
迟早
Sooner or later,
这世上每一个人都有离开的那天
everybody put here has a date when he's gonna go.
人生就是如此
That's just the way it is.
我认为离开的时候肯定会发生什么
And I think there's gotta be something when you go
不然  这一切到底是怎么开始的
'cause, I mean, how the hell did this whole thing start?
比我聪明的人都没搞清楚
People smarter than me can't figure it out.
所以我绝对不会选择火葬
That's why I would never go for cremation
因为那就真的结束了
because it's so... it's so final.
这个
This... This one.
1948号
1948.
对埋葬你的人来说最难接受的
That's the hardest part of anybody when they bury youse,
就是入土的时候
is when they go into the ground
因为那就真的结束了
because it's... it's so final.
如果你要埋在房子里  房子还在
If you go into a building, the building's there.
墓还在
The crypt is there.
一定要用金属棺材
It has to be a metal casket,
他们把你放在房间里
and they have you in the room.
都放好
And all that there.
就不算完全结束了
It's just not as final.
你死了  但还没结束
You're dead, but it ain't that final.
抱歉  如果你们想谈霍法先生的事
I'm sorry, but I gotta direct youse to my attorney,
我就得
Mr. Ragano...
请你们去找我的律师
if youse want to talk about Mr. Hoffa or...
雷加诺先生
or any matter, for that matter.
我没有别的可说的
I got noth... nothing new to say.
他死了
He's dead.
谁死了
Who's dead?
你的律师  雷加诺先生
Your attorney, Mr. Ragano.
-他死了  -是的
- He's dead? - Yeah.
谁干的
Who did it?
癌症
Cancer.
所有人都死了  希兰先生
Everybody's dead, Mr. Sheeran.
结束了
It's over.
他们都死了
They're all gone.
罗素  安吉洛  萨雷诺
Russell, Angelo, Salerno,
普罗  多夫曼  小虫萨利
Pro, Dorfman, Sally Bugs.
他们都死了
They're gone.
你在保护谁
Who are you protecting?
你知道谁没死吗
You know who's not gone?
霍法先生的家人  他的孩子们
Mr. Hoffa's family. His children.
他们还活着  他们一辈子都得不到真相
They're here. And they gotta live not knowing.
那很难熬
That's hard to do.
你也有孩子  弗兰克
I mean, you got kids, Frank.
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
弗兰克  是时候了  该说出真相了
Frank, it's time. It's time you say what happened.
你们看起来人不错
You seem like nice fellas.
感谢你们亲自来找我
I appreciate youse coming to see me.
但我帮不了你们
But I... I can't help you.
就这样吗
That's it?
就这样
That's it.
圣母玛利亚
Holy Mary, Mother of God...
-请为我们这些罪人祈祷  -请为我们这些罪人祈祷
- Pray for us sinners... - Pray for us sinners...
-现在和我们临终时  -现在和我们临终时
- Now and at the hour of our death. - Now and at the hour of our death.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
这...
That was...
这还不错
That wasn't too bad.
很久没祷告过了
It's been a while.
真的很不错
Not bad at all.
真心实意的  发自内心
And the intention was there. The intention.
我知道
I know.
我知道你是发自内心的
I know the intention is there.
是真的  神父
It was there, Father.
你对自己做过的事
Do you feel anything for...
有任何感觉吗
for what you've done?
没有  不过也许...
I, I don't. I mean, maybe that...
我现在坐在这里跟你说话
Because I'm here now talking to you,
也许这本身就是
that in itself is,
一种尝试...
you know, an attempt to...
但你真的一点感觉都没有吗
But you don't feel anything at all?
没有
No.
都是过去的事了
Water under the dam.
对他的家人有没有愧疚呢
Any... Any remorse for the families?
我不认识他的家人
I... I didn't know the families.
我不认识他们  只认识一个
I didn't know 'em. Except one I knew.
我认为我们可以悔过
I think we can... we can be sorry...
我们可以悔过  即使我们不觉得难过
We can be sorry even when we don't feel sorry.
我们可以做出意志上的决定
Well, for us to say, to make a decision of the will...
"上帝啊
"God...
我很抱歉  上帝
I am sorry, God.
原谅我"
Forgive me."
这就是意志上的决定
And that... that's a decision of the will.
什么样的人
What kind of man
会打那样一通电话
makes a... a phone call like that?
什么意思  什么电话
What do you mean? What phone call?
我不能告诉你
Well, I can't tell you.
我不能  我得...
I can't. I got...
没关系
That's okay.
弗兰克  你想再和我祷告一次吗
Frank, do you wanna pray with me again?
好的
Yeah.
这次我们用自己的话来说  好吗
This time, we'll do it in our own words. Okay?
好
Okay.
上帝啊  我们来到您面前
God, we come before you
罪孽深重  忧伤不已
sinful and sorrowful.
Sinful and sorrowful.
我们知道您善良仁慈
We know you are all good and all merciful.
-我们请求您  -我们请求您
- We ask you... - We ask you...
用您的眼光
to help us see ourselves...
-帮我们看清自己  -帮我们看清自己
- as you see us. - as you see us.
这是我女儿  佩琪
That's my daughter, Peggy.
-是吗  -是的
- Is it? - Yeah.
我好像还没见过她
I don't think I've met her yet.
她不怎么过来
Well, she... she ain't been around too much.
她是你的独生女吗
Is she your only child?
不是  我有四个女儿
No, I got four daughters.
你看
Over there. See?
真漂亮
Beautiful.
-大忙人  -是啊
- Busy man. - Yeah.
是啊
Yeah.
她身旁是谁
Who's that with her?
你不知道这是谁
You don't know who that is?
不知道
No.
吉米·霍法
Jimmy Hoffa.
是他啊
Oh, yeah.
得了吧  "是他啊"
Yeah, right, "Oh, yeah."
你不知道他是谁
You don't know who he is.
好吧  我不知道
Okay, I don't.
是啊  你想不到时间过得有多快
Yeah. Boy, you don't know how fast time goes by
明白了已经晚了
until you get there.
不过你不用担心这个
But you don't have to worry about that
因为你还有大把的好时光
because you have your whole life ahead of you.
长得很  时间过得太快...
Forever. It goes fast, time...
我跟你说
I'm tellin' ya.
我在给你量脉搏  希兰先生
I'm trying to take your pulse, Mr. Sheeran.
请不要说话
Please, please don't talk.
今天很不错
It's great today.
我还活着
I'm still alive?
-是的  -真是好消息
- Yes, you are. - That's good to know.
活得好好的
Alive and well.
现在没事了
And you're free
不过晚些时候还要再给你检查一遍
till later today when we have to put you through all this again.
我哪都不去
I'm here.
...教会之奉
...ministry of the church.
愿上帝赐予你宽恕与平静  弗兰克
May God grant you pardon and peace, Frank.
我赦免你的罪
And I absolve you from your sins.
以圣父  圣子
In the name of the Father, and of the Son,
圣灵的名义  阿门
and of the Holy Spirit, amen.
感谢上帝  因为上帝仁慈
Give thanks to the Lord, for he is good.
他的慈爱
His mercy...
-他的慈爱永远长存  -永远长存
- His mercy endures forever. - endures forever.
好了  弗兰克  我很快就会再来看你
All right, Frank. I'll be back to visit, okay? Very soon.
大概圣诞假期后
Probably after the Christmas holidays.
好的
Okay.
-弗兰克  上帝保佑你  -你也是  谢谢
- Frank, God bless you. - You too. Thank you.
圣诞节到了
It's Christmas?
快了
Almost.
我哪也不去
Well, I ain't going nowhere.
-神父  -怎么
- Father? - Yup?
帮我个忙好吗
Do me a favor?
别把门关严  我不喜欢那样
Don't shut the door all the way. I don't like that. Just...
-留一条缝  -好
- leave it open a little bit. - Okay.
In the Still of the Night - The Five Satins
♪ In the still of the night ♪
♪ I held you ♪
♪ Held you tight ♪
爱尔兰人
♪ 'Cause I love ♪
听说你刷房子
♪ Love you so ♪
♪ Promise I'll never ♪
♪ Let you go ♪
♪ In the still of the night ♪
♪ I remember ♪
♪ That night in May ♪
♪ The stars were bright above ♪
♪ I'll hope and I'll pray ♪
♪ To keep Your precious love ♪
♪ Well before the light ♪
♪ Hold me again ♪
♪ With all of your might ♪
♪ In the still of the night ♪
♪ So before the light ♪
♪ Hold me again ♪
♪ With all of your might ♪
♪ In the still of the night ♪